<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="131"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM)
                                Universiti Sains Malaysia
                                         2024























         All rights reserved. No part of this publication may be reproduced, stored in a retrieval
             system, or transmitted in any form or by any means, electronic, mechanical,
         photocopying, recording, or otherwise, without the prior permission of the Institute for
                         Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM),
                                 Universiti Sains Malaysia


                                  Email: mdbd@usm.my

                                           th
           This program book is published for the 7  International Conference on Molecular
         Diagnostics & Biomarker Discovery (MDBD) by the Institute for Research in Molecular
                                  Medicine (INFORMM)]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Straits Scientific (M) Sdn Bhd

                                    Straits Scientific (M) Sdn Bhd, also known as “3S,” was
                                    established in 1985, specializing in providing quality
                                    laboratory and research products in Malaysia. With over
                                    31 years of experience in the diagnostics industry, it has
                                    developed itself as a partner, trusted in laboratory testing
                                    by most of the hospitals and laboratories throughout the
                                    nation.



                                    IT Tech Research (M) Sdn Bhd

                                    IT Tech Group has been actively involved in a variety of
                                    businesses, including manufacturing, food ingredient
                                    supplies, laboratory engineering and design, trading and
                                    distribution, laboratory services and repair, educational
                                    training, and workshops. They are focused on
                                    chromatography, laboratory engineering and design,
                                    laboratory and environmental safety products, repair
                                    services and training.

                                    Genomax Technologies

                                    Genomax Technologies is founded in 2003 by a team of
                                    enterprising professional with years of experience in life
                                    science research products. Genomax Technologies’ core
                                    products cover 4 major categories of applications:
                                    bioinformatics, genomics, molecular cell biology and
                                    proteomics. We have local offices in Singapore, Malaysia,
                                    and Thailand.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Gene Xpress PLT

                                    Gene Xpress PLT is a young and dynamic Malaysian-
                                    based biotechnology company incorporated in 2014 with
                                    a focus on Nucleic Acid purification systems. They aspire
                                    to produce the best quality nucleic acid systems in the
                                    market at affordable prices. Working closely with several
                                    local Malaysian research institutes, collaborators, and
                                    some technological transfers from the US.



                        Media Partners]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Foreword by the Vice Chancellor of Universiti Sains
                     Malaysia
                     Opening Remarks by Director of INFORMM
                     Welcome Note by Conference Chair
                     Conference Agenda
                     Keynote Abstract
                     Enhancement of Biosensors Through Biomarkers, Sampling
                     and Design
                     “From Bench to Bedside to Business” – Translating Research
                     into Impact: A Personal Experience in Singapore

                     Plenary Abstract
                     The  Malaysian  Vascular  Events  Risk  (MAVERIK)  Study  –
                     Discovering Biomarkers for Myocardiac Infarction
                     Therapeutic  potentials  of  modified  heparin  derivatives
                     Biosensor for Infectious Diseases
                     How to Successfully Register Your Medical Device with MDA
                     Malaysia
                     Molecular and cellular pathology of hereditary neurological
                     and neuropsychiatric disorders
                     Oral Presenter: Diagnostics & Biomarker Discovery
                     OD1  Quality Assessment of Plain Chest X-Rays of the
                            Expatriates in Jordan: Multi-Centres Study
                     OD2  The Role of Mitogen-Activated Protein Kinases and
                           Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress Signaling Pathways in
                           Annatto Tocotrienol-Induced Human Chondrosarcoma
                           SW1353 Cell Paraptosis
                     OD3  Identification of Alpha-1 Antitrypsin as a Candidate
                            Biomarker for Post COVID-19 Syndrome by Two-
                            Dimensional Electrophoresis Proteomic Analysis
                     OD4  Temperature-Based Refolding of Recombinant
                            Human Epidermal Growth Factor
                     OD5  Exosomal MicroRNA from Blood Plasma as a
                            Predictive Biomarker for Bleeding Manifestations in
                            Dengue Fever]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[OD6  Molecular Characterization of LIC10280, a Novel
                            Putative Virulence Factor of Leptospira interrogans in
                            yeast model
                     OD7  Knockdown of OTUB1 and OTUB2 Induces Cell Cycle
                            Arrest and Modulates Cancer Regulatory Gene
                            Expression in Hepatocellular Carcinoma Cells
                     OD8  In silico development of DNA aptamer against actin
                            protein of E. histolytica
                     OD9  A Case Report of a Novel De Novo FBN1 c.2342del
                            Leading to Premature Termination Codon in Marfan
                            Syndrome Patients
                     OD10  Machine Learning-based Prostate Cancer Prediction
                            Model: Integrating FTIR Spectra from Urinary EVs
                            with Clinical Profiles in Modeling
                     OD11  Expression Of TNFR2 AND KI-67 In Sporadic Young-
                            Onset Crc In A Single Tertiary Center

                     OD12  KRAS Mutation Profile of Colorectal Cancer Patients
                            Diagnosed in Hospital Universiti Sains Malaysia

                     OD13  Development of Electrochemical Aptasensor for the
                            Detection of BipD Antigen of Burkholderia
                            pseudomallei for Diagnostics Application
                     OD14  Enzymatic access to the rare ΔGlcA (α1→4) Glc 3, 6,
                            N-sulfated heparin disaccharide, implications for
                            heparin quality control
                      Oral Presenter: Therapeutic
                     OT1  Evaluating the Potential of Mesenchymal Stem Cells
                            Expressing Erythropoietin for Treating Retinal
                            Dysfunction in a Rat Model
                     OT2  Therapeutic Potential of Stingless Bee Pollen:
                            Enhancing DNA Methylation and Genomic Stability
                     OT3  The role of ROS generation in the anticancer activity
                            of novel Schiff base compound in triple-negative
                            breast cancer]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[OT4  Application of in-silico approach in determining the
                            suitability of Rho GTPase and Rho GTPase activating
                            protein (RhoGAP) as drug targets of Giardia lamblia
                     OT5  Gene Expression Analysis of Giardia lamblia Small
                            GTPase, Rho subfamily protein treated with Dasatinib
                            inhibitor
                     OT6  TGFBR2 c.1220G>A Mutation and Thoracic Aortic
                            Aneurysm and Dissection Disease: Bioinformatics
                            Insights
                     OT7  Graphene Oxide and Reduced Graphene Oxide as
                            Novel Therapeutic Agents for Inhibiting Foam Cell
                            Formation and Atherosclerosis Risk Reduction
                     OT8  Anti-pigmentation and anti-ageing effects of
                            mycosporines produced by wild type and mutant
                            strains of Xanthophllomyces dendrorhous
                     OT9  Single-Cell Multiomics Reveals Monocyte-Specific
                            Dysregulation of IL1R2 and THBS1 in Colorectal
                            Cancer
                     OT10  Cytotoxic and Mutagenic Effects of Dewatered Sludge
                            Treated with Microbial Fuel Cell (MFC) using In Vitro
                            Systems
                     OT11  Determining the quantity and quality of DNA from the
                            FFPE tissues NGS library preparation: A sharing
                            experience
                     OT12  Development of Carboxymethylcellulose Hydrogel
                            from Oil Palm Empty Fruit Bunch for Efficient
                            Curcumin Delivery
                     OT13  CRISPR-Mediated Knockdown of OTUB1 and OTUB2
                            in HepG2 Cells Reveals Roles in Inflammatory
                            Pathways and Cell Viability
                     OT14  Efficacy of Stingless Bee Honey (oral and topical) in
                            Enhancing Wound Healing in STZ - induced Diabetic
                            Rat Model: An Experimental Study
                     OT15  Cytotoxic Effects of K. alvarezii Crude Extract on
                            Human Leukemia Cell Line K562]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[OT16  Andrographolide induced Apoptosis and Cell Cycle
                            Arrest in MDA-MB-231 and MCF-7 Breast Cancer
                            Cells
                     OT17  The Protective Effect of THICAPA on Familial
                            Alzheimer's Disease Pathogenesis Using Skin-derived
                            Fibroblast Cell Lines
                     Poster Presenter
                     P-1    Comparative genomic analysis of a Mycobacterium
                            tuberculosis STB-T6A strain isolated from spinal
                            epidural mass in Sabah, Malaysia
                     P-2    Biomarkers in Endothelial Dysfunction-associated
                            Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus
                     P-3    Alterations of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase
                            levels among smokers with coronary artery disease
                     P-4    The influence of receptor modulation in neurogenic
                            niche of LPC-induced demyelinated postnatal spinal
                            cord
                     P-5    Polymeric nanowires as 3D scaffold for cellular
                            cultivation intended for downstream biomarker or
                            molecular diagnostic applications
                     P-6    Identification of a novel variant in a proximal
                            symphalangism family by whole-exome sequencing
                     P-7    Multiplex PCR assay for simultaneous detection of
                            Vibrio parahaemolyticus  Vibrio alginolyticus
                     P-8    Development and comparison of primers for rapid
                            detection of Leptospira spp. using polymerase chain
                            reaction
                     P-9    Enhancing Molecular Diagnostic Testing for
                            Leptospirosis: Role of External Quality Assurance
                            (EQA) Program In Referral Laboratories
                     P-10  Application of Median Nerve Electrical Stimulation to
                            Regulate miR-1-3p in the BDNF/TrkB-MAPK Pathway
                            for Promoting Myelin Regeneration in a Rat Stroke
                            Model
                     P-11  Autoantibodies profile in paraneoplastic neurological
                            syndromes associated disorders in Malaysia]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[P-12  Genome-wide DNA methylation analysis in
                            cytogenetically normal acute myeloid leukemia (CN-
                            AML) patients from Malaysia
                     P-13  CML-miRNA Relapse Detector, a Ready-To-Use Test
                            for Guiding Treatment-Free Remission in Chronic
                            Myeloid Leukaemia Adult Patients at the Molecular
                            Response
                     P-14  Unravelling the Impact of Covid-19 Vaccination on
                            Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) Quantities: A Comparative
                            Analysis
                     P-15  Whole-Genome Sequencing Analysis of Multi-Drug
                            Resistant Salmonella enterica Serovar Typhi from
                            Clinical Isolates in Malaysia
                     P-16  Demographic Characteristics and Antifungal
                            Susceptibility of Kodamaea ohmeri Isolates from
                            Hospitals in Malaysia
                     P-17  GAPDH as a housekeeping gene expression in
                            apoptotic signaling variables and is suitable for
                            normalizing total RNA levels expression in human
                            breast cancer cells treated with dichloromethane
                            Clinacanthus nutans leaf extracts
                     P-18  MEF2A-Mediated Transcriptional Activation of
                            NFKBIA Reduces Cisplatin Resistance in Gastric
                            Cancer Cells
                     P-19  Humoral Response and Neutrophil Degranulation
                            Pathways Are Key Factors in Diffuse Large B-Cell
                            Lymphoma (DLBCL) Modulation
                     P-20  Mechanisms of Chemoresistance in Colorectal
                            Cancer: Insights from Gene Expression and Protein
                            Profiling in Cisplatin-Resistant Models
                     P-21  Spinal Muscular Atrophy (SMA) Carrier Screening in
                            Malaysia
                     P-22  Expanding The Mutational Spectrum: Identification
                            And Phenotypic Correlations Of Four Putative Novel
                            Variants In PAFAH1B1 and DCX Genes Related To
                            Lissencephaly]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[P-23  Phenotypic and Genetic Characteristics of
                            Mucopolysaccharidosis Type II Patients: A Single
                            Centre Retrospective Study in Malaysia
                     P-24  Revolutionizing Aptamer Development:
                            Electrochemical-based SELEX for Rapid Target
                            Binding
                     P-25  Manufacturing and Validation of current Good
                            Manufacturing Practices (cGMP)-Compliant Umbilical
                            Cord-Derived Mesenchymal Stromal Cells (UCMSC)
                            for Clinical Application
                     P-26  Quantitative Analysis of TNF-α Levels in Plasma:
                            Evaluating the Impact of Different Celastrol Doses in
                            High-Fat Diet-Fed ApoE-Knockout Mice Using ELISA
                     P-27  Detection Of Large Deletions And Duplication In F8
                            Gene Of Haemophilia A Patients
                     P-28  Frequency Of Anti-Acetylcholine Receptor (AChR)
                            Antibody Among Suspected Myasthenia Gravis
                            Patients In Malaysia
                     P-29  Advancing Biochemical Diagnosis of Aromatic-L-
                            Amino Acid Decarboxylase Deficiency (AADC-D):
                            HPLC-Based AADC Activity Assay Preceding Genetic
                            Testing
                     P-30  Colorimetric Aptablot Assay for the Detection of
                            Chikungunya Virus (CHIKV)
                     P-31  Discovery of Ten Novel Germline RB1 Gene
                            Mutations in Unrelated Malaysian Patients with
                            Retinoblastoma: A 12-Year Experience
                     P-32  The effect of lauric acid-rich diets in the immune
                            system: A flow cytometer analysis
                     P-33  Exploring The Positional Distribution of Fatty Acids in
                            Human Plasma Chylomicrons Using 13C Nuclear
                            Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy
                     P-34  Influence of Palm Olein on Human Gut Microbiota and
                            Gut-Fermented Short Chain Fatty Acids

                     Organizing Committee]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[PROTOCOL

                                                    COMMITTEE to add]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[PROTOCOL

                                                  COMMITTEE to add]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[PROTOCOL

                                                      COMMITTEE to add]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Agenda


                                        rd
                                 Day 1, 3  October 2024
          08:00 – 08:50   Registration
                          Associate Prof. Dr. Aziah Ismail
          08:50 – 09:00   Conference Advisor, Director of INFORMM, USM
                          “Welcoming Remarks”
                          KeyNote 1: Professor Dr. Nor Azah Yusof
          09:00 – 09:45   Universiti Putra Malaysia
                          “Enhancement of Biosensors Through Biomarkers, Sampling and
                          Design”
                          Dr. Mohd Fairulnizal Md Noh
          09:45 – 10:20   Institute for Medical Research, Malaysia
                          “The  Malaysian  Vascular  Events  Risk  (MAVERIK)  Study  –
                          Discovering Biomarkers for Myocardiac Infarction”
          10:20 – 10:30   Photo Session

          10:30 – 10:50   Coffee Break and Poster Viewing
                          Dr. Mark Skidmore
          10:50 – 11:25   Keele University, United Kingdom
                          “Therapeutic potentials of modified heparin derivatives”
                          Associate Professor Dr. Aziah Ismail
          11:25 – 12:00   Universiti Sains Malaysia, Malaysia
                          “Biosensor for Infectious Diseases”

                           xxxx
          12:00 – 12:35   Medical Device Authority (MDA), Malaysia
                          “How to Successfully Register Your Medical Device with MDA
                          Malaysia”
          12:35 – 14:00   Lunch and Poster Viewing

                          Tech-Talk
          14:00 – 14:20   Chemopharm Sdn. Bhd.

          14:30 – 17:30          Oral Session 1:
                              Diagnostic & Biomarker          Oral Session 2:
                                    Discovery                   Therapeutic

            17:30        End of Day 1]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[th
                                        Day 2, 4
                                        October
                                          2024

                          Keynote 2: Associate Professor Dr. Too Heng-Phon
           0900 – 0945    National University of Singapore, Singapore
                          “From Bench to Bedside to Business” – Translating Research
                          into Impact: A Personal Experience in Singapore
                          Dr. Catherine Hong Huan HOR
           0945 – 1020    Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong
                          Molecular and cellular pathology of hereditary neurological and
                          neuropsychiatric disorders
           1020 – 1050    Coffee Break and Poster Viewing

          11:00 – 12:30       Oral Session 3:             Oral Session 4:
                          Diagnostic & Biomarker            Therapeutic
                                Discovery
                          Closing Ceremony
          12:30 – 13:00   Presentation of prizes to best poster and oral presenters
                          Closing remarks by Chairperson
              13:00      Lunch & End of Day 2]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Keynote Speaker Abstract



           Enhancement Of Biosensors Through Biomarkers, Sampling And Design

                                                1,2,
                                    Nor Azah Yusof *
               1  Chemistry Department, Faculty of Science, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Selangor, Malaysia
           2  Institute in Nanoscience and Nanotechnology (ION2), Universiti Putra Malaysia, Selangor, Malaysia
                             *Correspondence Email: azahy@upm.edu.my


















               A  recent  development  in  biosensors  allows  rapid,  accurate,  and  on-site  detection  of
        biomarkers, which helps to prevent disease spread by the control of sources. Less invasive sample
        collection is necessary to use portable biosensors in remote environments  for accurate on-site
        diagnostics and testing. For non- or minimally invasive sampling, easily accessible body fluids, such
        as saliva, sweat, blood, or urine, have been utilized. It is also imperative to find accurate biomarkers
        to provide better clinical intervention and treatment at the onset of disease. At the same time, these
        reliable biomarkers can be utilized to monitor the progress of the disease. Emerging and validated
        biomarkers  promise  to  revolutionize  clinical  practice,  shifting  the  emphasis  away  from  the
        management of chronic disease towards prevention, early diagnosis and early intervention. The
        challenge of detecting these low abundance protein and nucleic acid biomarkers within the clinical
        context demands the development of highly sensitive, even single molecule, assays that are also
        capable of selectively measuring a small number of defined analytes in complex samples. In this talk,
        a  review  on  recent  biomarkers  in  development  of  biosensor  such  as  CRISPR,  aptamer  will  be
        discussed, together with review on design and sampling in biosensor development.]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Keynote Speaker Abstract



           From Bench to Bedside to Business – Translating Science into Impact. A
              Personal Experience in Spinning a Biotech Start-up in Singapore


                                     Too Heng Phon
                  Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore
                            Correspondence Email: bchtoohp@nus.edu.sg


















               Early cancer detection significantly improves survival rates and quality of life. However,
        about  50%  of  cancers  are  still  diagnosed  at  advanced  stages.  Innovations  in  early  detection,
        especially  liquid  biopsies,  are  promising  due  to  their  potential  to  provide  insights  on  disease
        prognosis, progression, and therapy responses in less invasive ways. Developing these innovations
        involves translating fundamental science into practical diagnostic or surveillance tools, a process
        fraught with regulatory and commercial challenges. Over the years, we have navigated and continued
        on  this  path,  facing  numerous  obstacles  in  bringing  laboratory  discoveries  to  patient  use.  Our
        journey, driven by curiosity and supported by private funding, led to the creation of the Singapore-
        based startup, MiRXES. This narrative aims to inspire those considering a transition from academia,
        demonstrating how a commitment to a meaningful vision can lead to a fulfilling and successful
        venture.]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Plenary Speaker Abstract



             The Malaysian Vascular Events Risk (MAVERIK) Study – Discovering
                           Biomarkers for Myocardial Infarction

         Mohd Fairulnizal Md Noh*, Sophia Rasheeqa Ismail, Roshan Jahn Mohd Salim, Farah
          Huda Mohkiar, Tan You Zhuan, Puteri Sofia Nadira Megat Kamaruddin, Siti Hafizah
         Zulkiply, Nurhayati Azizul, Norhayati Mustafa Khalid, Azizan Ali, Izyan Mohd Idris, Yong
               Shih Mei, Norfashihah Faridus, Shazana Rifham and Nursuffia Sulaiman

         1 Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National Institute of Health (NIH), 1 Jalan Setia Murni U13/52, Seksyen
                             U13 Setia Alam,40170 Shah Alam, Selangor
                            *Correspondence email: fairulnizal@moh.gov.my


















               Despite the high  prevalence of  premature myocardial infarction (MI)  in Malaysia, our
        understanding of the specific determinants of MI within its multi-ethnic population remains limited.
        The  Malaysian  Acute  Vascular  Events  Risk  (MAVERIK)  study  was  a  retrospective  case-control
        investigation to comprehensively explore the genomic, lipid-related, and other factors influencing
        first-onset MI in Malaysia. A total of 2,547 participants with first MI and 2500 controls without
        previous self-reported history of any cardiovascular disease were enrolled from 17 hospitals across
        Malaysia.  Rigorous  frequency-matching  by  age,  sex,  and  ethnicity  ensured  representative
        demographic  distribution.  Whole  blood,  plasma  and  serum  samples,  alongside  comprehensive
        clinical,  demographic,  and  behavioural  data  gathered  through  a  200-item  questionnaire,  were
        collected and stored for each participant. Additionally, fingernail and toenail samples were collected
        to investigate potential associations with heavy metals exposure (such as mercury, lead and arsenic)
        and its implications for cardiovascular health, including increased MI risk. Lipid profiles, glycated
        haemoglobin  (HbA1c),  and  Lipoprotein  (a)  (Lp(a))  were  analysed  due  to  their  roles  in  MI]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Plenary Speaker Abstract

        development  and  prediction.  Advanced  lipidomics  analysis  using  electrospray  ionisation  mass
        spectrometry  (ESI-MS)  followed  by  targeted  quantification  using  Mass  Spectrometry  and
        metabolomics studies utilising Neutron Magnetic Resonance (NMR) aimed to identify specific lipid
        molecules, metabolic pathways associated with MI, and potential biomarkers for early diagnosis or
        prognosis. Moreover, DNA extracted from blood samples facilitated a Genome Wide Association
        Study (GWAS) to identify genetic factors predisposing individuals to MI within the MAVERIK cohort.
        Factors such as tobacco consumption, diabetes history, hypertension, markers of visceral adiposity,
        indicators of lower socioeconomic status, and a family history of coronary disease were found to be
        more  prevalent  among  cases  than  controls.  In  conclusion,  the  MAVERIK  study  serves  as  a
        substantial, multi-ethnic epidemiological resource for coronary heart disease (CHD) in Malaysia.
        Results from heavy metal, lipidomics, and metabolomics analyses will be discussed, contributing to
        the identification and evaluation of genetic and other determinants of MI. These findings aim to
        inform regionally appropriate strategies to optimise public health interventions.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Plenary Speaker Abstract



                                         Title

                                      Aziah Ismail
                                        INFORMM
                                    Correspondence Email:]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Plenary Speaker Abstract



                                         Title

                                     Mark Skidmore

                                      Keele University
                                    Correspondence Email:]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Plenary Speaker Abstract



             Primary Cilium: A Hub for Receptors in Virus Infection and Cellular
                                    Pathophysiology

                                Catherine Hong-Huan HOR

              Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong SAR
                           Correspondence Email: catherinehor@hkbu.edu.hk

















               The primary cilium is a non-motile cilium found on the surface of nearly all cell types in
        vertebrates. It functions primarily as an "antenna" on the cell membrane to capture and transduce
        physical and chemo-signals from extracellular compartments to the cytoplasm and nucleus for cell
        signaling responses. Dysfunctional primary cilium in vertebrates adversely affects the physiological
        functions of multiple organs, including the brain. In children, defective primary cilia lead to a class
        of  heritable  disorders  collectively  known  as  ciliopathies.  However,  the  cellular  and  molecular
        implications of the primary cilium remain largely elusive. We decipher the molecular machineries
        underlying  the  transmembrane  receptor-mediated  signal  transduction  in  the  primary  cilium,
        particularly in the context of cellular neurophysiology and viral infection. Our data show that the
        primary cilium harbors cell-type-specific receptors to regulate crucial context-dependent cellular
        responses  such  as  ligand-receptor-mediated  signal  transduction,  cell  proliferation,  and  virus
        infection. Specifically, we reveal intriguing roles of the primary cilium in SARS-CoV-2 virus infection.
        Using genetically modified animal and cellular mutant models as our research platforms, we identified
        a novel causative gene of ciliopathy and shed new insights on the neuroendocrine roles of the
        primary cilium.]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[OD-1                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



        Quality Assessment of Plain Chest X-Rays of the Expatriates in Jordan: Multi-
                                     Centres Study

                                   1
                  Mohammad Ayasrah , Rasha Al Hrout  and Khaleel Rawahneh
                                                2
                                                                   3
             1  Jordan University of Science and Technology Faculty of Applied Medical Science, IRBID, IRBID
                                    GOVERNORATE, Jordan
                   2  School of Physics, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 USM, Penang, Malaysia
                       3  Madaba Health Directorate, Ministry of Health, Madaba, Jordan
               This study is a retrospective cross-sectional assessment of the quality of plain chest X-
        rays (CXRs) of expatriates in Jordan. It examines how well the American College of Radiology (ACR)
        and European Commission (EC) criteria were followed at 12 health sites. The study examined 1,020
        CXR images gathered in 2023, specifically assessing the degree to which these images adhered to
        specific radiographic quality standards. The results showed substantial discrepancies in adherence
        to various quality criteria. Although key criteria such as exposure and anatomical visualization showed
        good compliance, overall adherence to all standards was alarmingly low, with just 15% of CXRs
        meeting  the  entire  set  of  quality  requirements.  The  study  identified  specific struggles  in  organ
        superimposition and image annotation, with compliance rates of 23% and 29%, respectively. This
        work introduces a novel feature: using a quantitative classification system to evaluate the quality of
        CXR, similar to the systems used in mammography. This technique enables the more accurate and
        systematic examination of radiographs, with the potential to enhance the precision of evaluations.
        The findings emphasize the need for improved training, greater adherence to protocols, and stronger
        quality control systems to guarantee consistent quality in CXR procedures. The discrepancies in
        adherence underscore the need for systemic changes to enhance diagnostic accuracy and patient
        care. These results indicate that enforcing strict criteria more rigorously might greatly improve the
        quality of diagnostic imaging and maximize health outcomes in healthcare settings worldwide.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[OD-2                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



         The Role of Mitogen-Activated Protein Kinases and Endoplasmic Reticulum
              Stress Signaling Pathways in Annatto Tocotrienol-Induced Human
                         Chondrosarcoma SW1353 Cell Paraptosis

         Kok Lun Pang , Qixiang Wong , Yun Qi Ng , Roshan Mascarenhas , James Woon Sy-
                                                              2
                                           2
                                  2
                    1,2
                                Keen  and Kok Yong Chin *
                                                    3,
                                    2
         1  Jeffrey Cheah School of Medicine and Health Sciences, Monash University Malaysia, Jalan Lagoon Selatan,
                              47500 Subang Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia
          2  Newcastle University Medicine Malaysia, No. 1, Jalan Sarjana 1, Educity, 79200 Iskandar Puteri, Johor,
                                        Malaysia
          3  Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latif,
                         Bandar Tun Razak, 56000 Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                        *Corresponding Author: chinkokyong@ppukm.ukm.edu.my

               Chondrosarcoma is the second most common primary bone cancer and involves cartilage.
        Surgical removal is the main treatment because chondrosarcoma cells are naturally resistant to
        chemotherapy- or radiotherapy-induced cell death, regardless of stage. However, paraptosis is a
        distinct type of programmed cell death that differs from typical apoptosis. Cytoplasmic vacuolation,
        caspase independence, and dilation of the endoplasmic reticulum and/or mitochondria are its key
        distinguishing features. Paraptosis induction has significant potential as an alternative strategy for
        eliminating apoptosis-resistant cancer cells. Tocotrienol is a natural form of vitamin E found in
        various vegetable oils and nuts. It has four isoforms—α-, β-, γ-, and δ-tocotrienol, based on side-
        chain  variations  at  the  chromanol  ring.  Annatto-based  tocotrienol  (AnTT)  is  unique  because  it
        contains only γ-, and δ-tocotrienols, both of which have been widely reported to possess promising
        anticancer properties. Furthermore, γ- and δ-tocotrienol have also been shown to induce paraptosis
        in several cancer cell lines, though their molecular mechanisms remain unclear. We previously
        demonstrated that AnTT induces SW1353 chondrosarcoma cell death with extensive cytoplasmic
        vacuolation.  Simultaneously,  transcriptomic  analysis  showed  that  endoplasmic  reticulum  stress
        (ERS) and mitogen-activated protein kinases (MAPK) signaling were involved in the effects of AnTT
        treatment. Therefore, in this study, we aimed to elucidate the role of ERS and MAPKs, including p38,
        extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK), and c-Jun N-terminal kinase (JNK), in AnTT-mediated
        SW1353 cell death. The new data showed that AnTT-induced SW1353 cell death is not dependent
        on caspase activation, which is another characteristic of paraptotic cell death. Chemicals that blocked
        ERS signaling, MAPK pathways, or both exacerbated AnTT-induced, caspase-independent cell death.]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[OD-2                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        In conclusion, ERS and MAPK signaling are suggested to be involved in cancer cell defense against
        AnTT-mediated cell death. Tocotrienols, alone or in combination with ERS and/or MAPK inhibitors
        could be a potential adjuvant therapy for chondrosarcoma.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[OD-3                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




            Identification of Alpha-1 Antitrypsin as a Candidate Biomarker for Post
        COVID-19 Syndrome by Two-Dimensional Electrophoresis Proteomic Analysis

           Norbaiyah Mohamed Bakrim *, Aisyah Badrulhisham , Wan Nurliyana Wan Ramli ,
                                                                           2
                                                    1
                                 1,
                                             3
                          1
           Hairul Aini Hamzah , Nor Zamzila Abdullah , Salmah Anim Abu Hassan , Dzawani
                                                                   4
                        Muhamad , Mohd Yusri Idorus  and Alfi Khatib
                                5
                                                 6
                                                             7
        1  Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Kulliyyah of Medicine, International Islamic University Malaysia, Jalan
                             Sultan Ahmad Shah, 25200 Kuantan, Pahang
          2  Department of Internal Medicine, Kulliyyah of Medicine, International Islamic University Malaysia, Jalan
                             Sultan Ahmad Shah, 25200 Kuantan, Pahang
         3  Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Kulliyyah of Medicine, International Islamic University
                        Malaysia, Jalan Sultan Ahmad Shah, 25200 Kuantan, Pahang
          4  Department of Orthopaedics, Traumatology & Rehabilitation, Kulliyyah of Medicine, International Islamic
                    University Malaysia, Jalan Sultan Ahmad Shah, 25200 Kuantan, Pahang
           5  Department of Medicine, Hospital Tengku Ampuan Afzan, Jalan Tanah Putih, 25100 Kuantan, Pahang
                6  Institute of Medical Molecular Biotechnology, UiTM Sungai Buloh, 47000, Selangor
         7  Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Kulliyyah of Pharmacy, International Islamic University Malaysia,
                           Jalan Sultan Ahmad Shah, 25200 Kuantan, Pahang
                            *Corresponding Author: drbaiyah@iium.edu.my

               Despite a significant decrease in Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) case prevalence since
        the end of pandemic phase and effectiveness of the vaccination program, some patients continue to
        experience symptoms beyond three months of infection known as Post COVID-19 Syndromes (PSC).
        Common manifestations include enduring cough, shortness of breath and fatigue, which adversely
        affect quality of life. The primary challenge in managing PCS is its diagnosis, which relies on clinical
        symptoms and exclusion of other possible diagnoses. This approach is time-consuming, involves
        numerous tests and procedures, and leads to delayed initiation of appropriate intervention. Therefore,
        identifying  reliable  biomarkers  for  PCS  is  crucial  for  improving  diagnosis  accuracy,  predicting
        outcomes, and developing targeted therapies. This study compared the proteomic profiles between
        PCS patients and healthy controls to identify disease-specific proteins that could serve as candidate
        biomarkers. This was a comparative cross-sectional study that recruited six PCS patients who fulfilled
        the inclusion criteria; persistent symptoms more than three months post infection with diagnosis was
        confirmed by a physician at the Post COVID-19 clinic. The control group consisted of 10 age, gender
        and race matched healthy subjects with no history of infection for the past one year. Protein of pooled
        serum  from  each  group  were  extracted  and  separated  using  two-dimensional  electrophoresis]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[OD-3                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        method. Firstly, the proteins were separated via iso-electric point, then via different molecular weight.
        The protein spots were analysed using PD Quest software, and proteins expression with significant
        difference between the two groups were recognized. Subsequently, proteins of interest were analysed
        using Matrix Assisted Laser Desorption/Ionization Time-of-Flight (MALDI-TOF) Mass Spectrometry
        for protein identification. All subjects were Malay females with mean age of 38 ± 9.7 for PCS group
        and 42 ± 11.8 years for healthy control. Persistent cough and fatigue were found to be the most
        common presentations (83%) followed by exertional dyspnoea (67%). Proteomic profiles analysis
        reveals 182 proteins spots were detected in serum PCS patients in a range of pH 4 to 7. Alpha-1
        antitrypsin, with molecular weight of 46.7 kDa was identified among the proteins that significantly
        over-expressed when compared to control (p=0.02). This protein is a protypical protease inhibitor
        that protects lung tissue from proteolytic damage by inhibiting neutrophil elastase. The elevated
        levels of Alpha-1 antitrypsin in the serum of PCS patients align with its known antiviral and anti-
        inflammatory properties, suggesting that it could serve as a potential diagnostic marker for PCS.]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[OD-4                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




           Temperature-Based Refolding of Recombinant Human Epidermal Growth
                                        Factor

                 Ru Shen Wong, Mervyn W. O. Liew and Eugene Boon Beng Ong*

         Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 USM, Penang,
                                        Malaysia
                              *Corresponding author: eugene@usm.my

               The formation of recombinant human epidermal growth factor (rhEGF) inclusion bodies
        (IBs) often occurs due to the high-level expression of recombinant proteins in Escherichia coli. To
        obtain the bioactive rhEGF from IBs, solubilization of rhEGF IBs into a linear form and refolding into
        correctly  folded  bioactive  rhEGF  are  required.  However,  conventional  methods  require  a  high
        concentration of denaturant to solubilize the IBs and multiple dialysis steps to remove the denaturant
        for protein refolding. In this study, the temperature-based refolding (TBR) of rhEGF was developed,
        using lower denaturant concentration for IB solubilization and requiring fewer dialysis steps. The
        factors affecting the TBR were investigated, and their optimal conditions were also determined.
        Additionally, a comparison between TBR and conventional methods was conducted. Purified rhEGF
        IBs  (1  µg/µL)  were  solubilized  and  refolded  in  different  combinations  of  factors  (Incubation
        Temperature, Denaturant concentration, incubation time, and cooling Rate) and dialyzed against 1×
        PBS. The rhEGF content was measured via reverse-phase high-performance liquid chromatography.
        Among the four factors, only incubation temperature, denaturant concentration, and incubation time
        affected the TBR of rhEGF, with the highest recovery of rhEGF content at 90°C with 3M guanidine
        hydrochloride for 60 minutes. Furthermore, TBR increased the rhEGF yield by 325%   (~ 10.36
        µg)  compared to the conventional method (~ 2.44 µg). Thus, the recovery of rhEGF via TBR can be
        a suitable method for the recovery of rhEGF from bacterial IBs.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[OD-5                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



            Exosomal MicroRNA from Blood Plasma as a Predictive Biomarker for
                         Bleeding Manifestations in Dengue Fever

                  Gokulakannan Venkatesan , Nik Nur Syazana Nik Mohamed Kamal , Wan
                                                                      1
                                       1
                                                                           4
                                                               3
                                             2
                             1
          Nazatul Shima Shahidan , Salfarina Iberahim , Edinur Hisham Atan , Azura Hussin ,
                                   1
                      Norliana Ghazali  and Wan Suriana Wan Ab Rahman
                                                               1
            1  School of Dental Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Health Campus, 16150 Kota Bharu, Kelantan
         2  Department of Haematology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Health Campus, 16150
                                     Kota Bharu, Kelantan
            3  School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Health Campus, 16150 Kota Bharu, Kelantan
              4  Department of Pathology, Hospital Raja Perempuan Zainab 2, 15586 Kota Bharu, Kelantan
               Dengue virus infection is recognized as one of the most important mosquito-borne human
        diseases of the 21st century. It can manifest clinically as a moderate febrile illness, or a severe life-
        threatening disease called dengue hemorrhagic fever. Notably, there are currently no predictive
        diagnostic values for individuals prone to bleeding manifestations associated with this infection. This
        study explores the potential solution by focusing on exosomes, lipid vesicles enriched in specific
        microRNA. These exosomal microRNAs have the potential to form a disease-specific diagnostic
        signature,  paving  the way  for an analysis  of  exosomal  plasma microRNA  expression to predict
        bleeding tendency in dengue infection. This study aimed to investigate the potential of exosomal
        plasma microRNA expression as a predictive biomarker for bleeding tendencies in dengue virus
        infection. In total, 52 blood plasma exosome samples, dengue without warning signs (n = 26) and
        dengue  with  warning  signs  (n  =  26)  were  used  to  isolate  total  RNA.  Small  RNA  analysis  and
        microarray-based expression profiling were used to detect the miRNA profile of plasma exosomes
        to identify predictive biomarker for bleeding manifestations in patients with warning sign as compared
        to patients without warning signs. Predicted target genes were done using TargetScan and miRDB.
        A PPI network was constructed, and the network was analysed in Cytoscape to identify hub genes.
        This integrated approach helps in understanding the potential regulatory roles of miRNAs and their
        associated genes in cellular processes. The microarray profiling result revealed that 24 miRNAs were
        upregulated with a fold change cut-off value at log2 > 2.0 in the plasma-derived exosome miRNA in
        the dengue patients with warning signs.  In this study, hsa-miR-107 and hsa-miR-6879-5p were
        reliable candidates for predicting bleeding tendency in dengue fever. Functional analysis of target
        genes of these miRNAs in silico indicated their involvement in bleeding manifestation in dengue
        infection. Thus, this study highlighted hsa-miR-107 and hsa-miR-6879-5p as promising biomarkers]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[OD-5                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        for predicting bleeding in dengue fever. Further exploration of their clinical implications could pave
        the way for improved diagnostic strategies in dengue-infected individuals.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[OD-6                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



         Molecular Characterization of LIC10280, a Novel Putative Virulence Factor of
                          Leptospira interrogans in yeast model

                  Zhen Pei Wong , Aik-Hong Teh  and Eugene Boon Beng Ong *
                                                                  1,
                              1
                                           2
        1  Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 USM, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia
           2  Centre for Chemical Biology, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11900 Bayan Lepas, Pulau Pinang Malaysia

                              *Corresponding Author: eugene@usm.my
               Pathogenic Leptospira species are the cause of leptospirosis, a zoonotic disease. However,
        the molecular mechanisms of leptospiral pathogenesis are still unclear, as many genes related to
        virulence are still undiscovered. The budding yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae is a popular eukaryotic
        model that has been used as an alternative model to identify bacterial VFs that target conserved
        eukaryotic cellular processes. Previously, our group has identified a protein with unknown function,
        LIC10280, as potential candidate VFs of Leptospira interrogans from yeast growth inhibition assay.
        In  current  study,  we  validated  the  protein  LIC10280  as  a  leptospiral  VF,  studying  molecular
        characteristics and its function in leptospiral pathogenesis. First, in silico analysis is carried out on
        protein  sequence  of  LIC10280  to  predict  and  analyse  its  molecular  properties,  function,  and
        structure. Next,  the  targeted  eukaryotic  cellular  processes  or  molecules  of  LIC10280  were
        investigated in the yeast cell model. Then, the interaction between LIC10280 and host components
        was  investigated by in vitro studies.  As the results showed,  protein LIC10280 is predicted  as  a
        secretory protein that contains a signal peptide at the N-terminus of the protein sequence. Only
        heterologous expression of the full-length sequence of protein LIC10280 showed yeast growth
        inhibition activity, reduced the yeast cells’ viability, and the possibility of causing DNA fragmentation.
        The mature protein part of LIC10280 showed nucleus-binding properties in the yeast microscopy
        study.  This study is still ongoing to identify the possible target molecule(s) or cellular process of
        protein LIC10280 to better understand the pathogenesis of leptospirosis.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[OD-7                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




          Knockdown of OTUB1 and OTUB2 Induces Cell Cycle Arrest and Modulates
            Cancer Regulatory Gene Expression in Hepatocellular Carcinoma Cells

                             Wu Yanming and Nurulisa Zulkifle*

        Department of Biomedical Sciences, Advanced Medical and Dental Institute, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Bertam,
                               13200 Kepala Batas, Penang, Malaysia

                              *Corresponding Author: nurulisa@usm.my

               Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) is a leading cause of cancer mortality worldwide, ranking
        among  the  top  six  cancers  globally.  Despite  advances  in  molecular  markers,  HCC  remains
        challenging to treat, necessitating ongoing research into novel therapeutic targets. Deubiquitinating
        enzymes (DUBs) such as OTUB1 and OTUB2 are implicated in these processes and are found to be
        upregulated in HCC. This study aims to investigate the effects of OTUB1 and OTUB2 knockdown on
        cell cycle progression and gene expression in HCC cells to evaluate their potential as therapeutic
        targets. To achieve this, HepG2 KRAB  stable cells were transfected with CRISPR guide RNA plasmids
        targeting OTUB1 and OTUB2 using Lipofectamine. Subsequently, Cell cycle analysis was conducted
        using  Propidium  Iodide  (PI)  staining.  Furthermore,  RT-PCR  was  performed  using  primers  for
        selected cancer-related genes, including c-Myc, TP53, HIF-1α, VEGF, Bcl-2, NF-κB, and CDH-1.
        Finally, Statistical analyses were conducted using SPSS with significance set at p<0.05. As a result,
        PI staining shows a significant increase in the proportion of HepG2 KRAB/OTUB1  and HepG2 KRAB/OTUB2  cells
        in the G-phase (11.74% and 12.78%, respectively) compared to control groups (6.91% for HepG2
                                                                             WT
        and 6.14% for HepG2 KRAB ). Moreover, A similar pattern was observed in the S-phase, with increases
        to 30.45% and 28.80% in HepG2 KRAB/OTUB1  and HepG2 KRAB/OTUB2  respectively, compared to control
        groups  (20.03%  for  HepG2   and  21.02%  for  HepG2 KRAB ).  Meanwhile,  RT-PCR  analysis
                              WT
        demonstrates  a  significant  reduction  in  OTUB1  and  OTUB2  mRNA  levels  following  CRISPR
        knockdown. In HepG2 KRAB/OTUB1  cells, c-Myc expression decreased by 2.2-fold, TP53 by 2.8-fold, and
        HIF-1α and VEGF by 2.3-fold and 2.1-fold, respectively. Bcl-2, NF-κB, and CDH-1 levels were also
        significantly reduced by 3.1-fold, 2.0-fold and 2.4-fold, respectively. HepG2 KRAB/OTUB2  showed similar
        but less pronounced reductions in gene expression compared to HepG2 KRAB/OTUB1 . Based on these
        findings, the increase in G-phase and S-phase percentages in PI staining indicates that knockdown
        of OTUB1 and OTUB2 leads to cell cycle arrest at the G2/S transition, hindering normal cell cycle
        progression.  Consequently,  this  arrest  results  in  reduced  cellular  proliferation,  suggesting  that]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[OD-7                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        OTUB1  and  OTUB2  are  critical  for  promoting  cell  cycle  advancement  in  HCC.  Moreover,  The
        downregulation of oncogenes such as c-Myc and the tumor suppressor TP53 further supports
        impaired tumor growth and enhanced apoptosis. Additionally, decreased HIF-1α and VEGF levels
        suggest impaired angiogenesis, potentially slowing tumor progression and metastasis. In conclusion
        Knockdown of OTUB1 and OTUB2 disrupts key oncogenic pathways in HCC, leading to cell cycle
        arrest and reduced tumorigenic potential. Thus, these enzymes show promising therapeutic targets,
        offering new avenues for intervention in liver cancer treatment.]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[OD-8                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



         In silico development of DNA aptamer against actin protein of E. histolytica

                                                                       1,
             Syahrul Amin Sa’adon , Nadiah Abdul Rashid  and Nurulhasanah Othman *
                               1
                                                 2
           1  Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Main Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia,
                             Georgetown, 11800, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia
         2  Department of Biotechnology, Kulliyah of Science, International Islamic University Malaysia (IIUM), Bandar
                           Indera Mahkota, 25200 Kuantan, Pahang, Malaysia
                            *Corresponding Author: nurulhasanah@usm.my

               Amoebiasis imposes a substantial burden on low- and middle-income countries, including
        Malaysia, and necessitates timely and precise diagnosis to prevent severe outcomes such as amoebic
        liver abscess and mortality. However, current diagnostic methods rely primarily on microscopic and
        molecular  tests  like  PCR  and  ELISA.  In  response  to  this  challenge,  we  explore  an  innovative
        approach:  enhancing  aptamer  design  through  in  silico  methods  to  meet  specific  binding
        requirements for biomolecule targets (actin protein of E. histolytica). Unlike antibodies, Aptamers, a
        single-stranded RNA or DNA with a unique tertiary structure that offers advantages such as high
        affinity,  minimal  immunogenicity,  and  reusability.  Nevertheless,  despite  their  potential,  aptamer
        development remains labor-intensive and costly due to reliance on SELEX technology. To address
        this,  the  3D  structure  of a  single  oligonucleotide  strand  was  modeled to  contain  hairpin(s)  and
        predicted to retain folding stability based on the free energy of secondary structure formation. Next,
        optimization of the size and number of hairpins was conducted in concert with the aptamer sequence
        length, employing a local docking procedure via AutoDock Vina. Subsequently, the performance and
        reliability of the resultant aptamer structure in targeting the actin protein of E. histolytica were further
        assessed using molecular docking and molecular dynamics (MD) simulation. The results showed
        that five aptamers exhibiting the lowest docking energies against the actin protein were identified
        using AutoDock Vina. Moreover, the clustering of molecular dynamics (MD) trajectories provided a
        more precise representation of the binding interactions, from which Apt1 and Apt8 emerged as the
        most suitable candidates for the actin protein. This study showed that the dynamic H-bond formation
        between the active binding residues and nucleotides stabilizes Apt1 and Apt8 binding on actin
        protein. In conclusion, the computational prediction of complex binding will include validations
        through experimental assays in future studies. This approach makes it easier and cheaper to develop
        better aptamers.]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[OD-9                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




          A Case Report of a Novel De Novo FBN1 c.2342del Leading to Premature
                     Termination Codon in Marfan Syndrome Patients

                                                               2
                         1
                                                  1
         Anis Hazirah Azman , Ahmad Norasidi Mohd Raffie , Chew Hui Bein , Muzhirah Aisha
                    Md Haniffa , Keng Wee Teik , Mohd Nazif Samat Darawi *
                             2
                                          2
                                                                1,
                         1  Faculty of Health Sciences, Universiti Selangor, Malaysia
                         2  Department of Genetics, Hospital Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                     *Corresponding Author: nazifsamat@gmail.com, nazif@unisel.edu.my
               Marfan syndrome (MFS) is an autosomal dominant connective tissue disorder affecting
        various body systems, mainly cardiovascular, ocular, and skeletal systems. This disease results from
        a mutation in the FBN1 gene, which governs the production of fibrillin-1 protein vital for the integrity
        of  the  extracellular  matrix  across  various  bodily  tissues.  Over  7,000  FBN1  variants  have  been
        reported, with a majority being unique to each pedigree. The presence of numerous FBN1 variants
        has led to diverse phenotypic manifestations, varying severity levels, and different ages of onset
        posing challenges for diagnosis, treatment, and prognosis. Genomic DNA was extracted from a
        buccal swab specimen obtained from an 11-year-old girl who fulfilled the Ghent Nosology criteria
        and was subjected to exome sequencing (3Billion, Inc, Korea). A deletion of nucleotide (c.2342del)
        in the FBN1 gene was detected in the sample. Subsequently, a pair of primers was designed and
        utilized to flank and amplify the DNA region containing the mutation for other related family members.
        The  amplicons  generated  from  the  polymerase  chain  reaction  were  then  subjected  to  Sanger
        sequencing. The cloning step followed by Sanger sequencing was necessary in the case of the
        heterozygous  sample.  Prediction  of  protein  structure  was  conducted  using  AlphaFold2.  FBN1
        c.2342del causes a shift in the reading frame at codon 781 resulting in a premature termination
        codon at position 22 downstream from the original mutation site (p.Cys781LeufsTer22). Sanger
        sequencing revealed the same mutation in the proband’s twin but not in their parents and other
        family members. This indicates that the mutation occurred as a de novo event, meaning it arose
        spontaneously  rather  than  being  inherited.  AlphaFold's  protein  prediction  demonstrates  high
        confidence in the local positioning of individual amino acid residues, except at positions around 0-
        100, 400, and 800, but exhibits low confidence in the relative domain positioning. The primers
        successfully amplified the correct segment of FBN1. Since the mutation is heterozygous in certain
        samples, DNA cloning followed by Sanger sequencing was employed to identify the normal and
        mutated allele. The identified mutation is classified as a likely pathogenic. It is predicted to result in]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[OD-9                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        a loss or disruption of normal protein function through nonsense-mediated decay (NMD) or protein
        truncation.  Further validation through experimental study is needed to confirm the prediction from
        AlphaFold2. This research significantly enhanced the understanding of MFS. The discovery of the
        novel FBN1 variant c.2342del (p.Cys781LeufsTer22) contributes to the expanding databases and
        mutation repositories related to MFS.]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[OD-10                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




         Machine Learning-based Prostate Cancer Prediction Model: Integrating FTIR
                 Spectra from Urinary EVs with Clinical Profiles in Modeling

          Le-Wei Wong , Razvan Ghiarasim , Janarthanan Supramaniam , Zhen-Hui Bu , Bey-
                     1
                                                                       4
                                                           3
                                    2
                       Hing Goh 5,6,7 , Lam-Hong Lee  and Wai-Leng Lee *
                                              4
                                                             1,
         1  School of Science, Monash University Malaysia, 47500 Bandar Sunway, Selangor Darul Ehsan, Malaysia;
             2  Centre of Advanced Research in Bionanoconjugates and Biopolymers, "Petru Poni" Institute of
                             Macromolecular Chemistry, Iasi, Romania;
         3  School of Pharmacy, Monash University Malaysia, 47500 Bandar Sunway, Selangor Darul Ehsan, Malaysia;
             4  Data Ecosystem Research and Development Centre, School of Computing, Quest International
                          University, 30250 Ipoh, Perak Darul Ridzuan, Malaysia;
         5  Sunway Biofunctional Molecules Discovery Centre (SBMDC), School of Medical and Life Sciences, Sunway
                                  University, Sunway, Malaysia;
          6  Faculty of Health, Australian Research Centre in Complementary and Integrative Medicine, University of
                             Technology Sydney, Ultimo, NSW, Australia;
           7  Biofunctional Molecule Exploratory Research Group (BMEX), School of Pharmacy, Monash University
                      Malaysia, Bandar Sunway, Selangor Darul Ehsan, 47500, Malaysia;

                          *Corresponding Author: Lee.Wai.Leng@monash.edu
               This study aims to develop an extracellular vesicle (EV)--based machine learning (ML)
        predictive model for prostate cancer. Screening with Prostate-Specific Antigen (PSA) has enabled
        early prostate cancer detection; however, its limited specificity and high false-positive rates often
        lead to unnecessary biopsies and over-treatment. Recently, urinary EVs have emerged as potential
        biomarkers for prostate cancer. Recent advancements in ML-assisted spectroscopic analysis of liquid
        biopsies have shown potential to develop a non-invasive predictive model for prostate cancer using
        FTIR spectral markers from urinary EVs. In this study, we enrolled 33 male participants, including 16
        with pathologically confirmed prostate cancer and 17 non-cancerous individuals. The cohort was
        divided into training and testing sets in a 4:1 ratio. Datasets from 3601 FTIR features acquired from
        urinary EVs, and clinical profiles, including demographics, PSA values, and past medical history were
        integrated into the modeling. FTIR features were extracted with data weighting by the Gain Ratio
        algorithm, whereas the clinical features were manually selected based on their relevance to prostate
        cancer.  ML  classifiers,  including  k-Nearest  Neighbors  (k-NN),  Support  Vector  Machine  (SVM),
        Decision Tree (DT), and Naïve Bayes (NB), were trained using different combinations of the datasets
        with a five-fold cross-validation technique. The performance of the best-trained model was then
        evaluated on the testing set. Using FTIR features alone, the highest performance was achieved by]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[OD-10                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        the NB classifier when trained with the top 100 ranked FTIR features, with 85.1% area under the
        curve (AUC) of ROC and 84.6% accuracy. Notably, training the classifiers with PSA alone, which
        ranged from 1.09 to 102.56 ng/mL in this patient cohort, yielded unsatisfactory performance, with
        the NB classifier achieving the highest performance of 64.6% AUC and 73.1% accuracy. Despite
        PSA being a standard biomarker for prostate cancer, its limited classification performance indicates
        that relying solely on PSA for screening may be insufficient. Additional features or approaches are
        therefore required to improve the screening accuracy. Interestingly, combining both FTIR and clinical
        features offers a more holistic approach to model training, resulting in enhanced AUC and accuracy
        of 89.0% and 84.6%, respectively achieved by the DT model. When evaluating the DT model using
        the testing dataset, it demonstrated decent performance, with the AUC and accuracy reaching 91.7%
        and 85.7%. This study highlights the potential of ML classifiers to effectively exploit the spectral
        biomarkers derived from urinary EVs and clinical features that are indicative of cancer presence to
        address the limitations of PSA-based cancer screening.

               .]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[OD-11                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




            Expression of Tumor Necrosis Factor Receptor 2 (TNFR2) and Ki-67 in
          Sporadic Young-Onset Colorectal Cancer (CRC) in a Single Tertiary Center

                                                       2,4
                                1
          Nurul Hakimah Mohd Salim , Andee Dzulkarnaen Zakaria , Wan Faiziah Wan Abdul
         Rahman , Rohimah Mohamud , Siti Norasikin Mohd Nafi  and Nur Asyilla Che Jalil *
                                                                           1,4,
               1,4
                                                      1
                                  3
         1  Department of Pathology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia Health Campus, Kubang
                                   Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia
          2  Department of Surgery, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia Health Campus, Kubang
                                   Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia
         3  Department of Immunology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia Health Campus, Kubang
                                   Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia
                     4 Hospital Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia
                              *Corresponding Author: asyilla@usm.my

               Colorectal cancer (CRC) is currently the second leading cause of cancer-related death,
        with increasing prevalence among younger individuals. To date, the prevalence of CRC among young
        individuals has become alarming. The roles of Tumour Necrosis Factor Receptor 2 (TNFR2) and Ki-
        67 in modulating the disease prognosis have gained much attention from researchers. TNFR2 is
        found in tumor cells and tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs), which include immune-suppressing
        Tregs. It is often linked to cytokines that cause inflammation. This receptor expression can trigger
        the release of inflammatory cytokines and enhance the activity of immunosuppressive cells, allowing
        tumor  cells  to  evade  immune  system  mechanisms.  Ki-67  is  a  protein  that  plays  a  role  in  the
        proliferation of tumor cells, leading to a worse prognosis of the disease. Therefore, this study aimed
        to determine the expression of TNFR2 and Ki-67 and their associations with the clinicopathological
        features of young-onset colorectal cancer (YOCRC) in a single tertiary center. This retrospective
        study involved 36 patients (<50 years old) diagnosed with sporadic CRC between January 2013 and
        December 2023 at Hospital Universiti Sains Malaysia. TNFR2 and Ki-67 immunohistochemistry were
        performed and evaluated using immunoreactive scoring. The data were analyzed using descriptive
        statistics and Fischer's exact test, with P≤0.05 considered significant. The results revealed that most
        patients were female, with a predominance of Malays. The most common symptoms were altered
        bowel habits and non-specific abdominal pain. The most frequently observed histological types were
        conventional adenocarcinoma, signet ring cell carcinoma, mucinous, and neuroendocrine carcinoma.
        The majority of cases were diagnosed at stages III and IV, featuring moderately differentiated tumors,
        predominantly situated on the left side. No significant links were found between TNFR2 expression]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[OD-11                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        and  other  clinicopathological  features.  However,  significant  links  were  found  between  TNFR2
        expression and the stage of the tumor (p<0.03) as well as the number of TILs present (p<0.03).
        Additionally, Ki-67 expression showed a significant correlation with the level of TILs (p<0.02) but
        did not have significant associations with other clinicopathological characteristics. These findings
        suggest that TNFR2 and Ki-67 play crucial roles in the progression and prognosis of YOCRC. This
        study  also  emphasizes  the  potential  of  these  markers  as  prognostic  indicators  and  their  future
        application in the clinical management of the disease.]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[OD-12                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




          KRAS Mutation Profile of Colorectal Cancer Patients Diagnosed in Hospital
                                Universiti Sains Malaysia

                   1
         Ng Phei Ying , Siti Norasikin Mohd Nafi *, Nur Asyilla Che Jalil , Anani Aila Mat Zin ,
                                                                           1,4
                                                          1,4
                                        1,
                           Lee Yeong Yeh  and Kueh Yee Cheng
                                       2,4
                                                          3
          1  Department of Pathology, School of Medical Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 16150
                                Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia
          2  Department of Medicine, School of Medical Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 16150
                                Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia
         3  Biostatistics and Research Methodology Unit, School of Medical Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains
                           Malaysia, 16150 Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, Malaysia
           4  Hospital Universiti Sains Malaysia, Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 16150 Kubang Kerian,
                                     Kelantan, Malaysia
                              *Corresponding Author: snmn@usm.my

               Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third most common cancer globally and the second most
        common in Malaysia. KRAS is a strong negative predictive biomarker for anti-EGFR therapy in CRC,
        making its detection mandatory for late-stage treatment decisions. This emphasizes the importance
        of gene mutation detection in precision medicine. This study aimed to determine the KRAS mutation
        profile  of  CRC  patients  in  HUSM  via  targeted  next-generation  sequencing  (NGS)  and  direct
        sequencing approaches. Archival CRC tissue blocks were retrieved from the Pathology laboratory,
        HUSM. Gene mutations, including KRAS, were determined using the TruSight Tumor 15 (TST15)
        panel through targeted NGS (n = 12). KRAS exon 2 profiling, which covered the detection of codon
        12 and 13 variants, was then conducted using direct Sanger sequencing (n = 54). Using the TST15
        panel, 66.7% of CRC cases were detected with KRAS mutations (G12C (25%); G12D (25%); G12S
        (12.5%); G12A (12.5%); A146T (12.5%); and A146V (12.5%)), whereas 33.3% of CRC cases were
        found with wild-type KRAS. Through direct sequencing, 44.4% of CRC cases were found with KRAS
        mutation, whereas 55.6% had wild-type KRAS. Most of the cases were detected with the KRAS variant
        G12D (87.5%), followed by G12C (4.2%), G12S (4.2%), and G12A (4.2%). Two cases with KRAS
        exon 4 variants A146T and A146V found targeted NGS were excluded from the comparison of the
        findings. Using both approaches, seven cases showed similar findings: two cases of G12D and one
        case of G12S (variant frequency in targeted NGS: 34.4%, 36.1%, and 53.5%, respectively), and four
        cases of wild-type KRAS. In contrast for another three cases: two cases of G12C and one case of
        G12A (variant frequency in targeted NGS: 23.8%, 34.4%, and 11.4%, respectively) were detected]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[OD-12                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        using targeted NGS, but all three cases were found with wild-type KRAS using direct sequencing.
        Thus, those with variant frequencies of ≤34.4% in targeted NGS were possibly detected or missed
        through  direct  sequencing.  Using  two  molecular  techniques  NGS  and  direct  sequencing,  our
        investigation identified several variants of the KRAS gene in patients with CRC.]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[OD-13                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




            Development of Electrochemical Aptasensor for the Detection of BipD
              Antigen of Burkholderia pseudomallei for Diagnostics Application

         Kasturi Selvam, Mohamad Ahmad Najib, Muhammad Fazli Khalid, Muhammad Hafiznur
                     Yunus, Khairul Mohd Fadzli Mustaffa and Ismail Aziah*
         Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian 16150,
                                     Kelantan, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: aziahismail@usm.my

               Melioidosis, an infectious disease caused by Burkholderia pseudomallei, is prevalent in
        tropical regions and is associated with high mortality rates. The current gold standard for diagnosing
        melioidosis is culture, a method that is time-consuming and prone to cause false negative results,
        emphasizing the urgent need for rapid, sensitive, and specific diagnostic tests. In this study, a label-
        free  electrochemical  biosensor,  named  Melioidosis  Aptasensor,  was  developed  to  detect
        Burkholderia  invasion  protein  D  (BipD)  antigen  of  B.  pseudomallei,  aiming  to  address  the
        aforementioned diagnostic challenges. The Melioidosis Aptasensor was fabricated using screen-
        printed gold electrodes (SPGE). The BipD protein-specific aptamer, AptBipD1, was thiolated at the
        5' end and reduced with tris(2-carboxyethyl)phosphine (TCEP) before being immobilized onto the
        working  electrode  overnight  in  a  water-saturated  environment.  The  electrode  surface  was  then
        passivated with 6-mercaptohexanol (MCH) to reduce non-specific binding before the incubation with
        BipD protein for 30 minutes. Current measurements were performed using a 5 mM potassium
        ferro/ferricyanide solution in 10X PBS buffer at pH 7.4. Following sensor fabrication, the aptamer
        concentration was optimized between 0.5 µM and 2 µM. Moreover, the specificity of Aptasensor was
        evaluated  with  lysates  from  B.  pseudomallei  and  various  Gram-negative  pathogenic  bacteria,
        including Salmonella Typhi, Shigella flexneri, Klebsiella pneumoniae, and Escherichia coli. The limit
        of detection (LoD) of aptasensor was determined through linear regression analysis by spiking both
        the buffer solution (1X PBS, pH 7.4) and healthy serum with BipD protein serially diluted from 1
        µg/mL. A reduction in current was observed at each step during fabrication, indicating a decrease in
        the rate of electron transfer between the redox species and the electrode. The optimal aptamer
        concentration was 2 µM to provide sufficient binding sites for capturing the target. The aptasensor
        demonstrated  high  specificity,  as  confirmed  by  one-way  ANOVA  (p  <  0.001),  highlighting  a
        significant difference between B. pseudomallei and other tested bacteria, thereby minimizing false-
        positive results. Furthermore, the aptasensor achieved LoD of 2.52 ng/mL in buffer solution and]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[OD-13                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        2.29 ng/mL in serum, showcasing its ability to detect low concentrations of BipD protein. These
        results suggest that the developed aptasensor is a highly specific and sensitive tool for the detection
        of B. pseudomallei, offering significant potential for improving the diagnosis of melioidosis.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[OD-14                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




           Enzymatic access to the rare ΔGlcA (α1→4) Glc 3, 6, N-sulfated heparin
                   disaccharide, implications for heparin quality control

                                     Taran Kandola

                                      Keele University
                                   *Corresponding Author:]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[OT-1                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




              Evaluating the Potential of Mesenchymal Stem Cells Expressing
               Erythropoietin for Treating Retinal Dysfunction in a Rat Model

                      1,
                                        1
           Mok Pooi Ling *, Avin Koh Ee-Hwan , Shirley Ding Suet Lee , Mohd Hairul Nizam
                                                           1
             2
                                     2
                                                   2
                                                                  2
        Harun , Mae-Lynn Catherine Bastion , Lam Chenshen , Then Kong Yong , Munirah Binti
                                          3
                              2
                     Abd Rashid , Ng Min Hwei  and Suresh Kumar Subbiah
                                                                 4
           1  Department of Biomedical Science, Faculty of Medicine & Health Sciences, Universiti Putra Malaysia,
                                     Selangor, Malaysia
         2  Department of Ophthalmology, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre, Kuala
                                     Lumpur, Malaysia
           3  Tissue Engineering Centre, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Center, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                     4  Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Chennai, India
                            *Corresponding Author: pooi_ling@upm.edu.my
               Deterioration in visual function is a consequence of degeneration of retinal neuronal cells
        due to aging and commonly worsens when a patient has already underlying diseases, such as
        untreated diabetes mellitus. Stem cells have demonstrated potential clinical value in restoring the
        function of damaged tissues in many disease models. However, the efficacy of stem cell treatment
        can  be  affected  by  their  reduced  survivability  in  a  pathologically  harmful  or  inflamed  tissue
        microenvironment. In this study, we aimed to investigate the therapeutic potential of genetically-
        modified Mesenchymal Stem Cells (MSCs) to express erythropoietin protein (MSCs ) to reverse
                                                                    EPO
        retinal neuronal cell degeneration and improve the visual function using a Sprague Dawley rat model.
        EPO is an anti-apoptotic protein, and its receptor is highly expressed on the retina to protect the
        eyes from intense light exposure in the early morning. The genetically-modified cells were produced
        by transducing a lentiviral vector encoding a human EPO gene into human Wharton-Jelly MSCs. The
        transduced cells were sorted, confirmed to secrete the EPO protein by ELISA, and culture-expanded
        for further downstream experiments. The MSCs  was evaluated for their ability to differentiate into
                                          EPO
        neurospheres and reduce Y79 retinal neuronal cell damage induced by glutamate solution in vitro.
        The cells were then transplanted intravitreally into the rats which were treated prior with sodium
        iodate. Electroretinography (ERG) was performed on the rats before they were sacrificed to harvest
        the retina tissues for histological and gene expression analyses after one month of transplantation.
                                                                       EPO
        The in vitro results indicated a relatively larger neurosphere formation from the MSCs , and a
        significantly enhanced survival of the Y79 cells when they were exposed to conditioned media
        harvested  from  the  MSCs   group  when  compared  with  unmodified  MSCs.  There  was  also  a
                           EPO]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[OT-1                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        significantly increased fold change in the b-wave amplitude, a relatively thicker retina, and expression
        of a unique profile of genes that likely contributed to the survival of retinas exposed to sodium iodate
                             EPO
        when transplanted with MSC  compared to unmodified MSCs or sham control rat groups. In
        summary, the findings of our study showed the tremendous potential of MSCs EPO  in protecting the
        retina from retinal degeneration.]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[OT-2                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




          Therapeutic Potential of Stingless Bee Pollen: Enhancing DNA Methylation
                                 and Genomic Stability

                     Nurdianah Harif Fadzilah * and Wan Adnan Wan Omar
                                                                2
                                         1,
          1  Advanced Medical and Dental Institute, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Bertam, 13200 Kepala Batas, Penang,
                                        Malaysia
         2  Sri Nusa Traditional Rehabilitation Centre, No 6, Lorong Panglima 4, Bertam Perdana, 13200 Kepala Batas,
                                      Penang, Malaysia
                            *Corresponding Author: nurdianaharif@usm.my

               Bee pollen is considered a complete food, packed with essential nutrients and therapeutic
        properties  that  offer protective effects  against epigenetic  alterations, which in  turn help prevent
        genomic instability. Stingless bee pollens play a crucial role in enhancing DNA methylation patterns,
        specifically in Alu and LINE-1 repetitive elements. These repetitive elements are key indicators of
        genomic  stability,  and  their  proper  methylation  is  essential  for  maintaining  cellular  health  and
        preventing  various  diseases,  including  cancer.  This  study  investigated  the  protective  effects  of
        stingless bee pollen against global DNA hypomethylation. Bee pollen extract (BPE) was prepared
        from Geniotrigona thoracica stingless bee species native to Malaysia. Spectrophotometric testing
        was used for chemical and antioxidant activity, HPLC and GC-MS analysis for phenolic compound
        identification, trypan blue exclusion assay for antiproliferative effects, and PCR-Pyrosequencing for
        global methylation quantification. In antioxidant activity, G. thoracica BPE exhibited an EC50 of 0.98
        ± 0.18 mg/mL. HPLC and GC-MS analysis revealed distinct chemical profiles of phenolic compounds
        in G. thoracica BPE. In the antiproliferation assay, G. thoracica BPE showed a therapeutic index of
        3.12 and an EC50 of 0.5 mg/mL. In global DNA methylation analysis, G. thoracica BPE significantly
        increased Alu methylation at 24 hours (26.00% ± 0.58 vs. 21.50% ± 0.96, p = 0.007) and 48 hours
        (31.75% ± 1.89 vs. 20.25% ± 0.95, p = 0.004). LINE-1 methylation levels were also significantly
        elevated at 24 hours (79.92% ± 1.26 vs. 72.83% ± 2.21, p = 0.050) and at 72 hours (95.25% ± 2.46
        vs. 74.83% ± 0.44, p = 0.001) compared to untreated cells. The increased DNA methylation observed
        in Alu and LINE-1 elements suggests that stingless BPE could influence epigenetic regulation. The
        therapeutic properties of Malaysian stingless bee pollen extend beyond its antioxidant capabilities,
        promoting genomic stability through enhanced DNA methylation..]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[OT-3                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



          The role of ROS generation in the anticancer activity of novel Schiff base
                        compound in triple-negative breast cancer


             Reyhaneh Farghadani*, Han Yin Lim, Mahmood Ameen Abdulla, Jayakumar
                                     Rajarajeswaran

         Jeffrey Cheah School of Medicine and Health Sciences, Monash University Malaysia, Jalan Lagoon Selatan,
                          Bandar Sunway, Selangor Darul Ehsan 47500, Malaysia
                        *Corresponding Author: reyhaneh.farghadani@monash.edu

               Triple-negative  breast  cancer  (TNBC)  is  an  aggressive  subtype  of  breast  cancer
        characterized by high recurrence rates and poor prognosis, often leading to distant metastases in
        the brain, lung, bone, and liver. Current chemotherapeutic regimens for TNBC are limited by drug
        resistance and adverse side effects, underscoring the urgent need for novel and more effective
        treatments. Reactive oxygen species (ROS) play a dual role in cancer, acting as a double-edged
        sword. While modest ROS levels promote tumour progression, excessive ROS levels can suppress
        tumours. Cancer cells with elevated ROS are highly dependent on antioxidant defences, and further
        increases in ROS levels beyond a tolerable threshold can induce cell death. Therefore, strategies that
        elevate ROS levels are being explored to preferentially induce cell death in cancer cells, contributing
        to the efficacy of many anticancer agents. Schiff bases, biologically active molecules with enhanced
        pharmacological activities, have shown significant promise in drug discovery. Recent efforts have
        focused on developing Schiff base derivatives with potent anticancer properties and reduced toxicity.
        In this study, we investigated the anticancer potential of a novel β-diiminato Schiff base compound
        in TNBC, focusing on its ability to induce ROS generation. Our findings demonstrate that the Schiff
        base derivative significantly elevates intracellular ROS levels in TNBC cells in a dose-dependent
        manner, as measured by DCFDA assay. This increase in ROS disrupts mitochondrial membrane
        integrity, activating the intrinsic apoptotic pathway. In vivo studies also confirmed the safety profile
        of the compound. These results suggest that ROS generation is a critical mechanism underlying the
        anticancer  activity  of  Schiff  base  derivatives,  offering  a  promising  avenue  for  developing  new
        therapeutic strategies against TNBC.]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[OT-4                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




            Application of In-Silico Approach in Determining the Suitability of Rho
          GTPase and Rho GTPase Activating Protein (RhoGAP) as Drug Targets of
                                    Giardia lamblia

                          Nurhana Jasni and Nurulhasanah Othman*
           Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang, Malaysia

                            *Corresponding Author: nurulhasanah@usm.my

               Giardia lamblia is a globally distributed protozoan parasite that causes an intestinal disease
        named  Giardiasis.  The  primary  treatment  relies  on  nitroimidazole  drugs  such  as  metronidazole
        (MTZ), tinidazole, and albendazole. However, the incidence of refractory cases had increased which
        led to therapeutic non-compliance. Although numerous research studies have been conducted to
        address these concerns, they remain unresolved. Rho family GTPase and its positive regulator, Rho
        GTPase activating protein (RhoGAP) were found to be involved in various biological and cellular
        processes. They were found to be involved in regulating encystation, membrane trafficking, and the
        metabolic processes of the protozoan parasite. Thus, it is hypothesized that inhibiting these proteins
        would lead to the killing of the parasite. Target sequence-based search using DrugBank, molecular
        docking, and molecular dynamic simulation are the current methods that are employed in drug target
        discovery. Thus, these methods were applied to evaluate both proteins as drug targets. Through the
        target  sequence  analysis,  two  repurposed  drugs  were  matched  with  Rho  GTPase  which  are
        Dextromethorphan  and  Azathioprine.  On  the  other  hand,  three  drugs  were  matched  with  Rho
        GTPase-activating  protein  (RhoGAP)  which  were  Imatinib,  Dasatinib,  and  Ponatinib.  Molecular
        docking analysis using Auto Dock Vina showed the binding energies of the five drugs to their
        respective  proteins  were  -8.5  kJ/mol,  -8.0  kJ/mol,  -7.0  kJ/mol,  -5.3  kJ/mol,  and  -6.8  kJ/mol
        represented by Imatinib, Ponatinib, Dasatinib, Azathioprine, and Dextromethorphan, respectively.
        Molecular  dynamic  simulation  analysis  performed  at  100  ns  using  GROMACS  showed  all  the
        complexes exhibit various compactness, uniqueness, and satisfactory stability. Thus, we concluded
        that among all five drugs, two drugs which were Dasatinib and Imatinib potentially inhibit the Rho
        GTPase-activating  protein  (RhoGAP).  In  contrast,  one  drug  potentially  inhibits  the  Rho  GTPase
        protein.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[OT-5                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




          Gene Expression Analysis of Giardia lamblia Small GTPase, Rho subfamily
                          protein treated with Dasatinib inhibitor

                Haneen Imad Abdulsattar, Nurhana Jasni and Nurulhasanah Othman*

              Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang
                            *Corresponding Author: nurulhasanah@usm.my

               Giardiasis, caused by the protozoan parasite Giardia lamblia, is commonly treated with
        Metronidazole as the primary therapeutic option. However, the emergence of adverse effects and
        resistance  to  Metronidazole  has  inspired  research  into  new  treatments.  This  study  focused  on
        investigating the potential of RhoGTPase family proteins as targets for drug intervention in G. lamblia.
        Based on its involvement in metabolic processes, as indicated by the UniProtKB database, and
        previous findings showing up-regulation of Rho GTPase family protein in the virulent variant of E.
        histolytica, another protozoan parasite, it was hypothesized that by inhibiting RhoGTPase family
        proteins, the G. lamblia metabolic process could be interrupted, leading to the parasite's death.
        Previous analyses utilised target sequence analysis in the DrugBank database, molecular docking,
        molecular dynamic simulations, and minimal inhibitory concentration (MIC) test, demonstrating a
        strong  binding  affinity  between  the  putative  Rho  GTPase-activating  protein  and  Dasatinib.  This
        binding suggested that Dasatinib could be effective in killing this parasite at minimal inhibitory
        concentrations. Therefore, this study was designed to explore the effects of inhibiting the putative
        Rho GTPase-activating protein with Dasatinib on the small GTPase, Rho subfamily protein, through
        gene expression analysis.  G. lamblia trophozoites were cultured and treated with MIC 12.5 µM
        Dasatinib at three different time points, before parasite death, which occurred within 48 hours. The
        RNA  was  extracted  using  the  TRIzol  reagent,  quantified,  purified,  and  reverse-transcribed  into
        complementary DNA (cDNA). Quantitative PCR (qPCR) was performed using specifically designed
        primers targeting the small GTPase, Rho subfamily protein, with Aldolase serving as the reference
        gene. The qPCR parameters were optimized, resulting in high PCR efficiency (reaction efficiency =
        1.18 and R² = 0.97502). Microscopic analysis revealed distinct morphological changes in the treated
        G. lamblia cells, including shrinkage, loss of motility, and compromised cellular integrity, which
        further supported the gene expression findings. Treatment with Dasatinib led to significant alterations
        in small GTPase, Rho subfamily protein gene expression. After 30 hours of treatment, the gene was
        upregulated with a fold change (Fc) of 3.22. However, at 36 hours, downregulation was observed
        with Fc = 5.12, and by 42 hours, the gene expression had further reduced with an Fc = 3.16,]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[OT-5                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        indicating  a  substantial  reduction.  This  study  validated  that  inhibiting  the  putative  RhoGTPase-
        activating protein with Dasatinib resulted in differential regulation of the small GTPase, Rho subfamily
        protein gene expression, which may contribute to the killing of G. lamblia.]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[OT-6                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




         TGFBR2 c.1220G>A Mutation and Thoracic Aortic Aneurysm and Dissection
                             Disease: Bioinformatics Insights

                                                                       2
                   1
         Barizah Pulli , Aiman Afif Roslan , Chew Hui Bein , Muzhirah Aisha Md Haniffa , Keng
                                   1
                                                2
                          Wee Teik  and Mohd Nazif Samat Darawi *
                                                          1,
                                 2
                         1  Faculty of Health Sciences, Universiti Selangor, Malaysia
                         2  Department of Genetics, Hospital Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                     *Corresponding Author: nazifsamat@gmail.com, nazif@unisel.edu.my
               Thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissection (TAAD) is a genetically heterogeneous disorder
        characterized by abnormal dilatation of the thoracic aorta, often leading to a life-threatening condition
        such as aortic dissection or ruptures of the aorta. Many genes contribute to the development of
        TAAD, with the majority encoding proteins involved in the extracellular matrix, smooth muscle cell
        contraction or metabolism, or the transforming growth factor-β signalling pathway. Early identification
        of at-risk individuals through genetic testing is crucial for timely clinical management and potentially
        life-saving interventions. A heterozygous substitution of a nucleotide (c.1220G>A) in the TGFBR2
        gene was detected in the proband, a Chinese male using next-generation sequencing TAAD panel
        (Centrum  Medische Genetica,  Belgium).  Bioinformatics analyses were performed using SWISS-
        MODEL, BIOVIA Discovery Studio Visualizer, Polyphen-2 and SIFT to predict the impact of the variant
        on protein structure and evaluate their effects on protein function. Subsequently, we investigated the
        presence of the variant in other family members for early detection. A set of primers was designed
        and employed to flank and amplify the DNA segment harbouring the variant. The PCR-generated
        amplicons were analysed using Sanger sequencing. The primers successfully amplified the correct
        segment of the TGFBR2 gene with 832 bp in size. Sanger sequencing confirmed the presence of the
        same variant in the proband's son. A double peak in the electropherogram revealed a heterozygous
        genotype. This heterozygous missense substitution variant entails a guanine-to-adenine transition at
        position  1220  in  the  coding  sequence  of  the  TGFBR2  gene,  leading  to  a  serine-to-asparagine
        alteration at amino acid codon 407. The high degree of conservation of the serine residue at this
        position across diverse species suggests a crucial role in the function of the transforming growth
        factor-β receptor 2 protein. This receptor plays a crucial role in signal transduction and regulates
        cellular  processes  such  as  proliferation  and  differentiation.  Bioinformatics  analyses  effectively
        assessed the potential functional consequences of the genetic mutation by predicting their impact
        on  protein  stability  and  function.  Molecular  modelling  studies  further  elucidated  the  structural]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[OT-6                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        consequences of the mutation, highlighting potential disruptions to hydrogen bonding networks
        critical for protein stability and ligand binding. Our findings underscore the importance of genetic
        testing for TAAD, particularly for family members of identified carriers, to facilitate early diagnosis
        and timely intervention to prevent potential complications.]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[OT-7                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract




         Graphene Oxide and Reduced Graphene Oxide as Novel Therapeutic Agents
           for Inhibiting Foam Cell Formation and Atherosclerosis Risk Reduction

         FarizahHanimLat , RafeezulMohamed *, Ahmad NaqibShuid , MohdYusmaidieAziz  and
                                                                         3
                                                        2
                      1
                                      1,
                               Muhammad MahyiddinRamli
                                                      4
        1  Department of Biomedical Science, Advanced Medical and Dental Institute, UniversitiSains Malaysia, Bertam,
                             13200 Kepala Batas, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia
         2  Department of Health Community, Advanced Medical and Dental Institute, UniversitiSains Malaysia, Bertam,
                             13200 Kepala Batas, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia
         3  Department of Toxicology, Advanced Medical and Dental Institute, UniversitiSains Malaysia, Bertam,13200
                               Kepala Batas, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia
            4  Institute of Nano Electronic Engineering, Universiti Malaysia Perlis, 01000 Kangar, Perlis, Malaysia
                              *Corresponding Author: rafeezul@usm.my

               Foam cells, which are macrophages overloaded with cholesterol, play a critical role in the
        development of atherosclerosis, a major cause of heart attacks and strokes. Carbon nanomaterials
        (CNMs), particularly graphene oxide (GO) and reduced graphene oxide (rGO), have emerged as
        promising candidates for cardiovascular therapies. This study investigates the impact of GO and rGO
        derived from oil palm trunks on foam cell formation. GO was synthesized using a modified Hummers'
        method and subsequently reduced thermally to produce rGO. Both materials were characterized
        through Raman spectroscopy, FTIR, XRD, and AFM to assess their structural properties. RAW 264.7
        macrophages were treated with varying concentrations of GO and rGO (0.1 to 50 µg/mL) for 24, 48,
        and 72 hours to determine their effects on cell viability. Foam cell formation was evaluated by Oil
        Red O staining and total cholesterol quantification following treatment with oxidised low-density
        lipoprotein (oxLDL), GO and rGO. Pro-atherogenic cytokines secretion (IFNγ, TNFα, IL-6, IL-1β)
        were measured using ELISA, and gene expression of IL-1β, TNFα, ABCA1, CD36, ACAT1, SRA1,
        and ANXA were analysed via RT-qPCR. Raman spectroscopy indicated higher disorder in GO (ID/IG
        ≈ 1.23) compared to rGO (ID/IG ≈ 0.94). FTIR analysis showed that GO retained more oxygen-
        containing groups, and XRD revealed larger d-spacings for GO, highlighting its structural differences
        from rGO. AFM images confirmed that GO had greater surface roughness. Cell viability assays
        demonstrated that GO was more cytotoxic than rGO, particularly at higher concentrations and longer
        exposure times, leading to the selection of 1.0 µg/mL for further experiments. Both GO and rGO
        reduced  lipid  droplet  accumulation  and  total  cholesterol  in  oxLDL-treated  macrophages,  as
        evidenced by Oil Red O staining and total cholesterol quantification. Additionally, both materials]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[OT-7                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract

        decreased  the  secretion  of  pro-atherogenic  cytokines  (IFNγ,  TNFα,  IL-6,  IL-1β).  GO  notably
        suppressed the expression of IL-1β, TNFα, CD36, ACAT1, and SRA1 genes, while enhancing ABCA1
        expression, which facilitates lipid efflux. rGO exhibited similar effects on gene expression, though it
        showed  increased  expression of IL-1β and SRA1 genes  in oxLDL-treated  macrophages. These
        results suggest that GO and rGO hold potential as therapeutic agents for reducing atherosclerosis
        risk by mitigating inflammation and preventing foam cell formation in macrophages.]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[OT-8                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



           Anti-Pigmentation and Anti-Ageing Effects of Mycosporines Produced by
              Wild-Type and Mutant Strains of Xanthophllomyces dendrorhous

                           Neshalini Sathiabalan and Ai Lan Chew*

           Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Universiti Sains Malaysia, Penang, Malaysia
                       *Corresponding Author: chew@usm.my; ai_lan@hotmail.com

               Xanthophyllomyces  dendrorhous  is  a  well-known  species  for  carotenoid  pigment
        production which has been exploited biotechnologically. Research has also proven that this yeast
        species contains UV-absorbing molecules known as mycosporines that can thrive in high oxidative
        and UV-exposure habitats where it is often associated with its potential as an ideal sunscreen. Hence,
        here we investigated the potential of mycosporines produced by X. dendrorhous wild-type (WD) and
        mutant strains red (R), yellow (Y) and white (WH) on their anti-pigmentation and anti-ageing ability
        using the 96-well plate assay method. Mycosporines extracted from X. dendrorhous strains that were
        cultured in an optimized condition were tested for their melanin regulation ability through tyrosinase
        inhibition assay. The tyrosinase inhibition assay confirmed that mycosporines of R have the highest
        inhibition of 75.46% with the lowest IC50 value of 20.10 μg/ml. The inhibition percentage descended
        with the WD, Y and WH strains (64.97%, 56.17%, 53.08%) respectively portraying a moderate
        tyrosinase inhibition effect. Wrinkles, the obvious indicator of ageing are due to damaged collagen
        and  elastin  in  the  skin  epidermis.  Mycosporines  produced  by  the  X.  dendrorhous  were  also
        hypothesized to have anti-ageing effects which led to the analysis on the collagenase inhibitory assay
        and elastase inhibitory assay. The results showed that the R strains gave the highest collagenase
        inhibition activity of 89.73% which was followed by the WD, Y, and WH strains (85.34%, 81.98%,
        and 80.36%) respectively. Whereas the elastase inhibitory assay exhibited a strong elastase inhibition
        with the highest percentage (84.35%) by the R strain and accompanied by the WD, Y and WH strains
        (78.62%, 60.40%, and 55.95%) respectively. In short, our findings demonstrated that mycosporines
        produced  by  the  X.  dendrorhous  wild-type  and  mutant  strains  have  great  potential  as  natural
        molecular sunscreen with their strong anti-pigmentation and anti-ageing effects.]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[OT-9                                                 Oral Presenter Abstract



          Single-Cell Multiomics Reveals Monocyte-Specific Dysregulation of IL1R2
                             and THBS1 in Colorectal Cancer

                Sabrina George , Nor Haslinda Abdul Aziz and Nor Adzimah Johdi *
                            1
                                                 2
                                                                    1,
                 1  UKM Medical Molecular Biology Institute (UMBI), National University of Malaysia
             2  Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Faculty of Medicine, National University of Malaysia
                          *Corresponding Author: adzimah@ppukm.ukm.edu.my

               Colorectal cancer (CRC) remains a leading cause of cancer-related morbidity and mortality
        worldwide. The circulating immune cells play a pivotal role in CRC progression, with significant
        dysregulation often observed in CRC patients. This study aims to understand CRC's molecular and
        cellular  immune  landscape  that  may  serve  as  potential  biomarkers  or  therapeutic  targets.  We
        employed  a  multi-omics  approach,  combining  single-cell  RNA  sequencing  (scRNA-seq)  with
        antibody-based sequencing (AbSeq), to dissect the immune profile of peripheral blood mononuclear
        cells (PBMCs) at a single-cell resolution. PBMCs were analysed from six CRC patients and six
        healthy controls using a targeted panel of 399 genes and 30 surface proteins, providing an in-depth
        view of these populations' immune heterogeneity and functional states. From this dataset, 12,226
        high-quality  PBMCs  were  obtained  and  six  major  immune  subsets  were  identified:  monocytes
        (5,131, 41.97%), CD4+ T cells (2,481, 20.29%), CD8+ T cells (1,796, 14.69%), natural killer (NK)
        cells (1,705, 13.94%), B cells (769, 6.29%), and dendritic cells (DCs) (193, 1.58%). Further analysis
        using the Seurat algorithm revealed 11 distinct clusters. Differential gene expression analysis reveals
        a significant upregulation of Interleukin 1 receptor, type II (IL1R2) and Thrombospondin 1 (THBS1)
        in monocytes derived from CRC patients compared to healthy controls. IL1R2, an anti-inflammatory
        receptor, and THBS1, an ECM protein implicated in various cancer-related processes, were both
        found to be overexpressed. This upregulation suggests potential alterations in monocyte functionality
        and their role in CRC pathogenesis. Specifically, the elevated IL1R2 levels may contribute to an
        altered inflammatory response, while increased THBS1 expression correlated with a poor prognosis.
        These findings suggest the potential of IL1R2 and THBS1 as prognostic biomarkers and therapeutic
        targets  in  CRC.  Further  investigation  into  the  mechanistic  roles  of  these  molecules  in  CRC  is
        warranted to explore their potential as biomarkers and therapeutic targets.]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[OT-10                                                Oral Presenter Abstract



         Cytotoxic and Mutagenic Effects of Dewatered Sludge Treated with Microbial
                          Fuel Cell (MFC) using In Vitro Systems


          Muhammad Adib Fadhlullah Muhammad Lukman , Nur Azzalia Kamaruzaman *, Ana
                                                                       1,
                                                 1
                      Masara Ahmad Mokhtar  and Amira Suriaty Yaakop
                                         2
                                                               3
                   1  National Poison Centre, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 Minden, Penang.
                2  School of Industrial Technology, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 Minden, Penang.
                 3  School of Biological Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 Minden, Penang.
                              *Corresponding Author: azzalia@usm.my

               Significant increase in the production of activated sludge from wastewater treatment plants
        is causing severe environmental pollution and this has been a top-priority concern for environmental
        protection. Thus, there is an urgent need for sustainable waste treatment methods with innovative
        technological solutions. Microbial Fuel Cells (MFC) is a bio-electrochemical system which has been
        identified as a potential approach for sludge treatment and renewable energy production. However,
        utilization of dewatered sludge in conjunction with MFC technology has gained concerns regarding
        the environmental and health impacts of such practices especially in relation to DNA damage and
        cancer-inducing  factors.  Thus,  this  study  aims  to  evaluate  cytotoxic  and  mutagenic  effects  of
        dewatered sludge treated with MFC technology. MFC samples consisted of Bacillus subtilis (BS),
        Bacillus cereus (BC), Bacillus tropicus (BT), BS+BC, BS+BT and BS+BC+BT, and each sample was
        evaluated  in  six  concentrations  (1mg/ml,  0.5mg/ml,  0.25mg/ml,  0.125mg/ml,  0.0625mg/ml,
        0.0313mg/ml). Cytotoxicity study was conducted using MTT assay, a cellular metabolic test, whereby
        human foreskin fibroblast Hs27 cells were treated with MFC samples. For mutagenicity, a Bacterial
        Reverse Mutation (AMES) test was performed using the MFC samples. Salmonella typhimurium
        strains TA98 and TA100 were utilized to detect frameshift and base-pair mutations respectively.
        Analysis of cell viability (%) from the treatment of MFC found that in comparison to the controls (xT
        and T0), all samples (BS, BC, BT, BS+BC, BS+BT and BS+BC+BT) showed slightly increased cell
        viability. Controls did not contain any bacteria in the samples where xT represents untreated non-
        autoclaved sludge and T0 represents untreated autoclaved sludge. Furthermore, mutagenicity test
        using Salmonella typhimurium bacteria found that the number of colonies grown for MFC samples
        for both strains were elevated for BT sample when compared to the negative control. Moreover,
        combination of bacteria BS+BC, BS+BT and BS+BC+BT showed more elevated number of colonies
        in  comparison  to control,  which are higher  than the single bacteria treatment.  Additionally,  the]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[OT-10                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        number of colonies for BS and BC samples was lower than the negative control. Based on cytotoxicity
        and mutagenicity tests performed on the MFC samples, it could be deduced that the MFC samples
        did not induce cytotoxicity as cell viability was increased, and mutagenic effect could be observed
        for certain samples especially for MFC samples treated with combination of bacteria. Thus, MFC
        technology when applied to dewatered sludge show some safety potential in terms of cell viability
        but should be used with single bacteria treatment to minimize mutagenic effect.]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[OT-11                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




           Determining the Quantity and Quality of DNA from the FFPE Tissues NGS
                        Library Preparation: A Sharing Experience

                                                                   2,4
          Siti Noresah Mohd Zaim , Siti Norasikin Mohd Nafi * Norzaliana Zawawi  and Wan
                                                  1,
                             1
                                  Fadhlina Wan Adnan
                                                  3,4
         1  Department of Pathology, School of Medical Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 16150,
                                   Kubang Kerian, Kelantan
          2  School of Dental Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 16150, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan
          3  Department of Obstetrics & Gynecology, School of Medical Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains
                              Malaysia, 16150 Kubang Kerian, Kelantan
                     4  Hospital Universiti Sains Malaysia, 16150, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan
                              *Corresponding Author: snmn@usm.my

               Targeted Next-Generation Sequencing (NGS) is an approach that gains attention among
        clinicians and researchers to explore the specific mutation profiles of cancer.  In pathology, formalin-
        fixed tissue (FFPE) tissues are suitable for long-term storage and preserving histological aspects,
        giving  them  key  importance  in  retrospective  research  and  molecular  diagnostics.  However,  the
        procedure of formalin fixation and paraffin embedding leads to cross-linking and degradation of DNA,
        creating  challenges  for  molecular  research.  Here,  we  share  our  experience  in  determining  the
        quantity and quality of DNA from the FFPE tissues. as an initial step for NGS library preparation. This
        study aimed to evaluate the quality and quantity of DNA samples extracted from the FFPE endometrial
        cancer tissues and assess their suitability for NGS library preparation. A total of 28 FFPE tissue
        samples from endometrial cancer patients were collected from the pathology laboratory of Hospital
        Universiti Sains Malaysia (HUSM). The key tasks of this research include (1) extracting DNA from
        FFPE tissues, from which DNA was extracted using the QIAamp DNA FFPE Advanced UNG kit
        (QIAGEN, Germany)  (2) quantifying and assessing the quality of the DNA, the quantification was
        measured through fluorometric assays, and the quality was assessed using spectrophotometry by
        measuring purity ratios (A260/A280) and the integrity of the DNA using agarose gel electrophoresis,
        and (3) preparing NGS libraries and evaluating their quality for sequencing, NGS library preparation
        was  performed  using  a  targeted  gene  panel,  and  the  libraries  were  analysed  for  quality  using
        Bioanalyzer, followed by sequencing on an Illumina platform. Library quality was evaluated based on
        yield, fragment size distribution, and sequencing metrics. DNA extracted from the FFPE tissues
        showed average yields ranging from 20 to 100 ng/µL per sample. The purity ratios (A260/280) were
        within acceptable limits, ranging between 1.8 and 2.0, indicating minimal protein contamination.]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[OT-11                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        Despite some fragmentation, most extracted DNA samples were suitable for targeted NGS library
        preparation. Bioanalyzer results will demonstrate library fragment sizes for sequencing. This study
        highlights that, although DNA extracted from FFPE tissues can be degraded, it is still suitable for
        NGS library preparation with proper extraction techniques and quality control measures. Ensuring
        high DNA quality and quantity from FFPE samples is critical for generating reliable sequencing data
        and improving molecular diagnostics for cancer. These findings emphasize the importance of precise
        quality control in the NGS workflow, particularly when working with archived tissue samples.]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[OT-12                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




         Development of Carboxymethylcellulose Hydrogel from Oil Palm Empty Fruit
                          Bunch for Efficient Curcumin Delivery

          Nurfarrahhin Rosle , Nurrulhidayah Salamun , Khairunadwa Jemon , and Wan Fatin
                                                               3
                                             2
                         1
                                                    1,3,
                                Amira Wan Mohd Zawawi *
           1  Department of Biosciences, Faculty of Science, Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, 81310, Johor, Malaysia
          2  Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, 81310, UTM Johor Bahru,
                                      Johor, Malaysia
           3  Cancer and Infectious Diseases Group, Health and Wellness Research Alliance, Universiti Teknologi
                                 Malaysia, 81310, Johor, Malaysia

                            *Corresponding Author: wanfatinamira@utm.my

               Malaysia stands as one of the leading global producer of oil palm, generating an enormous
        quantity of biomass waste, particularly oil palm empty fruit bunches (OPEFB). Due to the challenges
        associated with OPEFB disposal, there is growing interest in repurposing this biomass by extracting
        its high-purity cellulose to produce valuable biomaterials such as natural hydrogels. On the other
        hand,  curcumin,  a  bioactive  compound  with   demonstrated  therapeutic  efficacy  in  biomedical
        applications like wound healing and drug delivery, presents a challenge due to its hydrophobic
        nature, thus restricting its clinical application. To overcome this, using a hydrogel as a hydrophilic
        carrier  is  an  effective  approach  to  facilitate  curcumin  delivery.  Therefore,  this  study  aims  to
        incorporate curcumin into carboxymethylcellulose hydrogel (CMC) to enhance its delivery efficiency.
        In this study, CMC hydrogel was synthesized from OPEFB through carboxymethylation process using
        sodium monochloroacetate (SMCA) and it was crosslinked at room temperature by using CaCl2 as
        a cross-linking agent to evaluate its effectiveness as a hydrophilic system for curcumin delivery. All
        samples were characterized using FT-IR, XRD, EDX and FESEM to analyse chemical changes and
        modifications. FT-IR analysis confirmed the successful conversion of cellulose to CMC, with spectra
        showing only cellulose-related peaks. The XRD analysis demonstrated a significant transition from
        the crystalline cellulose structure of cellulose to an amorphous phase, as evidenced by the absence
        of OPEFB cellulose peaks in the CMC hydrogel. Furthermore, the elemental composition of the
        samples was verified through EDX analysis, while FESEM revealed significant morphological changes
        during both the extraction and cross-linking processes. To incorporate curcumin into the CMC
        hydrogel, physical adsorption methods was employed. The optimal concentrations of both CMC and
        curcumin  were  determined  through  swelling  and  release  studies,  which  assessed  the  hydrogel]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[OT-12                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        capacity to load and release curcumin effectively. The results suggest that the 20% CMC hydrogel
        exhibit substantial potential to serve as an efficient hydrophilic system for curcumin delivery. The
        loading  capacity  analysis  indicated  that  0.2  mg/ml  was  the  optimal  concentration  of  curcumin.
        Moreover, release kinetics studies further confirmed that 0.2 mg/ml curcumin concentration achieved
        the most sustained release compared to other tested concentrations. Hence, this study offers a
        sustainable approach to biomass utilization while providing a promising framework for enhancing
        curcumin's therapeutic potential in biomedical applications.]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[OT-13                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




         CRISPR-Mediated Knockdown of OTUB1 and OTUB2 in HepG2 Cells Reveals
                     Roles in Inflammatory Pathways and Cell Viability

                       Sa’udah Badriah Mohd Sani and Nurulisa Zulkifle*

        Department of Biomedical Sciences, Advanced Medical and Dental Institute, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Bertam,
                               13200 Kepala Batas, Penang, Malaysia
                              *Corresponding Author: nurulisa@usm.my

               Hepatocellular  carcinoma  (HCC)  is  a  leading  cause  of  cancer  mortality  worldwide,
        necessitating the exploration of novel therapeutic targets. The deubiquitinating enzymes OTUB1 and
        OTUB2  are  upregulated  in  HCC  and  are  implicated  in  tumour  progression.  This  study  aims  to
        investigate  the  effects  of  OTUB1  and  OTUB2  knockdown  on  cell  viability  and  gene  expression
        pathways in HepG2 cells to assess their potential as therapeutic targets. Guide RNA sequences
        targeting OTUB1 and OTUB2 were designed and cloned into the pSpgRNA plasmid. These constructs
        were  transfected  into  HepG2 KRAB   cells  using  Lipofectamine.  RT-PCR  was  used  to  confirm  the
        downregulation of OTUB1 and OTUB2 expression levels. An MTS assay assessed the impact of
        knockdown  on cell viability.  RNA-seq was performed, and functional enrichment  analyses were
        conducted to identify affected pathways. As a result, RT-PCR confirmed a significant reduction in
        OTUB1 and OTUB2 mRNA levels post-CRISPR knockdown, with both gene expression reduced by
        2-fold (p<0.0001 and p<0.05, respectively). The MTS assay demonstrated that HepG2 KRAB/OTUB1  have
        significant cell growth inhibition at 24 hours (p<0.0001), HepG2 KRAB/OTUB2  also showing reduced cell
        viability, though to a lesser extent. RNA-seq analysis revealed significant pathway alterations. In
        HepG2 KRAB/OTUB1 ,  KEGG  enrichment  showed  upregulation  of  the  IL-17  signalling  pathway,  NF-kB
        signalling  pathway,  TNF  signalling  pathway,  and  cytokine-cytokine  receptor  interaction.  OTUB2
        knockdown similarly affected cytokine-cytokine receptor interaction and inflammatory pathways. GO
        analysis for HepG2 KRAB/OTUB1  indicated processes such as regulation of vasculature development and
        cytokine-mediated signalling, while HepG2 KRAB/OTUB2  was associated with cell migration and motility.
        The knockdown of OTUB1 and OTUB2 significantly influences pathways involved in inflammation
        and immune responses, which are crucial contributors to tumour progression and metastasis. The
        enrichment of inflammatory pathways such as IL-17 and TNF signalling underscores the role of
        OTUB1 and OTUB2 in maintaining a pro-tumour microenvironment through chronic inflammation.
        These pathways are known to enhance angiogenesis, facilitate immune evasion, and promote tumour
        cell survival, indicating that OTUB1 and OTUB2 contribute to the aggressive phenotype of HCC.]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[OT-13                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        Additionally, the GO terms related to vasculature development and cell migration suggest that OTUB1
        and OTUB2 may influence tumour angiogenesis and metastasis. By targeting these enzymes, it may
        be possible  to  disrupt the tumour-promoting  inflammatory  signalling, thereby  inhibiting  tumour
        growth and metastasis. This study demonstrates that CRISPR-mediated knockdown of OTUB1 and
        OTUB2  reduces  cell  viability  and  modulates  key  inflammatory  pathways  in  HepG2  cells.  These
        findings underscore the potential of OTUB1 and OTUB2 as therapeutic targets for disrupting the
        tumour-promoting inflammatory environment in HCC.]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[OT-14                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




           Efficacy of Stingless Bee Honey (oral and topical) in Enhancing Wound
            Healing in STZ - induced Diabetic Rat Model: An Experimental Study

          Suriati Mohd Nasir , Anis Ismail , Tuan Salwani Tuan Ismail *, Wan Amir Nizam Wan
                        1
                                                         2,
                                   1
               3
         Ahmad , Tengku Ahmad Damitri Al- Astani Tengku Din , Kuttulebbai Nainamohammed
                                                    1
                                                                 5
                                   4
                     Salam Sirajudeen  and Wan Faiziah Wan Abdul Rahman
             1  School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kota Bharu 16150, Kelantan, Malaysia
         2  Endocrinology Laboratory, Department of Chemical Pathology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains
                            Malaysia, Kota Bharu 16150, Kelantan, Malaysia
          3  Biomedicine Program, School of Health Sciences, Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kota Bharu
                                   16150, Kelantan, Malaysia
          4  Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Kuliyyah of Medicine, International Islamic University Malaysia,
                         Bandar Indera Mahkota, Kuantan 25200, Pahang, Malaysia
           5  Department of Pathology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kota Bharu 16150,
                                     Kelantan, Malaysia
                              *Corresponding Author:  tusti@usm.my

               Diabetes  mellitus  impairs  the  healing  process  of  wound  due  to  uncontrolled
        hyperglycaemia which eventually damages the blood vessels, leading to poor circulation and reduces
        the supply of oxygen and nutrients, essential for wound healing. Stingless bee honey (SBH) has
        gained  attention  among  researchers due to it's antimicrobial,  anti-inflammatory, and  antioxidant
        properties, which improve the wound healing process. Additionally, it has been found to lower fasting
        blood glucose levels (FBG). Typically, honey is applied topically for wound treatment, while the
        effectiveness of consuming SBH orally for wound healing is not well established. Therefore, this
        study aims to explore the therapeutic potential of SBH in promoting wound healing in diabetic wound
        rats model through topical, oral and combine applications. A total of 84 Sprague-Dawley rats (200-
        250 g) were equally divided into seven groups; where the first group was non diabetic (ND) rats and
        the other six groups were induced to be diabetes. The ND and diabetic untreated (DU) groups
        received normal saline while other diabetic groups treated with SBH (2 g/kg body weight), Metformin
        (MET/250 mg/kg body weight), oral SBH, oral MET, oral SBH + oral MET, topical SBH, topical SBH
        + oral MET; respectively. The treatment was administered daily for 12 days. Fasting blood glucose
        (FBG) level was measured at day 0, day 7 and day 12 of treatment. At day-7 and day-12, combination
        of oral SBH and oral MET showed the best result in reducing the FBG level followed by MET, oral
        SBH, topical SBH and combine topical SBH and oral MET. It shows that combination between oral]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[OT-14                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        SBH and oral MET give synergistic effect in hyperglycemic treatment. This study also demonstrated
        that the combination of topical SBH and oral MET resulted in highest wound contraction percentage
        among the treatment groups. This finding suggests that the combination of oral SBH and MET
        synergistically reduces FBG, but topical SBH, in combination with oral MET, gives the best outcome
        in promoting diabetic wound healing. Combination of SBH and MET could be a promising alternative
        therapy for glycemic control and wound healing. Therapeutic properties of SBH need to be further
        validated at the cellular level in future study.]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[OT-15                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




          Cytotoxic Effects of K. alvarezii Crude Extract on Human Leukemia
                                    Cell Line K562


          Nur Fatin Najihah Mat Husin , Anisa Natasha Jefri , Khairunadwa Jemon , Nurzila Ab
                                                 1
                                                                   1
                                1
                                                                    2
                               2
            1
         Latif , Nor Rizan Kamaluddin , Shaik Ahmad Kamal Shaik Mohd Fakiruddin , Nurriza Ab
                                         Latif *
                                            1,
           1  Department of Biosciences, Faculty of Science, Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, 81310, Skudai, Johor
         2  Cancer Research Centre (CaRC), Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National Institutes of Health (NIH),
          Block C, No.1, Jalan Setia Murni U13/52 Seksyen U13 Setia Alam, 40170 Shah Alam, Selangor, Malaysia.
                              *Corresponding Author: nurriza@utm.my
               Kappaphycus alvarezii is a red seaweed that grows abundantly in East Malaysia and is rich
        in bioactive constituents. The crude extract of K. alvarezii has been reported to exhibit promising
        pharmacological effects such as anticancer, antiinflammatory, antiviral, antioxidant, antidiabetic, and
        cholesterol-lowering agents, as well as hemagglutination activities. Therefore, this study aimed to
        quantify the total phenolic and flavonoid contents, and cytotoxic properties of the K. alvarezii crude
        extract isolated from Sabah coastal area.  Bioactive  compounds from the seaweed  powder were
        extracted using methanol and ethanol with different concentrations (50%, 70%, and 100%). 70%
        methanolic extract recorded the highest total phenolic content, which is 11.88 ± 0.56 mg GAE/g. The
        total flavonoid concentration of all the extracts, both methanolic and ethanolic, was found to be very
        low. The presence of potential bioactive compounds was profiled using liquid chromatography mass
        spectrometry  quadrupole  time-of-flight  (LC/MS-QTOF).  Phytochemical  screening  of  the  extract
        revealed  a  total  of  225  compounds  were  identified  including  phenolics,  flavonoids,  coumarins,
        terpenes, quassinoids, thiophene, and others. The in vitro anticancer activity of 70% methanolic
        crude extract was further investigated against  human leukemia cells, K562,  and normal human
        fibroblast cells, HSF 1184. The cytotoxic effect of the extract was assessed using the [3-(4, 5-
        dimethylthiazol-2-yl)-2,5-diphenyl-tetrazolium  bromide]  (MTT)  assay.  The  result  showed  to
        significantly inhibit K562 cell viability in a concentration- and time-dependent manner, with minimal
        cytotoxic effects observed on treated-HSF 1184 cell line. Flow cytometry analysis indicates the crude
        extract has been shown to promote apoptosis among the K562 cell population. Collectively, results
        from this study suggest the presence of active compounds could contribute to the anticancer effect
        of K. alvarezii crude extract.]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[OT-16                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




          Andrographolide induced Apoptosis and Cell Cycle Arrest in MDA-MB-231
                             and MCF-7 Breast Cancer Cells

                  Deeza Syafiqah Mohd Sidek and Daruliza Kernain Mohd Azman*

          Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Universiti Sains Malaysia,11800 USM, Penang.
                              *Corresponding Author: daruliza@usm.my

               Breast cancer continues to pose a major health threat among women globally with high
        mortality rates. Andrographolide is a major diterpenoid lactone that can be found in Andrographis
        Paniculata, a medicinal herb that is popular in Southeast Asia. Andrographolide previously has been
        potentially identified to have anti-cancer properties. This study is aimed to evaluate the effects of
        andrographolide on breast cancer cells by using two different breast cancer cell lines, MDA-MB-
        231, a triple negative cell line, and MCF-7, an ER-positive cell line. MDA MB 231, MCF 7, and MCF
        10A were treated with andrographolide at a different concentration ranging 0.781 µM to 200 µM for
        24, 48 and 72 hours. The cell viability was observed using the WST-1 reagent. The LC50 value
        calculated were used in the subsequent experiments. Both cells were seeded accordingly for each
        experiment and treated with LC50 and ½ LC50 concentration of andrographolide for 48 hours. Flow
        cytometry was used to determine the apoptosis and cell cycle distribution. The cells were stained
        using  annexin  V/propidium  iodide  for  apoptosis  and  propidium  iodide  (PI)  for  cell  cycle.
        Andrographolide was found to reduce cell viability for both MDA-MB-231 and MCF-7 cell lines in a
        concentration-time-dependent  manner.  The  LC50  values  of  both  cells  after  being  treated  with
        andrographolide are 23.06 µM for MDA-MB-231 and 12.21 µM for MCF-7 cells. LC50 value for the
        non-cancerous MCF-10A cell line could not be determined, as cell viability remained around ~80%
        even at the highest concentration of 200 µM after 24 hours. Andrographolide induced apoptosis in
        both cancer cell lines. The percentage of apoptotic cells in untreated controls were 3.91% for MDA
        MB 231 and 2.77% for MCF-7. After 48 hours of treatment with LC50 and ½ LC50 concentration of
        andrographolide, the percentage of apoptotic cells for MDA MB 231 cells increase by 7.93% and
        5.21%, respectively. A similar pattern can be observed for MCF 7 which also showed an increasing
        number of apoptotic cells, 6.58% and 4.22%, respectively. Andrographolide treatment of LC50 and ½
        LC50 concentration were observed to lead to cell cycle arrest in the G2/M phase in both cells which
        demonstrates its cytotoxic effects on these cancer cells. This study showed that andrographolide
        effectively reduced cell viability and induced apoptosis in MCF-7 and MDA-MB-231 breast cancer]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[OT-16                                                Oral Presenter Abstract

        cells. It also caused cell cycle arrest in the G2/M phase in these cancer cells which suggests that
        andrographolide may have selective effects on cancer cells.]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[OT-17                                                Oral Presenter Abstract




              The Protective Effect of THICAPA on Familial Alzheimer's Disease
                   Pathogenesis Using Skin-derived Fibroblast Cell Lines

           Danesh Thangeswaran , Shaharum Shamsuddin  and Venugopal Balakrishnan *
                             1
                                                  2
                                                                         1,
        1  Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 Minden, Penang
                2  School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian 16150, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: venugopal@usm.my

               Familial Alzheimer's disease (fAD) is hereditary and developed at an unusually early age.
        The accumulation of toxic amyloid-beta (Aβ) protein in the brain induces inflammation that leads to
        neurodegeneration, a hallmark of AD. The prevalence of fAD symptoms is alarming, and there are
        no drugs available to cure this neurological disorder. The search for novel fAD treatments has shifted
        towards formulations with the potential to mitigate toxic protein aggregations by modulating the
        amyloid  precursor  protein  (APP)  pathway.  THICAPA  is  a  novel  compound  belonging  to  the
        tetrahydroisoquinoline group of amines. These amines are naturally found in the brain and foods
        with broad medicinal properties, including anti-inflammatory properties and affine ligands for central
        nervous system receptors. Therefore, this study investigated the modulatory effect of THICAPA on
        the APP processing pathway using the fAD patient skin-derived fibroblast cell line. In this study, we
        have shown that 50 μM THICAPA has exerted a potent scavenging effect on aged Aβ42 oligomers
        in the healthy skin-derived fibroblast cell line. Following that, the impact of THICAPA on the gene
        and protein expressions linked to both amyloidogenic processing of the APP pathway was assessed
        through the qRT-PCR and Western blot techniques. THICAPA reduced the gene expression of APP,
        BACE1 and PSEN1 in the amyloidogenic pathway, indicating the downregulation of the β- and γ-
        secretase activities, respectively. Furthermore, the ELISA quantification of Aβ proteins displayed a
        significant  reduction  of  Aβ40,  and  Aβ42  isoforms  produced  from  the  amyloidogenic  pathway
        resulting from downregulated amyloidogenesis. Hereby, our study identifies THICAPA as a potential
        anti-AD candidate with significant therapeutic activity against toxic Aβ productions.]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[P-1                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract



          Comparative Genomic Analysis of a Mycobacterium tuberculosis STB-T6A
                Strain Isolated from Spinal Epidural Mass in Sabah, Malaysia

          Kai Ling Chin *, Eraniyah Jastan Suing , Ruhini Andong , Choong Hoon Foo , Sook
                                                       1
                                         1
                                                                       3
                    1,2,
                     3
                                 1,2
                                                  1,2
                                                                         1
            Kwan Chan , Jaeyres Jani , Kamruddin Ahmed  and Zainal Arifin Mustapha
           1  Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, Kota Kinabalu, Sabah, Malaysia
         2  Borneo Medical and Health Research Centre, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia
                               Sabah, Kota Kinabalu, Sabah, Malaysia
               3  Department of Orthopaedics, Queen Elizabeth Hospital, Kota Kinabalu, Sabah, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: chinkl@ums.edu.my
               Spinal tuberculosis, also known as Pott’s spine, is an extrapulmonary form of tuberculosis
        caused  by  Mycobacterium  tuberculosis  (Mtb).  This  condition  can  result  in  bone  destruction,
        deformity, and paraplegia. The high burden of tuberculosis among undocumented immigrants in
        Sabah suggests the potential spread of Mtb strains from other countries into Sabah. This study aims
        to determine the origin of a Mtb strain from a patient diagnosed with spinal tuberculosis in Sabah. A
        45-year-old male presented with clinical symptoms including chronic back pain, spinal tenderness,
        neurological deficits, paradiscal lesions, loss of anterior vertebra, and narrowing of the disc space,
        during his visit to Queen Elizabeth Hospital in Kota Kinabalu, Sabah. A biopsy was conducted to
        collect the epidural mass in the spine. The specimen was tested positive for tuberculosis using
        Xpert®  MTB/RIF  Ultra.  To  isolate  the  bacteria,  the  specimen  was  cultured  in  BACTEC™
        Mycobacterium Growth Indicator Tube system. DNA was extracted and subjected to whole genome
        sequencing  with  the  Illumina  NovaSeq™  6000  sequencing  system.  The  sequencing  data  of
        Mycobacterium  tuberculosis  STB-T6A  strain  has  been  submitted  to  the  National  Center  for
        Biotechnology Information (NCBI) and can be accessed under the following accession numbers, i.e.,
        BioProject: PRJNA1091826, BioSample: SAMN40864168, Sequence Read Archive: SRR28580507,
        and GenBank: JBBWUO000000000. The sequencing output was used for k-mer size estimation with
        KmerGenie version 1.7051, followed by de novo assembly using SPAdes version 3.15.4. Variant
        calling was performed with the Genome Analysis Toolkit (GATK), and the variants were annotated
        with  SnpEff  version  5.0.  Comparative  genomic  analysis  was  then  conducted  through  single
        nucleotide  polymorphism  (SNP)-based  phylogenetic  analysis,  utilizing  KSNP3  and  MEGA  11
        software. Additionally, drug resistance analysis was performed using Mykrobe Predictor. The de
        novo assembly generated 208 contigs with an N50 of 162,410 base pairs. The whole genome size
        of the Mtb STB-T6A strain is 4,395,691 base pairs with a GC content of 65.58%, comprising 4,233]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[P-1                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract

        protein-coding sequences, 45 tRNAs, 3 rRNAs (5S, 16S, and 23S rRNAs), and 3 ncRNAs. The variant
        calling analysis showed that 99.21% of the generated reads were successfully mapped to the M.
        tuberculosis H37Rv reference genome. The comparative genomic analysis showed that the Mtb STB-
        T6A strain belongs to the Indo-Oceanic lineage (Lineage 1) and is closely associated with the Mtb
        T46 strain from the Philippines. Moreover, the drug susceptibility analysis predicted the strain to be
        drug-susceptible. In summary, these findings offer significant insights into the genetic diversity and
        evolutionary connections of the Mtb STB-T6A strain.]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[P-2                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract




         Biomarkers in Endothelial Dysfunction-Associated Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus

            Nur Fatin Zalikha Zailan, Nazanin Talebabadi, Eusni Rahayu Mohd. Tohit, Hasni
                              Mahayidin and Masriana Hassan*

        Department of Pathology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 43400 Serdang,
                                     Selangor, Malaysia
                            *Corresponding author: masriana@upm.edu.my

               Diabetes mellitus (DM) is a chronic metabolic disorder by which the severe complications
        of the disease could lead to an increased risk of cardiovascular disease (CVD) mediated by vascular
        endothelial dysfunction. Chronic inflammation and oxidative stress, characterized by the imbalance
        of  reactive  oxygen  species  (ROS)  production,  are  among  the  factors  that  influence  endothelial
        damage. Evaluating biomarkers in an in vitro model representative of endothelial dysfunction could
        aid in the pathophysiological studies, clinical evaluation, and therapeutic potential for CVD-related
        diseases. Serum and plasma of both males and females from normal (healthy) individuals (n=41) as
        control  population  and Type  2  DM  (T2DM)  patients  (n=41)  were  collected  from the  Faculty  of
        Medicine and Health Sciences, UPM, and the Family Medicine Clinic, Hospital Sultan Abdul Aziz
        Shah, respectively. The production of nitric oxide (NO) (by Griess assay) and cytokines (by flow
        cytometry-based LEGENDplex immunoassays) was determined in plasma from both normal and
        T2DM  samples. The production of  ROS  (by dichlorodihydrofluorescein diacetate [DCFDA])  and
        endothelial damage were evaluated by serum induction in human umbilical vein endothelial cells
        (HUVEC). In the trans-endothelial permeability assay, the cells were cultured in a 0.4µm transwell
        insert and the endothelial injury was evaluated through fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC)-Dextran
        analysis. The level of plasma NO was comparatively lower but not significant in T2DM patients than
        in the control group. Similarly, non-significant lower plasma TNF-α, IL1-β, and IL-6 in T2DM patients
        than  the  normal  group  were  observed.  Conversely,  serum-induced  ROS  production  in  T2DM
        (2213.67 ± 393.17 RFU) was significantly higher (p = 0.0176) than the control group (1303.00 ±
        129.27 RFU). A significantly higher (p = 0.0035) trans-endothelial permeability was also detected in
        HUVEC stimulated with T2DM serum (1227.67 ± 122.99 RFU) than with the control serum (568.67
        ± 31.32 RFU). In addition, exogenous IL-1β and/or H2O2 promote a significant increase in ROS
        production and/or trans-endothelial permeability. The study shows that the reduction of NO and an
        increase in ROS production in T2DM could potentially contribute to the damage of the endothelial
        cells, thus suggesting the pivotal role of oxidative stress in endothelial dysfunction in DM. This in]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[P-2                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract

        vitro model will contribute to the assessment of potential biomarkers for early clinical evaluation and
        physiological studies of endothelial cell dysfunction in DM.]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[P-3                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract




         Alterations of Tissue Inhibitor of Metalloproteinase Levels Among Smokers
                              with Coronary Artery Disease

                                           2
                      1
                                                                           3
          Nazirah Samah , Shawal Faizal Mohamad , Beh Boon Cong , Nik Azuan Nik Ismail ,
                                                         2
                          4
           Faridah Mohd Nor , Wan Mohd Hafiz Wan Razali , Faizal Amri Hamzah , Adila A.
                                                                   6
                                                 4,5
                                          1,
                                                              1,
                            1
                       Hamid , Azizah Ugusman * and Amilia Aminuddin *
         1  Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latif, Bandar
                           Tun Razak, 56000 Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
         2  Department of Cardiology, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latif, Bandar Tun Razak, 56000
                                 Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
          3  Department of Radiology, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latif, Bandar Tun Razak, 56000
                                 Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
          4  Forensic Unit, Department of Pathology, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latif, Bandar Tun
                            Razak, 56000 Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
         5  Department of Forensic Pathology, Faculty of Medicine, Sungai Buloh Campus, Universiti Teknologi MARA,
                              47000 Sungai Buloh, Selangor, Malaysia
         6  Department of Emergency Medicine, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Jalan Yaacob Latif, Bandar Tun Razak,
                               56000 Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                  *Correspondence: amilia@ppukm.ukm.edu.my, dr.azizah@ppukm.ukm.edu.my
               Coronary artery disease (CAD) is characterized by narrowing or blockage of coronary
        arteries due to atherosclerotic plaque. CAD remains the leading cause of morbidity and mortality
        worldwide.  Smoking is recognized as a significant risk factor for the development of CAD. Among
        these mechanisms, emerging evidence suggests the involvement of various molecular players such
        as  tissue  inhibitors  of  metalloproteinase  (TIMPs).  TIMPs  are  matrix  metalloproteinase  (MMP)
        inhibitors involved in tissue remodeling and vascular integrity. Alterations in TIMP levels have been
        implicated in the pathogenesis of CAD, yet the specific impact of smoking on TIMP protein levels
        among individuals with CAD remains inadequately explored. Therefore, this study aimed to determine
        the protein levels of TIMPs among smokers with CAD. Serum isolated from whole blood samples of
        patients  with  three  main  groups  (acute  coronary  syndrome  (ACS),  chronic  coronary  syndrome
        (CCS), and control) was collected for ELISA analysis. The patients were then grouped into ACS and
        smoker  (n=17),  ACS  and  non-smoker  (n=14),  CCS  and  smoker (n=11),  CCS  and  non-smoker
        (n=10), control and smoker (n=20), and control and non-smoker (n=20). The percentage of stenosis
        was significantly higher in the ACS and CCS groups than in the control group. In non-smokers,
        TIMP 3 protein level was significantly increased in ACS (18.89 ± 6.07 ng/mL) and CCS (21.84 ±]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[P-3                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract

        8.63 ng/mL) groups compared to the control group (12.53 ± 2.62 ng/mL). Meanwhile, among
        smokers, TIMP 3 levels were higher in the CCS group compared to the control group (CCS=22.4 ±
        6.80 vs. Control=15.24 ± 3.48 ng/mL; p<0.05). However, there was no significant difference in the
        TIMP 3 levels between smokers and non-smokers within the three main groups. The finding supports
        the role of TIMP in the development of atherosclerotic plaque. However, smoking itself did not affect
        the levels of TIMP 3 in subjects with and without CAD.]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[P-4                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract




          The Influence of Receptor Modulation in Neurogenic Niche of LPC-Induced
                           Demyelinated Postnatal Spinal Cord

           Sharmili Sivanathan, Che Aishah Nazariah Ismail, Rahimah Zakaria, Shazana Hilda
                           Shamsuddin and Nazlahshaniza Shafin*
          Department of Physiology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 16150, Kubang Kerian,
                                     Kelantan, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: drshaniza@usm.my

               A  chronic  autoimmune,  neurodegenerative,  inflammatory  non-traumatic  demyelinating
        disease can impair the proper functioning of axons. The resulting demyelination leads to destructive
        damage to the nervous tissues and causes chronic disability, and relapsing symptoms and can
        progress into a chronic phase. Understanding the mechanism of remyelination is essential to stop
        the  disease  progression.  Additionally,  stimulation  of  endogenous  remyelination  could  have  a
        prodigious therapeutic impact. This study aims to elucidate the mechanism of GABA(B) modulation
        on  remyelination  of  neural  stem  cells  of  the  spinal  cord.  Notably  this  research  represents  the
        exploration of GABAB in potential neural stem cells of the spinal cord. Postnatal Sprague Dawley rats
        D10-D15 were sacrificed, and their spinal cord were collected for proliferation studies. Spinal cord
        samples were assigned to different groups; Lysophosphatidylcholine (LPC), LPC+GABA(B) Agonist,
        LPC + GABA(B) Antagonist, GABA(B) Antagonist, GABA(B) Agonist and the control group. The
        thymidine analogue 5-Ethynyl-2’-deoxyuridine (EdU) was added to the slices in the presence or
        absence of modulators. The expression level of cell proliferation, differentiation and inflammatory
        response  is  measured  by  immunofluorescence,  immunohistochemistry(IHC)  and   Apt-
        immunostaining. The numbers of EdU-positive cells were significantly lower in GABA(B) agonist-
        treated slices (p <0.05) compared with GABA(B) Antagonist-treated slices specific to the central canal
        area in LPC-induced demyelination postnatal spinal cord. Our findings suggest that slices treated
        with baclofen had considerably fewer proliferative cells and GABAB receptor antagonists might be
        able to initiate remyelination. By using aptamer for targeting the immunomodulatory markers TNF-ɑ
        and IL-1, the digital aptamers were created to find the aptamer that has the highest affinity to the
        target molecules. Findings from this study will provide novel insight into the potential role of GABAB
        receptor modulation on neural stem cell proliferation of the spinal cord. Furthermore, understanding
        the underlying mechanisms may guide future researchers in designing potential interventions to
        combat spinal events that lead to the remyelination of neurons.]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[P-5                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract




           Polymeric Nanowires as 3D Scaffold for Cellular Cultivation Intended for
                Downstream Biomarker or Molecular Diagnostic Applications

                          1,
                                                                      2
                                                        1
                                         1
         Salman H. Alrokayan *, Haseeb A. Khan , Tajamul Hussain , Fouzi Mouffouk , Salman
                                                       3
                                     1
                               Alamery  and Khalid Abu-Salah
           1  Department of Biochemistry, College of Science, King Saud University, Riyadh 11451, Saudi Arabia
                2  Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, Kuwait University, Safat 13060, Kuwait
         3  Department of Nanomedicine, King Abdullah International Medical Research Center, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia
                            *Corresponding Author: salrokayan@ksu.edu.sa
               The advent of 3D cell culture not only revolutionized the areas of drug discovery and tissue
        engineering  but  also  influenced  molecular  diagnostic  approaches,  particularly  in  cell-based
        assays.   This  technique  can  also  be  used  to  screen  for small  molecule  drugs  for  personalized
        medicine or genetically manipulated to understand disease pathways. Polymeric nanofibers represent
        an exciting new class of materials that has drawn substantial attention due to the ability of these
        materials to mimic the arrangement of fibrils of the extracellular matrix, making them suitable for a
        wide range of medical applications. We have developed a novel polymeric 3D scaffold based on the
        self-assembly of a star-like amphiphilic co-polymer of poly (caprolactone)-poly(ethylene oxide) base
        unit into nanowires. This nanomaterial has a scale similar to the cellular extracellular matrix and is
        capable of mimicking the extracellular microenvironment and has been tested for the growth and
        proliferation of stem cells. This nanomaterial may have direct implications in 3D cell culture for
        downstream biomarkers or genetic analyses for diagnostic purposes. (This project was funded by
        the National Plan for Science, Technology and Innovation (MAARIFAH), King Abdulaziz City for
        Science and Technology, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Award Number: 14-BIO-1066-02).]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[P-6                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract




           Identification of A Novel Variant in A Proximal Symphalangism Family by
                               Whole-Exome Sequencing

                                                1
                                                        1
                                                                   1
          Xin Chen , Qian Zhang , Litao Qin , Yihui Wang , Ke Yang , Congmin Li  and Shixiu
                                     1
                             1
                 1,2
                                            1,
                                         Liao *
          1  Medical Genetics Institute of Henan Province, Henan Key Laboratory of Genetic Diseases and Functional
           Genomics, Henan Provincial People’s Hospital, People’s Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou
                           University, Zhengzhou, Henan Province, PR China
          2  Medical Genetics Institute of Henan Province, Henan Key Laboratory of Genetic Diseases and Functional
          Genomics, Henan Provincial People’s Hospital, School of Clinical Medicine, Henan University, Zhengzhou,
                                   Henan Province, PR China
                            *Corresponding Author: ychslshx@zzu.edu.cn
               Proximal symphalangism (SYM1) is a rare congenital deformity of limbs. Because of the
        high heterogeneity, the genotype-phenotype analysis disturbed the clinical practice. We recruited an
        SYM1 family at Henan Provincial People's Hospital to elucidate the genetic etiology and examine its
        correlation with the clinical phenotype. The proband underwent whole-exome sequencing (WES).
        Candidate  variants  were  validated  in  the  family  members  through  Sanger  sequencing.  The
        pathogenicity of the variants was assessed using bioinformatics software. Limited flexion of the ring
        and little fingers of both hands was observed in the proband. His father, sister and niece had similar
        symptoms (Fig. 1A). X-ray film showed fusion of the proximal and middle phalanx of the bilateral
        ring and little fingers with interphalangeal joint space disappeared, and short bilateral first toes for
        proband (Fig. 1B). A heterozygous variant c.613T>G (p.Trp205Gly) of NOG gene was identified by
        WES. This variant has not been reported in the literature before and was co-separated from the
        phenotype in the pedigree (Fig. 1C). The 205th tryptophan of Noggin protein encoded by NOG was
        highly conserved among species (Fig. 1D). The protein modeling demonstrated that hydrophobic
        tryptophan  was  mutated  into  hydrophilic  glycine,  which  expanded  the  cavity  (74.304Å^3)  and
        reduced  the  ΔΔG  (-3.282kcal/mol,  ΔΔGpred=4.371),  leading  to  instability  (Fig.  1E).  Most  of  the
        reported NOG variants were located in the conserved region and cause diseases by affecting the
        secretion or dimerization of Noggin. Variant c.613T>G destroyed the hydrophobic interaction among
        Pro56, Trp205 and Trp217. In accordance with the recommendations of the American College of
        Medical Genetics and Genomics, this variant was classified as a likely pathogenic variant. It is worth
        noting variant p.Trp205Cys at the same amino acid site was reported in a family with facio-audio-
        symphalangism syndrome. Another patient carrying p.Trp205Cys displayed multi-system anomalies]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[P-6                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract

        including  hearing  loss, glaucoma,  asthma and vertebral  deformities. These results reflected the
        complex phenotypic heterogeneity of NOG-related disorders. We confirmed a novel variant c.613T>G
        of the NOG gene in a SYM1 family by WES. Our findings enriched the variation spectrum of the NOG
        gene and provided a basis for genetic counseling and prenatal diagnosis.

































        Fig. 1 (A) Pedigree chart of the SYM1 family. (B) X-ray film of bilateral hands and feet of the proband. (C) The
        results of Sanger sequencing. (D) Conservative analysis of the 205th tryptophan of Noggin protein. (E) The
        three-dimensional structure model of Noggin.]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[P-7                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract




         Multiplex PCR Assay for Simultaneous Detection of Vibrio parahaemolyticus
                                 & Vibrio alginolyticus

        Nurlina Rosli , Noorizan Miswan , Nur Ain M. Hussin , Muhammad Syafiq Izzuddin Abd.
                                  2
                                                  3
                   1
                                                                      2,
                              4
                  4
                                                     1,2
              Hadi , Azila Abdullah  and Rashidah Abdul Rahim  and Lau Nyok Sean *
                 1  School of Biological Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 Penang, Malaysia
                 2  Centre for Chemical Biology, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11900 Penang, Malaysia
                      3  Analytical Biochemistry Research Centre, 11900 Penang, Malaysia
         4  National Fish Health Research Center (NaFisH), Department of Fisheries Malaysia, 11960 Penang, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: nyoksean@usm.my
               The  Vibrio  genus  plays  major  roles  in  aquaculture  and  foodborne  pathogens.  V.
        parahaemolyticus (VP) is a well-known species in this genus for causing human infections through
        uncooked or contaminated seafood. Another significant species is V. alginolyticus (VA), which is also
        associated  with  aquaculture  infections  and  antibiotic  resistance  in  human  infections.  Identifying
        Vibrio  species  by  phenotype  and  biochemical  characteristics  is  a  challenge,  thus  necessitating
        nucleic  acid-based  methods.  Nevertheless,  certain  popular  toxin  genes,  such  as  toxR,  are
        overlappingly  present  within  different  Vibrio  species,  rendering  them  unsuitable  for  species
        identification. Additionally, horizontal gene transfers between Vibrio species can occur within the
        same  environment,  further  complicating  species  identification.  A  previous  study  has  utilized
        comparative genomics techniques to identify sequences that showed the potential as biomarker
        regions for V. parahaemolyticus and V. alginolyticus detections. They were revealed via genome
        clustering of multiple Vibrio species genomes based on open reading frames (ORFs). Based on these
        findings, our study aimed to develop new primer sets for the species-specific identification of V.
        parahaemolyticus and V. alginolyticus. These primer sets detect a hypothetical and heme-binding
        proteins in the two species, respectively. To further improve efficiency, the primers were designed
        for  a  multiplex  PCR  assay,  allowing  simultaneous  detection  of  both  species  in  one  reaction.
        Multiplexing  is  advantageous,  considering  both  species  are  typically  present  in  the  same
        environments. Our study utilized the PrimerPremier and PrimerBlast software to generate several
        primer set candidates based on the target sequences. PrimerPremier software was utilized to screen
        the hypothetical and heme-binding protein gene sequences for potential primer sequences. The
        resulting primers were then checked for specificity using PrimerBlast. A pair of primers was then
        selected for each species for multiplex PCR assay assessment using pure culture DNA samples of
        V. parahaemolyticus and V. alginolyticus. Our results showed that the primer sets were able to detect]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[P-7                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract

        V. parahaemolyticus and V. alginolyticus in both singleplex and multiplex assays at the DNA template
        concentration  of  50  ng/μl  with  good  specificity.  The  amplicons  were  299  and  217  bp  in  size,
        corresponding to the hypothetical protein of V. parahaemolyticus and the heme-binding protein of
        V. alginolyticus. No undesired amplifications were detected when the primer sets were tested against
        several  other  common  clinical  bacterial  species.  These  findings  underscore  the  efficacy  of  the
        developed primers in distinguishing between these two significant Vibrio species, offering a reliable
        tool for rapid and accurate detection in clinical and environmental samples.]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[P-8                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract



         Development and Comparison of Primers for Rapid Detection of Leptospira
                          spp. Using Polymerase Chain Reaction

                                                  1
                        1,
                                                                   3
          Noorizan Miswan *, Nurlina Rosli , Lau Nyok Sean , Nur Ain M. Hussin  and Veera
                                     2
                                   Singham K. Genasan
                                                   1
                 1  Centre for Chemical Biology, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11900 Penang, Malaysia
                 2  School of Biological Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 11800 Penang, Malaysia
                      3  Analytical Biochemistry Research Centre, 11900 Penang, Malaysia
                          *Corresponding Author: noorizan_miswan@usm.my
               Leptospirosis  is  an  endemic  disease  that  is  caused  by  pathogenic  Leptospira  spp.
        infections.  The  disease  usually  presents  with  flu-like,  febrile  symptoms  in  humans  which  can
        deteriorate severely and become fatal if not intervened with antibiotic therapy on time. However, the
        current gold standard diagnostic method being used, the microscopic agglutination test (MAT), can
        only detect antibodies approximately one week after the onset of symptoms, besides requiring skilled
        personnel and live cultures. Antigen-based detection methods, on the other hand, can detect much
        smaller  amounts  of  leptospires  that  are  present  in  clinical  samples  during  the  early  phase  of
        infections.  In  this  study,  two  primer  sets  were  developed  for  rapid,  antigen-based  detection  of
        Leptospira spp. via sequence alignment of the rrs and lipL32 genes of multiple Leptospira serovars.
        The rrs gene primers were designed to target all Leptospira spp. strains, while the lipL32 gene
        primers  were  designed  to  detect  only  pathogenic  Leptospira  spp.  serovars.  The  primers  were
        compared against two sets of primers that have been previously published, targeting the lfb1 and
        secYIV genes. All four primer sets were thus compared in a PCR assay of 15 leptospiral serovars
        representing different serogroups, and 3 non-leptospiral bacteria species commonly found in clinical
        settings. The results showed successful detection of the rrs gene among all leptospiral serovars and
        successful detection of the lipL32 gene among only pathogenic leptospiral serovars. The specificity
        of both primer sets was also confirmed as no undesired amplification was observed in the PCR
        reactions with non-leptospiral organisms. The limit of detection was 0.05 pg for purified target DNA
        samples. In conclusion, the newly designed rrs and lipL32 primers gave optimal results for specific,
        sensitive, and rapid detection of Leptospira spp. by PCR.]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[P-9                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract



         Enhancing Molecular Diagnostic Testing for Leptospirosis: Role of External
                 Quality Assurance (EQA) Program in Referral Laboratories

            Mohd Nadzuan Yahaya*, Muhammad Ridhuan Mohd Ali, Meruwan Amin Shoib,
         Muslihah Mohamad, Nor Hazrin Abd Hazis, Rohaidah Hashim and Murnihayati Hassan
         Bacteriology Unit, Infectious Disease Research Centre (IDRC), Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National
                         Institutes of Health (NIH), Setia Alam, Selangor, Malaysia
                          *Corresponding Author: nadzuan.yahaya@moh.gov.my

               Leptospirosis, caused by the spirochete bacteria Leptospira, is a zoonotic disease with
        significant public health implications worldwide and poses a considerable health burden due to its
        prevalence and potential severity in Malaysia. Leptospira polymerase chain reaction (PCR) plays a
        crucial role in identifying the presence of the causative bacteria and confirming the diagnosis. The
        Institute of Medical Research (IMR) is a referral laboratory offering leptospirosis confirmatory tests
        including Leptospira microscopic agglutination test (MAT), culture and PCR. This study aimed to
        identify the role of an External Quality Assurance (EQA) programme for Leptospira PCR diagnostic
        testing from a referral laboratory perspective. We examined the performance data from the EQA report
        for the first year of enrolment (2023). The data were tabulated for descriptive statistics. A literature
        review was conducted to obtain evidence compared to our laboratory experience in similar scenarios.
        In 2023, the EQA module was conducted in three dispatches between March and November. For
        each dispatch, five samples were examined in the same manner as the patient sample, giving a total
        of 15 EQA samples tested for one calendar year. Only one discordant result was recorded in March
        2023  due  to  a  transcription  error  (80%  concordance)  during  the  first  dispatch.  Otherwise,  the
        subsequent dispatches in June and October 2023 yielded 100% results in concordance, with the
        overall concordance rate being 93.3%. Result concordance indicates the consistency of our test
        results which is essential for ensuring the accuracy and reliability of the test currently offered at our
        centre.    EQA  programs  are  generally  a  requirement  for  laboratory  accreditation  and  molecular
        modules in infectious disease and serve as an external platform for laboratories to assess their ability
        to generate accurate, reliable, and consistent reports. Laboratory performance in the EQA program
        is one of the quality performance indicators (QPI) for our institute with a minimum concordance
        result of 85%. Our laboratory was able to achieve the QPI, which also translates to accurate and
        replicable  results.  EQA  participation  allows  laboratories  to  detect  errors  or  discrepancies  by
        comparing their findings with those of other laboratories and reference standards. EQA plays a crucial
        role in instilling confidence in healthcare providers, patients, and public health authorities regarding]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[P-9                                                   Poster Presenter Abstract

        the efficacy of molecular testing for disease diagnosis and management. EQA significantly enhances
        the quality, reliability, and accuracy of molecular diagnostic testing, crucially contributing to high-
        quality diagnostic service delivery in referral laboratories.]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[P-10                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract



         Application of Median Nerve Electrical Stimulation to Regulate miR-1-3p in
          the BDNF/TrkB-MAPK Pathway for Promoting Myelin Regeneration in A Rat
                                     Stroke Model

             Rui Li , Jingyi Lu , Chengcai Zhang , Pengyue Zhang  and Kai Ling Chin *
                                                                       2,
                                                        3
                                          3
                  1,2
                            1
         1  Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, The Second People's Hospital of Kunming, Rehabilitation Hospital
                            affiliated to Kunming University, Kunming, China
        2  Department of Biomedical Sciences, Faculty of Medicine & Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, Kota
                                   Kinabalu, Sabah, Malaysia
         3  Institute of Acupuncture, Tuina, and Rehabilitation, The Second Clinical Medical School, Yunnan University
                            of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Kunming, China
                             *Corresponding email: chinkl@ums.edu.my

               Restoration of the upper limb motor dysfunction following ischemic stroke remains a major
        challenge for rehabilitation medicine. Clinically, we had demonstrated that median nerve electrical
        stimulation (MNES) could significantly improve the upper limb motor function in stroke patients, but
        the underlying mechanism is still unclear. Myelin regeneration is crucial for restoring nerve function
        after a stroke. Within this therapeutic process, the microRNA miR-1-3p, which targets brain-derived
        neurotrophic factor (BDNF), may have a significant impact. In this study, we aimed to investigate the
        potential involvement of MNES in regulating miR-1-3p in the BDNF/TrkB-MAPK pathway to promote
        myelin regeneration in a rat stroke model. Adult male Sprague-Dawley rats (n=18) were divided into
        three groups, i.e., control (sham group), left middle cerebral artery occlusion stroke model (MCAO
        group), and MCAO group receiving MNES treatment (MNES group). The target genes for miR-1-3p
        were predicted using the TargetScan database. The miR-1-3p and BDNF gene expression were
        detected  with  quantitative  reverse  transcription  polymerase  chain  reaction  (RT-qPCR).  The
        expression of BDNF, tropomyosin-related kinase B (Trk-B), and mitogen-activated protein kinases
        (MAPK) were detected by Western blotting. Luxol Fast Blue (LFB) staining was employed to assess
        myelin regeneration. Using bioinformatics analysis, BDNF was identified as the target gene for miR-
        1-3p.  RT-qPCR  analysis  demonstrated  that  MNES  treatment  significantly  decreased  miR-1-3p
        expression (p<0.05) and increased BDNF expression (p<0.01) following ischemic stroke in rats.
        Moreover, the expression levels of BDNF (p<0.05), Trk-B (p<0.01), and MAPK (p<0.01) proteins
        were elevated. The LFB staining in the MCAO group is lighter and patchier, indicating a reduction in
        myelin; however, it becomes noticeably darker and more uniform after MNES treatment, suggesting]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[P-10                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        enhanced  myelin  regeneration.  In  conclusion,  the  MNES  treatment  could  inhibit  miR-1-3p  and
        activate the BDNF/TrkB-MAPK pathway to promote myelin regeneration after a stroke.]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[P-11                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract



         Autoantibodies Profile in Paraneoplastic Neurological Syndromes Associated
                                 Disorders in Malaysia

                                                                          1
                                                            1
                                           1
                       1,
           Ching Yee Ming *, Siti Fatimah Abdullah , Ainur Yusniza Yusof , Siti Asma Bakar ,
                                          1
              Bavithra Venu , Syuriatika Dionysius , Nur Syahirah Alias  and Masita Arip
                         1
                                                           1
                                                                        2
           1  Autoimmune Unit, Allergy and Immunology Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National
                            Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health Malaysia
          2  Allergy and Immunology Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health,
                                   Ministry of Health Malaysia
                            *Corresponding Author: chingym@moh.gov.my
               Paraneoplastic neurological syndromes (PNS) are a heterogeneous group of neurological
        disorders associated with cancer which is not directly caused by metastatic invasion, nutritional
        deficiencies,  infections  or  side  effects  of  the  treatment.  The  presence  of  well-characterised
        paraneoplastic antibodies facilitates the diagnosis of PNS and to identify of the possible underlying
        tumour. In this study, we have evaluated the positivity rate of paraneoplastic antibodies and the
        clinical symptoms of patients with suspected PNS. Paraneoplastic antibodies test results from 793
        samples sent to the Autoimmune Lab of the Institute for Medical Research (IMR), Setia Alam, from
        January 2023 to December 2023 were retrospectively reviewed. The paraneoplastic antibodies test
        detects the presence of antibodies against 12 antigens, namely amphiphysin, CV2, PNMA2 (Ma2/Ta),
        Ri, Yo, Hu, recoverin, SOX1, titin, zic4, GAD65 and Tr (DNER) by immunoblot. The age of this study
        cohort ranged from 9 to 89 years old, with a median age of 58 years, predominantly male (53.2%).
        Of the total 793 samples reviewed, 780 were serum samples, while 13 were cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)
        samples. The positivity rate was 10.8%, including 3 samples which were positive for more than 1
        antigen.  Among the positive samples, the most common high-risk paraneoplastic antibodies (>70%
        associated with cancer) were anti-Yo (18.4%). The most common clinical symptom reported in this
        cohort was encephalitis-related features (46.2%), with a positivity rate of 5.7%. In this study, the
        positivity rate of paraneoplastic antibodies was 10.8%, with anti-Yo antibodies as the most reported
        high-risk antibodies.]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[P-12                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          Genome-Wide DNA Methylation Analysis in Cytogenetically Normal Acute
                    Myeloid Leukemia (CN-AML) Patients from Malaysia

                                               2
                            1,2,
           Nor Rizan Kamaluddin *, Norfarhana Mazlan , Zahidah Abu Seman , Noor Atiqah
                                                                2
          Fakharuzi , Azian Naila Md Nor , Elsa Haniffah Mejia Mohamed , Muhammad Redha
                 2
                                                            3
                                  2
                      4
                                                                       4
         Abdullah Zawawi , Mohd Khairul Nizam Mohd Khalid , Saiful Effendi Syafruddin , Ezalia
                                                  5
                                  1,2
                                                      2
                               Esa and Yuslina Mat Yusoff
          1  Virology Unit, Infectious Disease Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of
                                Health, Ministry of Health Malaysia
          2  Hematology Unit, Cancer Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health,
                                   Ministry of Health Malaysia
                3  Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Malaya, Kuala Lumpur
               4  UKM Medical Molecular Biology Institute, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur
           5  Inborn Errors Metabolism and Genetic Unit, Nutrition, Metabolic and Cardiovascular Research Centre,
                Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health Malaysia
                            *Corresponding Author: norizan.k@moh.gov.my
               Cytogenetically  normal  acute  myeloid  leukaemia  (CN-AML)  is  characterised  by  the
        absence of chromosomal abnormalities, and they constitute between 40 to 50% of all AML cases.  In
        the cases of CN-AML, epigenetic alterations could be an important factor driving the pathogenesis.
        Thus, this study aimed to explore the epigenetic landscape in CN-AML utilising Whole Genome
        Bisulfite Sequencing (WGBS) technology. A cohort of 70 CN-AML patient samples and 10 healthy
        controls  were  subjected  to  WGBS.  Differential  methylation  analysis  was  performed  to  identify
        genome-wide hypermethylated and hypomethylated regions. A total of 18,998 hypermethylated and
        7,979 hypomethylated gene regions were found. The extensive hypermethylated regions found in
        our cohort were consistent with the literature on AML. Among the hypermethylated regions include
        the  promoter  region  of  key  tumour  suppressor  genes,  including CDKN2A, TP53I3,  and WT1.
        Pathway  enrichment analysis indicated a significant enrichment of the Ras-associated  protein  1
        (Rap1) signalling pathway. This finding was supported by a recent AML transcriptome study which
        identified the Rap1 signalling pathway as one of the top pathways that are dysregulated in AML. In
        conclusion, the results showed that CN-AML patients exhibited distinct epigenetic changes and this
        study confirmed that aberrant DNA methylation is an important hallmark of CN-AML.]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[P-13                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract



         CML-miRNA Relapse Detector, a Ready-To-Use Test for Guiding Treatment-
             Free Remission in Chronic Myeloid Leukaemia Adult Patients at the
                                  Molecular Response

         Aliza Mohd Yacob *, Latifah Ibrahim , Nor Asiah Muhamad , Hamidah Akmal Hisham ,
                       1,
                                      2
                                                        3
                                                                            1
                 Shuhaila Mat Sharani , Ernie Zuraida Ali , and Yuslina Mat Yusoff
                                 1,4
                                                                     1
                                                 5
             1  Cancer Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health, Malaysia
             2  Special Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health, Malaysia
                   3  Sector for Evidence-Based Healthcare, National Institutes of Health, Malaysia
                4  Biomedicine Program, School of Health Science, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan
         5  Nutrition, Metabolic and Cardiovascular Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes
                                     of Health, Malaysia
                           *Corresponding Author: aliza.yacob@moh.gov.my
               No treatment-free remission (TFR) test is yet known. The decision for TFR in chronic
        myeloid leukemia (CML) patients is based on a test to monitor disease response to tyrosine kinase
        inhibitors (TKIs) treatments.  Thus 50% of patients relapse within 2 years and 80% within the first 6
        months after treatment cessation.  The gold standard, Real-time quantitative PCR is currently used
        and  the  new  digital  PCR  with  improved  sensitivity  is  under  study  to  be  the  next  reference
        test.  However, a test dedicated to TFR is much needed to overcome the limitation of detecting
        disease at levels beyond the current lower limit  of detection or undetectable. In this study, we
        developed a test with an indication table for guiding TFR in CML adult patients at the molecular
        response: The  test, CML-miRNA Relapse  Detector involves  a  quantitative  analysis  followed  by  a
        qualitative analysis.  The quantitative analysis uses a custom microRNA (miRNA) quantitative PCR
        array followed by a qualitative analysis of cancer genes.  miRNAs of the array were selected from
        next generation sequencing (NGS) analysis.  Targets of three validated miRNAs were predicted using
        molecular prediction tools and databases.  Predicted genes were compared to mRNA NGS data.  This
        is followed by gene analysis on the Proteomic and Genomic Data Commons (PDC/GDC), a repository
        for tumors and cancer. We developed a TFR-CML Indication Table using results from the 3 validated
        miRNAs, NGS mRNA analysis, miRNA target analysis, and Proteomic and Genomic Data Commons
        analysis.  This table will guide the right time to stop TKI treatment in adult Chronic Myeloid Leukemia
        (CML) patients who have consistently reached the deep molecular response stage.  It can also be
        used to recognize the signs of early relapse in patients. This test uses existing laboratory setups and]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[P-13                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        thus is ready to use to guide TFR in CML Adult Patients at the Molecular Response.  Further analysis
        using a bigger sample size is recommended and will be conducted.]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[P-14                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          Unravelling the Impact of Covid-19 Vaccination on Ribonucleic Acid (RNA)
                           Quantities: A Comparative Analysis

         Norfarhana Khairul-Fahmy*, Tengku Nurainna Fatihah Tengku Abdullah, Jamiila Ismail,
                             Masita Arip and Norhazlin Mustafa
          Allergy & Immunology Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National Institutes of Health
                                (NIH), Ministry of Health Malaysia
                           *Corresponding Author: norfarhana.kf@moh.gov.my

               Covid-19 vaccination has shown remarkable effects in transitioning the global pandemic
        to the endemic phase. Although this is an important milestone, vaccine effectiveness varies from one
        person to another. Inter-individual variations in vaccine responses highly affect the magnitude of
        vaccine  immunity  and it  is predicted  that  genetic  factors  contributed  significantly to it.  Prior to
        carrying out any genetic studies, nucleic acid isolation is always the starting point for all downstream
        experiments. Thus, this study aims to assess the change in RNA quantity before and after COVID-
        19 vaccination. The types of vaccines included in the study were BNT162b2 (Pfizer), CoronaVac
        (Sinovac) and ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 (AstraZeneca). Subjects were divided into two groups: those with
        a history of Covid-19 infection (convalescent) and no history of Covid-19 infection (healthy). Blood
        was collected in PAXgene tubes at two time-points: before the administration of the first dose Covid-
        19 vaccine (pre-) and before the administration of the second dose (post-). RNA was extracted using
        the  QIAsymphony  SP  instrument.  RNA  concentration  was  assessed  using  Qubit  fluorometric
        quantification and concentration is translated as the quantity of RNA present in each sample. Results
        showed that RNA concentrations were significantly decreased from pre- (mean = 63.35 µg/ml, s.d.
        = 23.07) to post-vaccination (mean = 59.24 µg/ml, s.d. = 26.17) in all samples (t (133) = -2.22,
        p<0.05). Changes in RNA concentration pre- and post-vaccination were also significantly different
        across  all  types  of  studied  vaccines.  Further  assessments  revealed  that  convalescent  subjects
        (median = 57.97 µg/ml, IQR = 29.95) contained significantly higher RNA concentration than healthy
        individuals  (median  =  52.34  µg/ml,  IQR  =  23.56),  Z  =  -2.12,  p<0.05.  Stratification  of  subjects
        according to the types of vaccines showed no significant difference between the convalescent and
        healthy groups. RNA quantity reflects how vigorously a gene has been transcribed and those genes
        are expressed according to the needs of the moment. Results from this study may indicate the
        immune response dynamics towards Covid-19 vaccination. The body may initially ramp up gene
        expression prior to vaccination and downregulate certain responses after vaccination, resulting in a]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[P-14                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        net decrease in RNA concentration. Additionally, the vaccine acts as a booster for convalescent
        subjects by triggering a strong reactivation of the immune memory established during the initial
        infection. This reactivation leads to a more sustained transcriptional activity, as reflected by higher
        RNA levels. In conclusion, this study provides foundational insights into the differential immune
        responses to Covid-19 vaccination.]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[P-15                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract



          Whole-Genome Sequencing Analysis of Multi-Drug Resistant Salmonella
                  enterica Serovar Typhi from Clinical Isolates in Malaysia

         Nor Hazrin Abd Hazis*, Hana Farizah Zamri, Mohammad Ridhuan Mohd Ali, Jama'ayah
                            Mohamed Zahidi and Rohaidah Hashim
           Bacteriology Unit, Infectious Disease Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, NIH Setia Alam,
                                   Ministry of Health Malaysia
                            *Corresponding Author: norhazrin@moh.gov.my

               Typhoid fever, caused by Salmonella enterica serovar Typhi (S. Typhi), poses a significant
        public health challenge in low- and middle-income countries. The rise of multidrug-resistant (MDR)
        S. Typhi, which shows resistance to both first-line and second-line antibiotics, has compromised the
        effectiveness of antimicrobial treatments. This study aimed to examine the antimicrobial resistance
        genes and the molecular epidemiology of MDR S. Typhi over 10 years (2014–2023) in Malaysia.
        Twenty-four  MDR  S.  Typhi  isolates,  confirmed  through  antimicrobial  susceptibility  testing  were
        subjected to whole-genome sequencing (WGS) using the Illumina NextSeq platform. The WGS data
        were processed with TheiaProk Illumina PE Version 1.3.0, and a single-nucleotide polymorphism
        (SNP)  phylogenetic  tree  was  generated  using  kSNP3_PHB  Version  2.01  within  Terra.bio
        (https://app.terra.bio).  The  resulting  phylogenetic  tree  was  visualized  using  Microreact
        (http://microreact.org).  WGS  analysis  identified  all  isolates  as  genotype  4.3.1.1  (H58  haplotype
        lineage  1),  a  lineage  strongly  associated  with  multidrug  resistance.  The  analysis  identified  five
        antimicrobial resistance genes linked to first-line antibiotics: catA1 for chloramphenicol resistance;
        dfrA7, sul1, and sul2 for trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole resistance; and blaTEM-1D for ampicillin
        resistance. Additionally, WGS detected single-point mutations in the gyrA gene (gyrA_S83Y and
        gyrA_S83F),  which  are  associated  with  reduced  susceptibility  to  second-line  fluoroquinolone
        antibiotics, such as ciprofloxacin. A single-nucleotide polymorphism (SNP)-based phylogenetic tree,
        constructed using selected genomes from public databases, clustered the Malaysian MDR S. Typhi
        isolates with internationally reported strains from Bangladesh and Pakistan, where genotype 4.3.1.1
        is known to be endemic. WGS of the MDR S. Typhi genotype 4.3.1.1 offers valuable insights into
        the genetic mechanisms driving its resistance to multiple antibiotics and its global dissemination. As
        a sub-lineage of the H58 haplotype, this genotype is especially alarming because of its strong
        association  with  widespread  multidrug  resistance,  particularly  in  areas  where  typhoid  fever  is
        endemic.]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[P-16                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




           Demographic Characteristics and Antifungal Susceptibility of Kodamaea
                        ohmeri Isolates from Hospitals in Malaysia

           Nur Fadhilah Abu Bakar*, Mohammad Ridhuan Mohd Ali, Salina Mohamed Sukur,
                          Murnihayati Hassan and Rohaidah Hashim
         Bacteriology Unit, Infectious Disease Research Centre (IDRC), Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National
                            Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health Malaysia
                          *Corresponding Author: nurfadhilah.ab@moh.gov.my

               Kodamaea ohmeri is an emerging yeast pathogen that has gained attention in various parts
        of  the  world,  including  Malaysia,  due  to  its  association  with  invasive  infections,  particularly  in
        immunocompromised individuals. Despite its growing clinical importance in invasive fungal diseases
        (IFD), there is a lack of comprehensive global data on the occurrence and distribution of K. ohmeri.
        The purpose of the study is to outline the demographics of patients infected with K. ohmeri and to
        assess the antifungal susceptibility in Malaysia. All infection cases of K. ohmeri were extracted from
        the National Surveillance of Antimicrobial Resistance (NSAR) database from the year 2019 to 2023.
        Subsequently, the data were analysed to determine the distribution and antifungal susceptibility
        patterns. Out of the 188,193 fungi cases reported in the NSAR database, 0.064% were identified as
        K. ohmeri (n=120) and there was a rising pattern from 2019 to 2023. The majority of cases (16%)
        were among individuals aged 25-44 years, followed by those aged 65 and above, who accounted for
        11%. In addition, K. ohmeri was predominantly found in sterile blood specimens (62%), while non-
        sterile sources like fluid and urine made up 13% and 11% of cases, respectively. Out of the 8 isolates
        tested, 3 were resistant to fluconazole, but all 8 were sensitive to the other 5 antifungal agents. The
        rising trend, with most cases coming from blood samples, shows that K. ohmeri infections are
        becoming more common, particularly in healthcare settings. To address this, healthcare providers
        and public health officials must enhance treatment strategies and improve infection control measures
        to reduce the risk of nosocomial K. ohmeri infections. Given the significant resistance to fluconazole,
        its use may be unsuitable for treating infections caused by K. ohmeri. Further research on K.ohmeri
        is essential to better understand its prevalence and optimize patient care.]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[P-17                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




         GAPDH as a Housekeeping Gene Expression in Apoptotic Signaling Variables
        and is Suitable for Normalizing Total RNA Levels Expression in Human Breast
            Cancer Cells Treated with Dichloromethane Clinacanthus nutans Leaf
                                        Extracts

          Zaleha Md Toha*, Norhasyimah Haron, Kristine Sandra Pey Adum and Hasni Arsad
          Advanced Medical and Dental Institute, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Bertam, 13200 Kepala Batas, Seberang
                                   Perai Utara, Pulau Pinang
                            *Corresponding Author: zaleha.mdtoha@usm.my

               One trustworthy and popular technique for determining and assessing the levels of gene
        expression is real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction, or RT-qPCR. The right interpretation
        of real-time PCR results depends on the selection of appropriate housekeeping or internal control
        genes. Here, we provide a method to find housekeeping genes that might be used as an appropriate
        internal control for comparison studies of gene expression data collected using quantitative real-time
        PCR  (RT-qPCR)  and  high  throughput  sequencing  in  breast  cancer.  When  comparing  gene
        expression data, the most often utilized housekeeping genes are β-actin and glyceraldehyde-3-
        phosphate dehydrogenase (GAPDH). The purpose of this study to determine an appropriate internal
        control for the expression of genes in breast cancer cell lines (MCF-7) treated with extracts from
        Clinacanthus nutans (CNDCM) and dichloromethane. The GAPDH and beta-actin were selected as
        internal  controls.  All  target  genes  were  obtained  and  significantly  selected  from  transcriptomic
        profiling RNA-Seq data and their validation by RT-qPCR. The selection of target genes is based on
        KEGG software, which has potential as a proapoptotic that is important in cancer research. The target
        genes used in the study included ALDH3A1, CYP1A1, CYP2A6, FCER1G and CES1. All the genes
        were then normalized and compared with beta-actin and GAPDH as housekeeping genes or internal
        controls.  Fold  changes  in  relative  gene  expression  were  determined  by  the  changes  in  cycle
        threshold  (CT)  values  and  the  data  obtained  were  normalized  against  the  housekeeping  gene
        transcript. Relative fold changes were calculated using the delta-delta CT method (2-∆∆CT) or the
        Levin method. The target gene primer set did not have an amplification efficiency within the range
        95-100%.  The  expression  levels  of  the  target  genes  were  normalized  to  the  expression genes
        housekeeping β-actin and GAPDH. The correlation coefficient was calculated by a standard curve
        indicating the linearity of the data. The expression genes indicated ALDH1A3, CYP2A6 and CES1 as
        upregulated genes, while CYP1A1 and FER1G were downregulated genes. The final result found,]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[P-17                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        that the GAPDH was the stable housekeeping gene when normalized with all target genes and proved
        to be less variable and thus potentially more accurate for research and clinical analyses of breast
        cancer  cell  lines.  These  findings  emphasize  the  significance  of  a  thorough  assessment  of
        housekeeping genes for their applicability as an internal control for optimal intra- and inter-assay
        comparison  of breast  cancer  gene  expression  that  may  be  extended  to  other  tumor  types  and
        diseases.]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[P-18                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          MEF2A-Mediated Transcriptional Activation of NFKBIA Reduces Cisplatin
                            Resistance in Gastric Cancer Cells

                                                                             1
                                   1,2
                                              3
                                                               1,2
                    1,2
         Chenghao Chu , Yongwei Zhang , Ruiran Yu , Bin Liu , Bin Wang , Zhangxuan Xu
                                                     1,2
                                   and Kai Ling Chin *
                                                 2,
               1  Department of General Surgery, Anqing First People’s Hospital, 246000, Anqing, China
         2  Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, 88400, Kota Kinabalu, Sabah, Malaysia
                 3  Department of Oncology, Anqing First People’s Hospital, 246000, Anqing, China
                             *Corresponding Author: chinkl@ums.edu.my
               Cisplatin (DDP) resistance represents a pivotal contributing factor to chemotherapy failure
        and adverse patient outcomes in the context of gastric cancer (GC). The objective of the present
        study was to delineate roles and the underlying mechanisms through which myocyte enhancer factor
        2A (MEF2A) in DDP resistance in GC. The human gastric cell lines AGS and MKN-45 were used to
        construct DDP-resistant cells (AGS/DDP and MKN-45/DDP). Cell Counting Kit-8 (CCK-8) assay was
        used to assess cell proliferation and determine the half-maximal inhibitory concentration (IC50) of
        cisplatin (DDP). Colony formation ability was evaluated by colony formation assay and cell apoptosis
        was measured by flow cytometry. Reverse transcription-quantitative polymerase chain reaction (RT-
        qPCR) and Western blotting analysis were used to quantify the mRNA and protein levels. Chromatin
        immunoprecipitation (ChIP) and dual luciferase assays were used to affirm the relationship between
        MEF2A and its target NF-κB inhibitor alpha (NFKBIA). CCK-8 analysis showed that AGS/DDP and
        MKN-45/DDP  cells  exhibited  higher  DDP  resistance  and  IC50  values  than  their  parental  cells.
        Moreover, both qRT-PCR and Western blot experiments uncovered that NFKBIA was significantly
        reduced in AGS/DDP and MKN-45/DDP cells than their parental cells. Upregulation of NFKBIA led
        to a decreased cell survival rate and IC50, decreased the number of cell colonies, and enhanced cell
        apoptosis in AGS/DDP and MKN-45/DDP cells. Furthermore, the mRNA and protein levels of MEF2A
        were significantly reduced in AGS/DDP and MKN-45/DDP cells than their parental cells. The binding
        motif of MEF2A was identified from the JASPAR online database (https://jaspar.elixir.no/), revealing
        two putative transcriptional sites on the NFKBIA promoter (#1, -558~-572; and #2, -59~-73). ChIP
        and dual luciferase assays confirmed that MEF2A interacts with the NFKBIA promoter, where MEF2A
        transcriptionally  activates  the  expression  of  NFKBIA  in  AGS/DDP  and  MKN-45/DDP  cells.  In
        conclusion, MEF2A mitigated the DDP resistance in GC cells by activating NFKBIA, shedding light
        on MEF2A/NFKBIA might be a promising intervention target for improving DDP resistance in GC.]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[P-19                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




         Humoral Response and Neutrophil Degranulation Pathways Are Key Factors
                  in Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma (DLBCL) Modulation

                                      2
                        1,
                                                                            1
         Nor Adzimah Johdi *, Amanda Seng , Wei-Kang Lee , Hanif Zulkhairi Mohamad Said
                                                   2
                              and Wan Fariza Wan Jamaluddin
                                                        3
         1  UKM Medical Molecular Biology Institute, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                  2  Codon Genomics Sdn Bhd, Seri Kembangan Selangor Darul Ehsan, Malaysia
               3  Cell Therapy Center, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Cheras, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                          *Corresponding Author: adzimah@ppukm.ukm.edu.my
               Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL) is globally recognized as the most prevalent and
        aggressive subtype of non-Hodgkin lymphoma. While conventional treatments are effective initially,
        the disease can become resistant or relapse over time. The study aimed to examine the differentially
        expressed  genes  at  the  transcriptome  level  and  molecular  pathways  in  DLBCL  patients.  This
        investigation utilized RNA sequencing analysis to compare differentially expressed gene samples
        from five diffuse large B-cell lymphoma patients with two healthy volunteers. These participants were
        admitted  to  Hospital  Canselor  Tuanku  Muhriz  UKM  (HCTM)between  2019  and  2020.  Using  a
        negative binomial distribution model, the differentially expressed genes were conducted using the
        DESeq2 R package (version 1.10.1). The obtained P values were corrected with the Benjamin and
        Hochberg method and identified using a False Discovery Rate threshold of <0.05, with log2 fold
        change (FC) of ≥2 or ≤-2. Results showed 73 differentially expressed genes between the two groups,
        among  which  70  genes  were  downregulated,  and  three  were  upregulated.  The  differentially
        expressed  genes  analyzed  with  the  Reactome  pathway  were  significantly  associated  with  the
        downregulation of antimicrobial humoral response (P<0.001), neutrophil degranulation (P<0.001),
        chemokine  receptors  bind  chemokines  (P=0.028),  defensins  (P=0.028)  and  metabolism  of
        angiotensinogen (P=0.040). These findings suggest that the identified pathways may contribute to
        cancer progression and weaken the immune response in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma patients.
        This study offers insights into previously undiscovered downstream targets and pathways modulated
        by diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[P-20                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          Mechanisms of Chemoresistance in Colorectal Cancer: Insights from Gene
               Expression and Protein Profiling in Cisplatin-Resistant Models

                                                           3,4
                                              2
                                                                        1,
            Zhijack Fong , Zainal Abidin Syafiq Asnawi , Bey-Hing Goh , Wai-Leng Lee *
                      1
        1  School of Science, Monash University Malaysia, Jalan Lagoon Selatan, Bandar Sunway, 47500 Subang Jaya,
                                     Selangor, Malaysia
          2  Jeffery Cheah School of Medicine, Monash University Malaysia, Jalan Lagoon Selatan, Bandar Sunway,
                              47500 Subang Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia
           3  Department of Biological Sciences, School of Medicine and Life Sciences, Sunway University, 47500
                                 Subang Jaya, Selangor Malaysia
                4 College of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310058, China

                           *Corresponding Author: lee.wai.leng@monash.edu

               Colorectal cancer (CRC) is one of the most commonly diagnosed cancers and a leading
        cause of cancer-related deaths. The ineffectiveness of chemotherapy, including combination drug
        regimens, complicates the survival rates of advanced CRC. The molecular mechanisms underlying
        chemoresistance in CRC remain largely elusive. This study aimed to investigate these mechanisms
        from both clinical and in vitro perspectives. First, bioinformatics analysis of transcriptomic data from
        colon and rectum adenocarcinoma patients in The Cancer Genome Atlas revealed a substantial
        number of differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between chemosensitive and chemoresistant CRC
        patients. Further, clustering of these genes using Gene Ontology and KEGG databases, coupled with
        literature mining, implicated apoptosis inhibition as a pivotal factor in CRC chemoresistance. In our
        laboratory, we established in vitro CRC cell lines with acquired drug resistance. Three HCT116
        sublines with acquired cisplatin resistance were developed through prolonged drug exposure with
        stepwise dosage increases: HCT116/I24781, HCT116/I248, and HCT116/I555, exhibiting 24.5-fold,
        19.2-fold, and 17.2-fold increases in cisplatin resistance, respectively. Proteomics analysis and cell-
        based assays validated that these cisplatin-resistant HCT116 sublines developed insensitivity to
        cisplatin-induced  apoptosis.  Intriguingly,  both  clinical  transcriptomic  in  silico  analysis  and
        proteomics  studies  of  in  vitro  resistant  CRC  lines  in  this  study  suggested  that  hypoxia-related
        pathways may play a role in regulating CRC chemoresistance. Unlike the reactive oxygen species
        (ROS)-dependent cell death observed in cisplatin-sensitive HCT116 parental cells, ROS failed to
        sensitize the resistant lines to cisplatin treatment, resembling the behavior of hypoxic cancer cells.  In
        vitro cells were supplemented with oxygen for their growth, leading us to speculate that cisplatin-
        triggered pseudohypoxia may occur in the resistant lines.  Together, these findings suggest that both]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[P-20                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        apoptosis evasion and therapy-induced pseudohypoxia may contribute to chemoresistance in CRC
        cells.]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[P-21                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




               Spinal Muscular Atrophy (SMA) Carrier Screening in Malaysia

           Nor Azimah Abdul Azize *, Vengadeshwaran A/L Suberamaniam , Lua Seok Hian ,
                                                             1
                                                                           1
                             1,
                       2
                                    2
                                                                           3
           Ch’ng Gaik Siew , Moey Lip Hen , Muzhira Aisha Md Haniffa , Winnie Ong Peitee ,
                                                          3
           Chew Hui Bin , Leong Huey Yin , Kavitha A/P Rethanavelu , Ngu Lock Hock  and
                                                         3
                                                                       3
                                    3
                      3
                                     Yusnita Yakob
                                                1
          1  Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur
               2  Genetics Department, Pulau Pinang Hospital, Ministry of Health Malaysia, Pulau Pinang
               3  Genetics Department, Kuala Lumpur Hospital, Ministry of Health Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur
                           *Corresponding Author: azimahazize@moh.gov.my
               Spinal  muscular  atrophy  (SMA)  is  an  autosomal  recessive  neuromuscular  disorder
        presented  with  progressive  proximal  muscle  weakness  and  paralysis,  affecting  approximately
        1:10,000 live births, with reported carrier frequency of 1:41 in Europe and 1:51 worldwide. Majority
        of the SMA cases due to the homozygous deletion of exons 7 and 8 of the survival motor neuron
        (SMN) 1 gene. The severity of the disease is determined by the SMN2 gene.  In Malaysia, carrier
        frequency of SMA is currently not available. The aim of this study is to analyse copy number of
        SMN1 and SMN2 gene using two different methods in identifying SMA carriers among volunteered
        parental and family members at risk. A retrospective data from 2009-2023 (n=2018) were collected.
        The laboratory methods involved DNA extraction from blood-EDTA samples, followed by PCR-RFLP
        method  for  samples  received  in  2009-2015  (n=1024)  and  by  multiplex  ligation-dependent
        amplification (MLPA) method for samples 2016-2023 (n=994). Copy number were analysed using
        GeneMarker software. About 132 parental and 32 family members were analysed for carrier status.
        Of 1024 samples analysed by PCR-RFLP, 168 (16%) were diagnosed as SMA and remaining 84%
        could not be determined whether normal or carrier. By MLPA, 168/994 (17%) patients were SMA
        positive. Whereas 92% (122/132) of parental samples carry 1 copy of SMN1 gene, 7% (9/132) carry
        2 copies and 1% (1/132) carry 1 copy with intragenic mutation. Analysis of 32 family members
        revealed  81%  (26/32)  carry  1  copy,  16%  (5/32)  and  3%  (1/32)  carry  2  copies  and  3  copies,
        respectively. PCR-RFLP was unable to identify SMA carrier because it cannot detect heterozygous
        deletion. In contrast, MLPA can provide the copy number of both SMN1 and SMN2 gene hence is
        able to genotype the carrier and severity of SMA as well. In carrier screening, 92% of parents carry
        1 copy with genotype [1+0]. About 7% of parental SMA carry 2 copy and may have genotype of
        silent carrier [2+0]. For analysis of family members, 81% are SMA carrier with genotype [1+0].
        Family members with 2 SMN1 copy number have genotype either normal [1+1] or silent carrier]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[P-21                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        [2+0], therefore segregation analysis in the family is recommended. A higher frequency rate in our
        study (92% from parental and 81% from family members) suggested the importance on carrier
        screening as it can reduce the risk of having affected offspring. MLPA is a gold standard method not
        only for SMA diagnosis and carrier screening but also prognosis.]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[P-22                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




             Expanding the Mutational Spectrum: Identification and Phenotypic
          Correlations of Four Putative Novel Variants in PAFAH1B1 and DCX Genes
                                Related to Lissencephaly

             Nur Hasmi Abdul Multalib *, Nor Azimah Abdul Azize , Vengadeshwaran a/l
                                  1,
                                                       1
          Suberamaniam, Malini a/p Mahalingam Ahmad Rithauddin Mohamed  and Yusnita
                                         2,
                                                                 3
                                        Yakob
                                             1
          1  Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur
                2  Paediatric Department, Raja Permaisuri Bainun  Hospital, Ministry of Health Malaysia
              Perak Tunku Azizah Women & Children Hospital, Ministry of Health Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur
              3
                            *Corresponding Author: nurhasmi@moh.gov.my
               Lissencephaly (LIS) refers to a group of neurodevelopmental disorders that is marked by
        a smooth brain surface arises from neuronal migration disruption occurring between 12 and 24
        weeks of gestation. The clinical presentation manifests in varying degrees of developmental delayed,
        epilepsy, and intellectual disability, primarily driven by mutations in PAFAH1B1 and DCX gene. The
        PAFAH1B1 gene mutations are responsible for over half of LIS cases and is inherited in autosomal
        dominant pattern. While the DCX gene mutations cause about 10 percent of cases with X-linked
        inheritance. The aim of the present study was to identify pathogenic variants in patients clinically
        suspected for having LIS in these two causative genes. We conducted data analysis from 22 patients
        clinically diagnosed with LIS referred to our laboratory from 2015 to 2024. Blood EDTA samples
        were collected for DNA extraction, followed by PCR amplification and sanger sequencing of both
        genes. The identified variants were evaluated for pathogenicity by in-silico prediction tools and in
        accordance  to  American  College  of  Medical  Genetics  and  Genomics  (ACMG)  guidelines.  Four
        pathogenic variants were identified in 4 out of 22 patients (18%) with two variants in PAFAH1B1
        (p.(Glu34LysfsTer4) and p.(His379Arg))  and  DCX gene (p,(Ser74LeufsTer2) and p.(Ala204Asp)).
        All variants were not previously reported elsewhere; thus, novel. We believe these variants are the
        causative as it is consistent with imaging and phenotypes presented in the patients.  Symptoms like
        intellectual disability and seizures occurs in most LIS patient and given the phenotypic overlap
        between the two genes a comprehensive molecular testing is recommended to ensure more accurate
        diagnosis of LIS. About 80% of patients remain unsolved in our study, mainly due to test limitation
        as the method used was for single gene and not able to detect large deletion. Therefore, future
        molecular study using exome and genome sequencing is imperative to identify other genes that]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[P-22                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        responsible for LIS, thus enhance detection rates and improve genetic counselling as well as patient
        management. Our findings not only expanded the spectrum of genetic mutations in PAFAH1B1 and
        DCX genes but also contributed in understanding genotype-phenotype correlations in LIS, which
        would be invaluable for clinical management and diagnostic strategies.]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[P-23                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          Phenotypic and Genetic Characteristics of Mucopolysaccharidosis Type II
                 Patients: A Single Centre Retrospective Study in Malaysia

                1,2
                                                                             2
                                                         1
                                         1
        Affandi O , Salina AR , Fatimah Diana AN , Norashareena MS , Mohd Shihabuddin AN ,
                          1
                                            3

                             HY Leong , LH Ngu  and Julaina AJ 1
                                     3
          1  Inborn Errors of Metabolism and Genetics Unit, NMCRC, Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National
                     Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health, Setia Alam, Selangor, Malaysia
          2  Faculty of Pharmacy, Universiti Teknologi MARA (UiTM), Puncak Alam Campus, Puncak Alam, Selangor,
                                        Malaysia
          3  Genetics Department, Hospital Kuala Lumpur, Ministry of Health Malaysia, Jalan Pahang, 50586 Kuala
                                     Lumpur, Malaysia
                           *Corresponding Author: julaina.jalil@moh.gov.my
               Mucopolysaccharidosis type II (MPS II; Hunter syndrome) is a rare, X-linked disorder
        caused by deficient activity of the enzyme iduronate-2-sulfatase which contributes to a multisystemic
        metabolic  manifestation.  Treatment  is  available  as  enzyme  replacement  therapy  (ERT)  with
        recombinant iduronate-2-sulfatase (idursulfase). The prevalence of MPS II is quite common in Asian
        countries including Malaysia. This report conducted a retrospective analysis to investigate the clinical
        characteristics, genotypes and of Malaysian patients with MPS II. Skin biopsy samples were collected
        from subjects at Hospital Kuala Lumpur who had consented to participate in the NMRR-20-669-
        54509 research and for future research projects. Descriptive analyses were performed using SPSS
        version 23.0. Results are presented as mean ± standard deviation and frequency. Eight patients
        agreed to participate in this study with the mean age (in years) of 12.88 ± 6.03. IDS activity and
        glycosaminoglycans (GAGs) levels were 4.75 ± 1.16 nmol/4hr/mg protein and 828.51 ± 243.32
        ng/mg protein, respectively. Six patients were of Malay ethnicity, whereas two were of Chinese
        descent. Most patients were from the central region (5 out of 8). Most of the patients presented with
        claw-like hands, coarse facies and obstructive sleep apnea. Five patients were reported to have
        missense mutation, and one each for splice mutation and rearrangement of enzyme complex. The
        reduction in GAG levels (p<0.05) observed in patients 1, 2, 3, and 5 demonstrated a significant
        response to enzyme replacement therapy. This study provided additional information on the clinical
        and genotype in MPS II patients. Based on these data, characterisation of this cohort group could
        be used as a baseline for pharmacological chaperone testing in cell studies in the future.]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[P-24                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          Revolutionizing Aptamer Development: Electrochemical-based SELEX for
                                  Rapid Target Binding

                                                                           1,
                                                1
                            1
         Shankariswari Yadevan , Nur Fatihah Mohd Zaidi and Khairul Mohd Fadzli Mustaffa *
        1  Institute for Research in Molecular Medicine (INFORMM), Health Campus, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang
                                      Kerian, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: khairulmf@usm.my

               Aptamers  are  single-stranded  oligonucleotides  that  fold  into  3-dimensional  shapes
        capable of binding non-covalently with high affinity and specificity to a target molecule. Lately, they
        have been gaining more attention than antibodies due to their advantages as affinity ligands. They
        are isolated through in vitro process called Systemic Evolution of Ligands by EXponential enrichment
        (SELEX) and offer advantages like longer shelf life, low-cost production, better stability, and low
        immunogenicity. However, the use of conventional SELEX becomes a barrier to the production of
        aptamer due to its laborious and costly nature. To overcome these challenges, this study introduces
        an electrochemical-based SELEX designed for rapid, real-time, and effective aptamer development.
        This selection platform involves immobilizing target protein by using linkers containing thiol and
        carboxyl  group  on  the  gold  electrode,  followed  by  DNA  aptamer.  To  analyse  the  binding,  the
        electrode surface is exposed to a ferro/ferricyanide redox couple solution which yields square wave
        voltammetry  (SWV)  signal.  This  electrochemical  approach  eliminates  the  need  for  beads  and
        fluorescence labelling, providing easier aptamer/target incubation, washing, and elution steps. After
        the elution, the bound aptamers are amplified using polymerase chain reaction (PCR), and the
        resulting  PCR  products  are  regenerated  to  produce  single-stranded  DNA  (ssDNA)  pool  for
        subsequent cycles. Negative selection is also carried out by incubating electrodes with linkers and
        DNA aptamer without the target protein. As a result, six SELEX cycles were successfully performed
        where high-affinity aptamers bind to the target analyte. To confirm the success of immobilization
        steps, cyclic voltammetry (CV) and SWV were employed to check for stability and peak reduction
        current, respectively. The SWV reduction peak current was calculated for each SELEX cycle before
        and after incubating with DNA aptamers using the formula [(i° − i)/i°%] to determine the most
        enriched cycle. In conclusion, DNA aptamers bound to target proteins were successfully isolated and
        later will be characterized for its binding and affinity. These potential high-affinity aptamers hold
        promise for use in diagnostic or therapeutic applications.]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[P-25                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




           Manufacturing and Validation of Current Good Manufacturing Practices
           (cGMP)-Compliant Umbilical Cord-Derived Mesenchymal Stromal Cells
                             (UCMSC) for Clinical Application

            Noor Atiqah Fakharuzi, Kamal Shaik Fakiruddin, Rohaina Abd Razak, Govathini
         Sathiaselan, Muhammad Nazirul Fahmi, Nur Alia Syuhada, Mughuntha Anujana Nagen,
          Sujatha Suthandiram, Yuslina Mat Yusoff, Adiratna Mat Ripen and Lim Moon Nian*

          Department Good Manufacturing Practice (GMP) Laboratory, Biomedical Research Core Facility (BioRCF),
         Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National Institutes of Health (NIH), Ministry of Health Malaysia (MOH),
                           Setia Alam, 40170 Shah Alam, Selangor, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: limmn@moh.gov.my

               Umbilical cord-derived mesenchymal stromal cells (UCMSCs) hold significant promise in
        treating various diseases due to their regenerative and immunomodulatory properties. In Malaysia,
        MSCs are classified as Cell and Gene Therapy Products (CGTPs) and regulated as biologics. The
        regulatory  framework  for  CGTPs  is  outlined  in  the  Guidance  Document  and  Guidelines  for
        Registration of CGTPs, as well as in the second edition of the Drug Registration Guidance Document
        (DRGD). In this regulatory context, producing MSCs on a large scale using a robust manufacturing
        protocol is crucial to meet clinical demands. Thus, this study aimed to validate the production of
        UCMSCs in compliance with regulatory requirements. The product validation involves several key
        steps  including  validation  of  raw  materials,  qualifying  GMP  personnels  and  validating  the
        manufacturing processes. In this study, we established a well-characterized two-tiered system of
        Master Cell Bank (MCB) and Working Cell Bank (WCB) to generate a large-scale expansion of
        UCMSCs.  Comprehensive  in-process  and  product  release  tests  including  sterility,  karyotyping,
        endotoxin  test,  mycoplasma,  and  immunophenotype  were  evaluated  to  determine  the  identity,
        potency, safety, and purity of the UCMSCs in accordance with the International Society for Cell and
        Gene Therapy (ISCT) and Pharmaceutical Inspection Co-operation Scheme (PIC/S) GMP Guide on
        Manufacture  of  Sterile  Medicinal  Product  (Annex  1).  Altogether,  our  results  demonstrated  that
        UCMSCs  maintain  their  multipotent  differentiation  capacity,  morphology  and  surface  marker
        expression. No genetic abnormalities were detected and all batches were confirmed to be free of
        microbial contamination. In conclusion, we successfully adapted our clinical-grade MSC production
        process to meet the GMP requirements. UCMSCs were efficiently derived from three donors using]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[P-25                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        a  GMP-compliant  culture  system,  and  three  consecutive  production  batches  were  successfully
        validated under stringent regulatory conditions.]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[P-26                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          Quantitative Analysis of TNF-α Levels in Plasma: Evaluating the Impact of
          Different Celastrol Doses in High-Fat Diet-Fed ApoE-Knockout Mice Using
                                        ELISA

             Arifah Ahmad Damahuri , Thuhairah Hasrah Abdul Rahman , B. Vimala R.M.T
                                                           1
                                1
                           Balasubramaniam  and Nasibah Azme *
                                                         1,
                                         2
                   1  Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University Teknologi MARA
            2  Nutrition, Metabolism & Cardiovascular Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, Selangor
                            *Corresponding Author: nasibah@uitm.edu.my

               A notable trend in contemporary society is the consumption of a hypercaloric (Western)
        diet, which is associated with the induction of systemic inflammation. Celastrol has been explored in
        multiple models as a promising drug to highlight its therapeutic properties in reducing inflammation.
        However, the effects of different celastrol doses on inflammatory cytokine levels in ApoE-knockout
        mice remain to be determined. Thus, this study aims to investigate the effect of different doses of
        celastrol on TNF- α levels in the plasma of ApoE-knockout mice fed a high-fat diet (HFD) via ELISA.
        Four groups of male ApoE-knockout mice were fed with HFD for 12 weeks starting at 8 weeks of
        age. Meanwhile, the control normal diet group was fed with a chow diet. During the last 4 weeks,
        three groups that were fed a HFD received intraperitoneal injection of celastrol treatment at doses of
        1.5 mg, 2 mg, and 2.5 mg/kg/day, respectively, while the control HFD and normal diet groups
        received 2% DMSO/day. At the end of the treatment, blood was collected through cardiac puncture
        before mice were sacrificed and centrifuged for 15 minutes at 1000 xg at 4°C within 30 minutes of
        collection. Then, plasma was assigned for double-sandwich ELISA according to the manufacturer’s
        instructions, Finestest (Mouse TNF- α, Tumor Necrosis Factor Alpha ELISA kit; EM0183). Data were
        analyzed using Thermo Scientific Multiskan FC 357 Microplate Photometer and Kruskal-Wallis test
        in GraphPad Prism 10. The findings showed there were no significant changes between all groups,
        but all celastrol-treated groups displayed a decreasing pattern in TNF- α level compared to the control
        HFD  group.  Celastrol,  as  an  anti-inflammatory  therapy,  warrants  further  studies  on  prolonged
        Western diet consumption, as it may be effective in other models, particularly those at high risk of
        developing inflammation. Additionally, we need to explore the local inflammatory status in tissues,
        which may yield different results compared to plasma inflammatory cytokine levels.]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[P-27                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




          Detection of Large Deletions and Duplication in F8 Gene of Haemophilia A
                                       Patients

                                            1
          Abdullah Aziz Nursaedah *, Lam Kah Yuen , Lukman Izzatul Nabila , Asrapil Waitul
                              1,
                                                               1
                          1
          Fifika , Salam Syarini , Mohamad Fadilah Nur Hakimah , Nik Mat Zin Nik Nor Imam ,
                                                                           1
              1
                                                     1
          Jradeh Bilal , Jaslowska Ewa , Yee Thynn Thynn , Gomez Keith , Mohd Sahid Ermi
                    3
                                                            3
                                                 3
                                 3
                                                      1
                                                                       1
                                    1
              Neiza , Musa Nurul Hidayah , Mohd Yasin Norafiza , Md Nor Azian Naila ,
                  1
         Somasundram Suguna , Md Afandi Faridah , Mohd Fathullah Tun Maizura , Jamaludin
                                                                   2
                                           2
                           1
                      Sufiza , Mat Ripen Adiratna  and Mat Yusoff Yuslina
                                                               1
                           2
                                            1
          1  Haematology Unit, Cancer Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health,
                               Ministry of Health, Selangor, Malaysia
                      2  National Blood Centre, Ministry of Health, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
         3  Katharine Dormandy Haemophilia Centre and Thrombosis Unit, Royal Free London NHS Foundation Trust,
                                   London, United Kingdom
                           *Corresponding Author: nursaedah@moh.gov.my
               Haemophilia A (HA) is an X-linked recessive bleeding disorder caused by mutations in the
        F8 gene, leading to deficiency of blood coagulation factor VIII. Diverse types of mutations have been
        reported  in  HA  patients  including  intron  22  inversion,  intron  1  inversion,  missense,  nonsense,
        frameshift and splice site mutations. However, in a small subset of patients, conventional PCR fails
        to amplify any exons or no mutations are detected upon analysis, suggesting the possibility of
        structural variations including large deletions and duplications. In this study,  multiplex ligation-
        dependent probe amplification (MLPA) was carried out to detect large deletions and duplications in
        the F8 gene of HA patients. Fragment analyses were performed using genetic analyzer with GS500-
        ROX as the internal size standard followed by data analysis using Coffalyser software. MLPA probe
        ratios were determined by comparing relative probe signals from each patient sample to those from
        healthy male DNA controls. Probe ratios in between 0.75 and 1.25 were considered as normal
        whereas ratios of <0.75 and >1.25 indicated deletion, and duplication, respectively. Among the
        studied 129 HA patients, 16 (12.4%) patients who did not have a mutation detected by inversion
        testing or F8 sequencing were subjected to MLPA.  Large deletions and duplications were detected
        in 6.2% (n=8) and 0.8% of patients (n=1), respectively. The gross deletions spanned across various
        locations including exon 1-7 (n=1), exon 4-6 (n=2), exon 13-21 (n=1) and exon 26 (n=4) of F8
        gene. Meanwhile, the gross duplication spanning exon 23-25 of the F8 gene was observed in one
        HA patient. These large structural variations lead to severe (n=7) and moderate (n=2) bleeding]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[P-27                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        phenotypes in HA patients. MLPA is a valuable molecular diagnostic approach for identifying large
        deletions and duplications in the F8 gene of HA patients, thereby facilitating precise genetic testing,
        carrier identification, and treatment decisions]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[P-28                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




        Frequency of Anti-Acetylcholine Receptor (AChR) Antibody among Suspected
                         Myasthenia Gravis Patients in Malaysia

          Nurhanani Mohamed Nor, Nur Syahirah Alias, Syuriatika Dionysius, Bavithra Venu,
                  Ainur Yusniza Yusof, Siti Asma Bakar and Siti Fatimah Abdullah
           1  Autoimmune Unit, Allergy and Immunology Research Centre, Institute for Medical Research, Malaysia

               Myasthenia gravis (MG) is a chronic neuromuscular autoimmune disease, characterised
        by muscle weakness and is potentially life-threatening. It is caused by  autoantibodies targeting
        components of the neuromuscular junction and this include acetylcholine receptors (AChR). The
        objective of this study is to evaluate the frequency and diagnostic utility of anti-AChR antibody in
        Malaysian MG-suspected patients. This is a retrospective study analysing the frequency of anti-AChR
        antibody  (IgG) measured  by enzyme-linked  immunoassay  (ELISA) selected from our diagnostic
        database from 2023. Results equal to and above 5 nmol/L are considered positive. A total of 905
        patients’ sera were analysed, of which 30% (274/905) of them had a positive anti-AChR antibody
        with a mean age of 48.3 years. Among the youngest seropositive patients were 8-month-old female
        twins that presented with bilateral ptosis since birth and were diagnosed with ocular MG. More than
        half of seropositive patients were Malays (54.7%), followed by Chinese (31.8%), other races (10.2%)
        and Indians (3.3%). A female predominance was also observed (56.9%) and there was a significant
        mean difference between males and females who were seropositive (p<0.05). Serological tests of
        autoantibodies are useful as non-invasive biomarkers to support the diagnosis of MG. In this study,
        anti-AChR antibody were detected in suspected MG patients presented with typical clinical features,
        thus proving its diagnostic  utility.  However, for further classification of MG  subtypes  especially
        among  seronegative  patients,  detection  of  other  autoantibodies  such  as  those  against  muscle-
        specific tyrosine kinase (MuSK) and lipoprotein receptor-related protein 4 (LRP4), is warranted to
        assist clinicians in disease management.]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[P-29                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




         Advancing Biochemical Diagnosis of Aromatic-L-Amino Acid Decarboxylase
          Deficiency (AADC-D): HPLC-Based AADC Activity Assay Preceding Genetic
                                        Testing

          Norashareena Mohamed Shakrin *, Norzahidah Mohd Khalid , Nor Azimah Azize ,
                                    1,4,
                                                                           2
                                                           2
             Yusnita Yaakub , Ch'ng Gaik Siew , Abdah Md Akim  and Julaina Abdul Jalil
                                                      4
                                                                         1
                         2
                                        3
         1  Inborn Error of Metabolism & Genetic Unit, NMCRC, Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National Institute
                   of Health Malaysia, Ministry of Health Malaysia (MOH), Setia Alam, Selangor
         2  Biochemistry Unit, SDC & Molecular Diagnostic Unit, SDC, Institute for Medical Research (IMR), National
                      Institute of Health Malaysia, Jalan Pahang, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
                      3  Genetic Unit, Pulau Pinang General Hospital, Georgetown, Penang
           4  Department of Biomedical Sciences, Faculty of Medicine & Health Sciences, Universiti Putra Malaysia
                                (UPM), Serdang, Selangor, Malaysia
                           *Corresponding Author: shareena.ms@moh.gov.my
               Aromatic-L-amino  acid decarboxylase deficiency, AADC-D  (OMIM #608643)  is a rare
        genetic disorder caused by pathogenic homozygous or compound heterozygous variants of the dopa
        decarboxylase (DDC) gene leading to severe neurological impairments. The AADC enzyme, which
        requires  pyridoxal  5-phosphate  as  a  cofactor,  is  responsible  for  the  decarboxylation  of  L-3,4
        dihydroxyphenylalanine (L-dopa) and 5-hydroxytryptophan (5- HTP) and is the final step in the well-
        characterized synthesis of the monoamine neurotransmitters dopamine and serotonin. The exact
        global incidence of AADC deficiency is unknown, but it is more prevalent in Asian populations. Early
        and accurate diagnosis is crucial for timely intervention, yet current biochemical diagnostic methods
        lack of specificity. Low concentrations of biogenic amines profile in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) are
        suggestive but not specific to this disorder. The discovery of reliable biomarkers is essential to
        improve diagnosis and patient outcomes. Our objectives were to validate a High Performance Liquid
        Chromatography  (HPLC)  based assay  for determination  of  the  AADC  activity  in  plasma  for  the
        diagnosis of AADC-D. HPLC with electrochemical and fluorescence detection was used to quantify
        AADC enzyme activity in two plasma samples of AADC-D patients and healthy controls using both
        of its substrates, 5-hydroxytryptophan (5-HTP) and 3,4-dihydroxyphenylalanine (L-dopa). The assay
        of AADC enzyme activity in patients’ plasma showed significantly reduced activity compared to normal
        reference  ranges.  The  measured  enzyme  activity  of  patient  1  and  patient  2  were  12.4±6.1  and
        17.9±11.5  (pmol/min/mL)  respectively;  below  the  lower  limit  of  the  reference  range,  highly
        suggestive of AADC deficiency. The results showed clear discrimination between confirmed AADC-]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[P-29                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        deficient patients and healthy controls (37.2±4.7pmol/min/mL). This low enzyme activity is consistent
        with the clinical features and genetic findings. The genetic analysis revealed a pathogenic variant in
        the  DDC  gene,  which  encodes  the  aromatic  L-amino  acid  decarboxylase  enzyme.  Compound
        heterozygous mutations were detected at c.175G>A, p.(Asp59Asn) in exon 2 and c.714+4A>T, p.(?)
        in intron 6 of the DDC gene. This diagnosis aligns with the patient’s clinical symptoms and confirms
        the presence of this rare genetic disorder. In conclusion, the combination analysis of markedly
        reduced enzyme activity and a pathogenic mutation in the DDC gene supports a definitive diagnosis
        of AADC-D. The findings suggest that plasma AADC activity assay by HPLC can serve as a reliable
        biomarker for biochemical diagnosis of AADC deficiency.]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[P-30                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




         Colorimetric Aptablot Assay for the Detection of Chikungunya Virus (CHIKV)

                  Low Yong Chun *, Magdline Sia Henry Sum  and Anna Andrew
                              1,
                                                     1
                                                                    2
                    1  Institute of Health and Community Medicine, Universiti Malaysia Sarawak
                      Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Malaysia Sarawak
                     2
                           *Corresponding Author: yongchun_@hotmail.com
               Chikungunya virus (CHIKV) infection is responsible for causing febrile illness in humans
        and posed a public health concern especially since the largest outbreak in the Indian Ocean in 2004.
        Patients infected with CHIKV might suffer from persistent joint pain for months to years. Serological
        tests  detecting  CHIKV  antigens,  such  as  enzyme-linked  immunosorbent  assays,  have  several
        limitations, including high cost, the need for well-trained personnel, batch-to-batch variation, and
        less stable. Unlike antibodies, aptamers (single-stranded DNA or RNA molecules) offer high affinity
        and  specificity  for  target  molecules,  can  be  produced  in  vitro  and  do  not  have  batch-to-batch
        variation. In this study, an Aptablot assay was developed using an aptamer, replacing antibodies
        commonly used in conventional dot blot assays. The aptamers were selected via Systematic Evolution
        of Ligands by Exponential Enrichment and are specific against CHIKV. The aptamers were modified
        with Thiol group at 5’ end and conjugated with 20 nm maleimide activated gold nanoparticles (AuNP)
        using a conjugation kit. The Aptablot assay was verified by immobilizing a series of concentrated
        CHIKV  on  the  nitrocellulose  membrane  and  incubated  with  aptamer-conjugated AuNP  after  the
        membrane was blocked with Bovine Serum Albumin in Phosphate Buffer Saline with Tween-20. The
        limit of detection of the Aptablot assay was 10  PFU/ml, which is within the typical CHIKV load (10 4
                                         4
        to 10  PFU/ml) in patients' samples during the viremic stage of infection. The colorimetric Aptablot
            8
        assay developed in this study is simple, fast, and user-friendly, and it can be done without the need
        for advanced equipment or skilled personnel. Our findings suggest that the Aptablot assay is a
        promising tool for the detection of CHIKV, especially in resource-limited settings where CHIKV is
        endemic..]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[P-31                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




        Discovery of Ten Novel Germline RB1 Gene Mutations in Unrelated Malaysian
                    Patients with Retinoblastoma: A 12-Year Experience

                                                     1
                                1,
          Ilia Nazihah Mohamad Ayob *, Anis Frasha Mohamad , Mohd Khairul Nizam Mohd
                   Khalid , Chew Hui Bin , Leong Huey Yin  and Yusnita Yakob
                        1
                                    2
                                                   2
                                                                  1
           1  Unit of Molecular Diagnostics, Institute for Medical Research, National Institutes of Health, Ministry of
                                      Health, Malaysia
                         2  Genetics Department, Kuala Lumpur Hospital, Malaysia
                             *Corresponding Author: nazihah.ma@moh.gov.my
               Retinoblastoma  (Rb)  is  the  most  common  malignant  intraocular  tumor  in  children.  Globally,
        retinoblastoma affects around 1 in 17,000 live births, with about 8,000 new cases reported annually. In Malaysia,
        an average of 14.5 new Rb cases are diagnosed every year. Rb arises due to mutations in the RB1 gene located
        on chromosome 13q14.2 and  is recognized as a prototypical hereditary cancer in humans. Around 30-40% of
        cases follow an autosomal dominant inheritance pattern, while the remaining 60-70% are sporadic and non-
        inherited.  In  this  study,  we  present  our  12-year  experience  in  identifying  RB1  gene  variants  among
        retinoblastoma patients in Malaysia. This retrospective cohort study analyzed over 350 samples sent to the
        Institute for Medical Research for molecular testing between 2012 and June 2024. Genetic testing involved
        amplifying all coding regions and splice sites of the RB1 gene using PCR, followed by Sanger sequencing to
        detect causative mutations. Pathogenic variants were confirmed using public databases and in silico prediction
        tools like VarSome and Franklin, according to ACMG guidelines. For cases with no mutation detected by PCR
        and sequencing, MLPA (Multiplex Ligation-Dependent Probe Amplification) analysis was performed using the
        SALSA MLPA Probemix P047 RB1 kit. Products were run on an Applied Biosystems 3500 Genetic Analyzer
        with GeneScan™ 500 LIZ® as the size standard, and results were analyzed with Coffalyser.Net software. A total
        of 81 distinct mutations were identified using the PCR-sequencing method and MLPA. Out of the 384 samples
        tested, 10 samples were found to harbour novel RB1 gene variants. Identification of mutational origin was
        important especially to inform the family of the affected proband regarding the risk of Rb to other siblings and
        relatives. Screening relatives at risk for RB1 mutations before the disease begins to manifest, was also found to
        be more cost-effective than conventional ophthalmological examinations. Prenatal diagnosis could also be
        offered to the mother in the future. In our samples, 21% of Malaysian patients with Retinoblastoma received the
        definitive molecularly proven diagnosis. For the remaining patients, tumor sample analysis is recommended, as
        this was not done in the current study. Additionally, the discovery of novel variants expands the genetic spectrum
        of the RB1 gene, contributing to future research on this disease. Accurate diagnosis is crucial not only for patient
        management but also for genetic counseling and early detection of at-risk family members.]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[P-32                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




        The Effect of Lauric Acid-Rich Diets in the Immune System: A Flow Cytometer
                                       Analysis

                                                      1
                                        1
                                                                  1
                            1,
             Maisarah Ab Fatah *, Yap Sia Yen , Voon Phooi Tee , Ng Yen Teng , Ammu
                          Radhakrishnan  and Kanga Rani Selvaduray
                                     2
                                                            1
                       1  Malaysian Palm Oil Board (MPOB), Kajang, Selangor, Malaysia
                      2  Monash University Malaysia, Bandar Sunway, Selangor, Malaysia
                         *Corresponding Author: maisarah.abfatah@mpob.gov.my
               Lauric acid is a medium-chain saturated fatty acid, with a 12-carbon atom chain (C12:0).
        Previous  in  vitro  studies showed  that lauric  acid  activates  the immune system through various
        pathways. However, there were also studies that showed that lauric acid do not activate the immune
        system. Therefore, further investigation needs to be done to investigate the contradicting findings.
        Here, we examined the effect of lauric acid-rich diets in mice pellet, on the immune system. Three
        types of diets from different types of fat sources were used. Diets A and B are rich in lauric acid,
        originating from different plant sources but containing similar amounts of lauric acid. Diet C is the
        basal diet. Each diet contains 50 % kcal of carbohydrate, 25 % kcal of protein and 25 % kcal of fat.
        These pellets were given to BALB/c female mice for six weeks to observe the effects of different diets
        on the immune system. Each diet group was be divided into two sub-groups: OVA-immunised and
        non-immunised group. The OVA-immunised group was immunised with a single dose of 50 μg
        ovalbumin (OVA) adjuvanted with alum subcutaneously, on day 14 and 28, while the other group act
        as the control group. The blood from each mouse was collected after sacrifice and the whole blood
        analysis was done using flow cytometer. Our data analysis showed that Diet A has a significant
        change in CD4 cells expression between the OVA and control group (p<0.01), while the CD4 cells
        expression in Diet B and Diet C were not significant.]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[P-33                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




            Exploring The Positional Distribution of Fatty Acids in Human Plasma
             Chylomicrons Using  C Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy
                               13
                             Ng Yen Teng and Voon Phooi Tee*

                          Malaysian Palm Oil Board (MPOB), Kajang, Malaysia.
                             *Corresponding Author: vptee@mpob.gov.my

               Analysis  of  the  positional  distribution  of  fatty  acids  in  triacylglycerols  (TAG)  using
        conventional lipase-catalysed hydrolysis and gas chromatography (GC) is laborious.  C nuclear
                                                                      13
        magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy has been validated to be a rapid, direct and accurate
        analytical method for determining the positional distribution of fatty acids in edible oils and fats.
        However, the utilisation of  C NMR in the regiospecific distribution of fatty acids in human plasma
                           13
        samples has yet to be studied extensively. In this study, we aimed to determine the positional
        distribution of fatty acids located at sn-1, 3 and sn-2 positions of blood TAG extracted from human
        chylomicrons using the  C NMR method. The study employed two test fats, namely palm olein (PO)
                         13
        and lard (LD), with predominantly oleic and palmitic acids situated at the sn-2 position of the TAG
        backbone, respectively. A postprandial, crossover-designed feeding intervention was conducted on
        14 subjects (female=7, male=7), and postprandial blood samples were collected at 3, 4, and 5 hours.
        Plasma chylomicrons, packed with the ingested TAG (~90%), were harvested from the postprandial
        blood  samples  using  the  ultracentrifugation  method.  The  TAGs  extracted  from  the  plasma
        chylomicrons were then analyzed using the 600 MHz  C NMR spectrometer (JEOL ECZR Series
                                               13
        600). Both test fats were utilized to optimize the acquisition and processing parameters of  C NMR
                                                                        13
        spectroscopy for routine regiospecific analysis of blood TAG. The Limit of Detection (LOD) was
        visually determined at 40mg/ml. The obtained  C NMR spectrum of extracted TAG was compared
                                          13
        with the optimized spectrum profiling produced from the two test fats. Subsequently, the positional
        distribution  of  fatty  acids  composition  (SFA,  MUFA,  PUFA)  of  the  extracted  TAG  from  plasma
        chylomicrons was identified. The  C NMR spectrum reflected the positional distribution of fatty acids
                                13
        from the intake of the two test fats in the human chylomicron samples. Consistent with the sn-2
        hypothesis, the PO-diet produced more MUFA, while the LD-diet produced more SFA at the sn-2
        position in the plasma chylomicrons at 3, 4, and 5 hours postprandially. In conclusion,  C NMR
                                                                        13
        spectroscopy is able to provide a direct measurement and serve as one of the rapid methods to
        determine  the  positional  distribution  of fatty  acids  in  blood  TAG  extracted  from  human  plasma
        chylomicrons after a high-fat diet intake, which is valuable to the healthcare industry.]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[P-34                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract




         Influence of Palm Olein on Human Gut Microbiota and Gut-Fermented Short
                                   Chain Fatty Acids

                                                   2
                                                                    3
         Yap Sia Yen *, Voon Phooi Tee , Cheah Yoke Kqueen , Verna Lee Kar Mun  and Kanga
                                 1
                  1,
                                    Rani Selvaduray
                                                 1
           1  Malaysian Palm Oil Board (MPOB), 6 Persiaran Institusi, Bandar Baru Bangi, 43000 Kajang, Selangor,
                                        Malaysia
          2  Department of Biomedical Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University Putra Malaysia,
                                43400 Serdang, Selangor, Malaysia
          3  Department of Family Medicine, School of Medicine, International Medical University, 70300 Seremban,
                                   Negeri Sembilan, Malaysia
                            *Corresponding Author: syyap@mpob.gov.my

               Gut  dysbiosis  is  often  associated  with  a  reduced  diversity  of  the  gut  microbiota
        composition and lower levels of its metabolites, short-chain fatty acids (SCFA). Diet high in saturated
        fats is associated with gut dysbiosis, but palm olein — which contains about similar proportions of
        saturated and unsaturated fatty acids is frequently mischaracterised as having the same negative
        health effects as saturated animal fats that trigger gut dysbiosis.  Currently, there is limited research
        on the effects of palm olein diet on gut microbiota composition and SCFA profiles of healthy adults.
        This study investigated the potential effects of a Malaysian habitual diet containing palm olein on gut
        microbiota composition and faecal SCFA profiles in 94 healthy adults over three weeks. The gut
        microbiota composition was analysed by amplifying the V3-V4 variable regions of 16S rRNA gene,
        and  subsequent  sequencing  using  the  MiSeq  Illumina  next  generation  sequencing  (NGS)
        platform.  The faecal SCFA were quantified using gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-
        MS).  Six linear and three branched-chain SCFA were detected, amounting over 800 umol/g dry
        weight.  The dominant linear SCFA, namely acetate: propionate and butyrate, were more than 96%
        in a ratio of 2:1:1.5, while the branched SCFA were 2.5%. Among the 14 phyla identified, Firmicutes
        was predominant, while the remaining 13 phyla accounted for about 25% of the gut microbiota
        composition. Of the 3,708 operational taxonomic units (OTUs) analysed, 365 OTUs met the selection
        criteria based on the Linear Discriminant Analysis (LDA) score ≥ 4 from LEfSe analysis and the
        presence of genes involved in lipid metabolic pathways, as determined by Phylogenetic Investigation
        of Communities by Reconstruction of Unobserved States (PICRUSt) analyses.  The palm olein diet
        was associated with an increase in Lactobacillus ruminis, accompanied by smaller amounts of Bacilli,
        Bacteroides and Coriobacteriaceae. These results suggest that these bacteria may serve as dietary]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[P-34                                                  Poster Presenter Abstract

        biomarkers for SCFA-producing bacteria following palm oil consumption in healthy adults.  Overall,
        these preliminary results provide valuable insights into the effects of palm olein on SCFA profile and
        the abundance of SCFA-producing bacteria, and offering an important reference for understanding
        its impact on gut health.]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[7 INTERNATIONAL MDBD CONFERENCE 2024
          TH
        ORGANIZING COMMITTEE
                                            Secretary: to re-check


         Advisor                            Publicity & Website
         Assoc Prof. Dr. Aziah Ismail       Dr. Eugene Ong Boon Beng
                                            Mr. Wong Ru Shen
         Chairperson                        Ms. Kavita Janasegran
         Dr. Eugene Ong Boon Beng           Ms. Anisha Kaur Johl A/P Pritam Singh
                                            Ms. Heba Mohammad Nabhan TumAllah
         Co-Chairperson
         Dr. Nurulhasanah Othman            Venue & Exhibition
         Assoc. Prof. Dr Venugopal Balakrishnan   Assoc. Prof. Dr. Venugopal Balakrishnan
                                            Dr. Leow Chiuan Herng
         Secretary                          Ms. Nor Suhada Binti Anuar
         Dr. Anizah Rahumatullah            Mdm. Syahirah Hanizah Binti Abdul Rais
         Dr Nik Yusnoraini Yusuf
                                            Technical
         Treasurer                          Dr. Lai Ngit Shin
         Ms. Nordina Ahmat                  Mr. Ahmad Anas Hamka Ayob
         Mr. Fazril Ezwan Bin Shafii        Mr. Mohamed Qais Abu Bakar
         Mdm. Zalani Binti Mamat            Mr. Abdul Hakim Jamaluddin
                                            Mr. Mohamad Fadhzli Abdul Wahab
         Scientific                         Ms. Shankariswari Yadevan
         Dr. Khairul Mohd Fadzli Mustaffa    Mr. Kok Boon Hui
         Assoc. Prof. Dr. Khoo Boon Yin     Mr. Yap Zi Jian
         Dr. Noor Fatmawati Mokhtar
         Prof. Dr. Gurjeet Kaur             Protocol
         Dr. Muhammad Hafiznur bin Yunus    Dr. Norsyahida Arifin
         Mr. Mohamad Fazli Khalid           Dr. Chew Ai Lan
         Mrs Elis Rosliza Mohd Adzmi        Mr. Muhammad Noor Fais Bin Kamarudin
         Ms. Sanaa Yaseen Issa              Mdm. Rodziyah Saari
         Mr. Ahmad Najib Mohamad            Ms. Dinie Adila Mohd Zainol
         Ms. Ong Xin Yi                     Ms. Mehalene Jayaram
         Ms. Kasturi A/P Selvam             Ms. Vilasini A/P K Rajinthran
                                            Ms. Datshini A/P Tamilannan]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[Secretariat & Registration         Sponsorship
         Dr Daruliza Kernain Mohd Azman     Assoc. Prof. Dr. Tye Gee Jun
         Mdm. Nordyana Zakaria              Dr. Noor Fatmawati Binti Mokhtar
         Mdm. Azimah Ahmad                  Dr. Rohanizah Binti Abdul Rahim
         Mdm. Izzati Zahidah Binti Abdul Karim
         Mdm. Salmi Binti Sallih
         Mdm. Nor Aida Abu Bakar]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[7  INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON MOLECULAR DIAGNOSTICS & BIOMARKER
           TH
                                      DISCOVERY
                              Advancing Medical Health Technology
                                   2024 OCTOBER 03-04



                                   Conference Sponsors








                                      Media Partners]]></page></pages></Search>